<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ApacheCon on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheCon/</link><description>Recent content in ApacheCon on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheCon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheConNA: Misc</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Misc # In his talk on Spdy Mathew Steele explained how he implemented the spdy protocol
as an Apache httpd module - working around most of the safety measures and
design decisions in the current httpd version. Essentially to get httpd to
support the protocol all you need now is mod_spdy plus a modified version of
mod_ssl.
The keynote on the last day was given by the Puppet founder.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Hadoop metrics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-hadoop-metrics99/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 20:25:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-hadoop-metrics99/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Hadoop metrics # Have you ever measured the general behaviour of your Hadoop jobs? Have you
sized your cluster accordingly? Do you know whether your work load really is IO
bound or CPU bound? Legend has it noone expecpt Allen Wittenauer over at
Linked.In, formerly Y! ever did this analysis for his clusters.
Steve Watt gave a pitch for actually going out into your datacenter measuring
what is going on there and adjusting the deployment accordingly: In small</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:23:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat # Monitoring - a task generally neglected - or over done - during development.
But still vital enough to wake up people from well earned sleep at night when
done wrong. Rainer Jung provided some valuable insights on how to monitor Apache httpd and Tomcat.
Of course failure detection, alarms and notifications are all part of good
monitoring. However so is avoidance of false positives and metric collection,</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On Security</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-security105/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 20:22:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-security105/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On Security # During the security talk at Apache Con a topic commonly glossed over by
developers was covered in quite some detail: With software being developed that
is being deployed rather widely online (over 50% of all websites are powered
by the Apache webserver) natually security issues are of large concern.
Currently there are eight trustworthy people on the foundation-wide security
response team, subscribed to security@apache.org. The team was started by</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On documentation</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-documentation104/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 20:20:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-documentation104/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On documentation # In her talk on documentation on OSS Noirin gave a great wrap up of the topic of
what documentation to create for a project and how to go about that task.
One way to think about documentation is to keep in mind that it fulfills
different tasks: There is conceptual, procedural and task-reference
documentation. When starting to analyse your docs you may first want to debug</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On delegation</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-delegation103/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 20:19:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-delegation103/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On delegation # In her talk on delegation Deb Nicholson touched upon a really important topic in
OSS: Your project may live longer than you are willing to support it yourself.
The first important point about delegation is to delegate - and to not wait
until you have to do it. Soon you will realise that mentoring and delegation
actually is a way to multiply your resources.
In order to delegate people to delegate to are needed.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: First keynote</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-first-keynote98/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 20:13:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-first-keynote98/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: First keynote # All three ApacheCon keynotes were focussed around the general theme of open
source communities. The first on given by Theo had very good advise to the
engineer not only striving to work on open source software but become an
excellent software developer:
Be loyal to the problem instead of to the code: You shouldn't be
addicted to any particular programming language or framework and refuse to work</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 20:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe # ApacheCon is the ``User Conference of the Apache Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. What
should that mean? If you are going to Apache Con you have the chance of meeting
committers of your favourite projects as well as members of the foundation
itself. Though there are a lot of talks that are interesting from a technical
point of view the goal really is to turn you into an active member of the</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 11 (last part)</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-11-last-part97/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 20:35:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-11-last-part97/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 11 (last part) # One of the last sessions covered logging frameworks for Java. Christian Grobmeier started by detailing the common requirements for all logging frameworks:
Speed - developers do not want to pay a disproportional penalty for using a logging framework.
Fail-safety and reliability - under no circumstances should your logging framework kill your application. In addition it would be most annoying to find that one log message that would help you de-cypher the problem your application ran into missing.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 10</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-1096/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 20:34:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-1096/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 10 # In the next session Jukka introduced Tika - a toolkit for parsing content from files including a heuristics based component for guessing the file type: Based on file extension, magic and certain patterns in the file the file type can be guessed rather reliably. Some anecdotes:
not all mime types are registered with IANA, there are of course conflicting file extensions,
Microsoft Word not only localises their interface but also the magic in the file,</description></item><item><title>ApacheCon EU - part 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:54:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</guid><description>ApacheCon EU - part 09 # In the Solr track Elastic Search and Solr Cloud went into competition. The comparison itself was slightly apples-and-oranges like as the speaker compared the current ES version based on Lucene 3.x and Solr Cloud based on Lucene 4.0. During the comparison it still turned out that both solutions are more or less comparable - so choice again depends on your application. However I did like the conclusion: The speaker did not pick a clear winner in terms of projects.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 08</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0895/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 20:53:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0895/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 08 # Jan Lehnardt&amp;rsquo;s talk covered the history of CouchDB - including lessons learnt along the way. The first issue he went into: Shipping 1.0 is hard! They spent a lot of effort and time in order to have a stable database that won&amp;rsquo;t loose your data - only to have a poorly patch slip in for 1.0 that resulted in data loss. The fury of action happening afterwards was truely amazing - people working on rolling shifts all over the planet to not only fix the issue but also provide recovery tooling for those affected by the bug.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 07</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 20:51:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 07 # Julien Nioche shared some details on the nutch crawler. Being the mother of all Hadoop projects (as in Hadoop was born out of developments inside of nutch) the project has become rather quite with a steady stream of development in the recent past. Julien himself uses the nutch for gathering crawled data for several customer projects - feeding this data into an NLP pipeline based on Behemoth that glues Mahout, UIMA and Gate together.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 06</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part0693/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 20:48:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part0693/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 06 # For the next session I joined the Tomcat crowd in Marc Thomas&amp;rsquo; to learn more on Tomcat reverse proxy configurations. One rather common setup is to have Tomcat connected to an httpd instance. One common issue encountered with this setup in particular when running httpd with the event mpm is the problem of thread exhaustion on tomcat&amp;rsquo;s side. Fixes include always having more active tomcat threads than there can be httpd threads at any one time and to disable persistent connections.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 05</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-592/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 20:47:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-592/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 05 # The afternoon featured several talks on HBase - both it&amp;rsquo;s implementation as well as schema optimisation. One major issue in schema design in the choice of key. Simplest recommendation is to make sure that keys are designed such that on reading data load will be evenly distributed accross all nodes to prevent region-server hot-spotting. General advise here are hashing or reversing urls.
When it comes to running your own HBase cluster make sure you know what is going on in the cluster at any point in time:</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 04</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0491/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 20:46:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0491/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 04 # The second talk I went to was the one on the dev@hadoop.a.o insights given by Steve Loughran. According to Steve Hadoop has turned into what he calls an operating system for the data center - similar to Linux in that it&amp;rsquo;s development is not driven by a vendor but by its users: Even though Hortenworks, Cloudera and MapR each have full time people working on Hadoop (and related projects), this work usually is driven by customer requirements which ultimately means that someone is running a Hadoop cluster that he has trouble with and wants to have fixed.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 03</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0390/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 20:27:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0390/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 03 # Tuesday started early with a plenary - run by the sponsor, not too many news there, except for the very last slide that raised a question that is being discussed often also within the ASF - namely how to define oneself compared to non-ASF projects. What is the real benefit for our users - and what is the benefit for people to go with the ASF.</description></item><item><title>ApacheCon EU - part 02</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0286/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 20:26:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0286/</guid><description>ApacheCon EU - part 02 # For me the week started with the Monday Hackathon. Even though I was there early the room quickly filled up and was packed at lunch time. I really liked the idea of having people interested in a topic register in advance - it gave the organisers a chance to assign tables to topics and put signs on the tables to advertise the topic worked on.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 01</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0189/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 14:30:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0189/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 01 # Apache Con EU in Germany - in November, in Sinsheim (in the middle of nowhere): I have to admit that I was more than skeptical whether that would actually work out very well. A day after the closing session it&amp;rsquo;s clear that the event was a huge success: Days before all tickets were sold out, there were six sessions packed with great talks on all things related to Apache Software Foundation projects - httpd, tomcat, lucene, open office, hadoop, apache commons, james, felix, cloud stack and tons of other projects were well covered.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Wrap Up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 20:45:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up25/</guid><description>Apache Con Wrap Up # First things first - slides, audio and abstracts of Apache Con are all online now on their Lanyrd page. So if you missed the conference or could not attend a session due to conflicting with another interesting session - that&amp;rsquo;s your chance to catch up.
For those of you who are speaking German, there&amp;rsquo;s also a summary of Apache Con available on heise Open. (If you don&amp;rsquo;t speak German, I have been told that the Google Translate version of the site captures the gist of the article reasonably well.</description></item><item><title>Talking people into submitting patches</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches388/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 20:22:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches388/</guid><description>Talking people into submitting patches # In November I am going to attend Apache Con NA. This year I decided to do a little experiment: I sumitted a talk on talking people into contributing to free software projects. The format of the talk is a bit unusual: Drawing from my - admittedly limited and very biased - experience explaining free software to others and talking people into contributing patches this talks tries to initiate a discussion on methods to get awesome developers to consider contributing their work back to free software projects.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Wrap up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 23:27:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up16/</guid><description>Apache Con – Wrap up # After one week of lots of interesting input the ASF&amp;rsquo;s user conference was over. With a focus on Apache software users quite a few talks are not too well suited for conference regulars but more or less targeted at newbies who want to know who too successfully apply the software. As a developer of Mahout with close ties to the Lucene and Hadoop community what is of course most interesting to me are stories of users putting the software into production.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Atlanta</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 23:24:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</guid><description>Teddy in Atlanta # While I was happily attending Apache Con US in Atlanta/GA my teddy had a closer look at the city: He first went to the centennial olympic park, took a picture of the world of coca-cola (wondering what strange kinds of museums there are in the US. After that he headed over to Midtown having a quiet time in the Piedmont park. And finally had a closer look at the private houses still decorated for Halloween.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – last day</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 23:23:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</guid><description>Apache Con – last day # Day three of Apache Con started with interesting talks on Tomcat 7, including an introduction to the new features of that release. Those include better memory leak prevention and detection capabilities – the implementation of these capabilities have lead to the discovery of various leaks that appear under more or less weird circumstances in famous open source libraries and the JVM itself. But also better management and reporting facilities are part of the new release.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Mahout, commons and Lucene</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-mahout-commons-and-lucene15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 23:21:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-mahout-commons-and-lucene15/</guid><description>Apache Con – Mahout, commons and Lucene # The second day the track interesting to me provided an overview of some of the Apache commons projects. So seemingly small in scope and light-weight in implementation and dependencies these projects provide vital features not yet well supported by the Sun JVM. There is a commons math implementation featuring a fair amount of algebraic, numeric and trigonometric functions (among others), the commons exec framework for executing processes externally to the JVM w/o running into the danger of creating dead-locks or wasting resources.</description></item><item><title>ApacheCon - Keynotes</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-keynotes85/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 23:20:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-keynotes85/</guid><description>ApacheCon - Keynotes # The first keynote was given by Dana Blankenhorn – a journalist and blogger regularly publishing tech articles with a clear focus on open source projects. Focussed on the evolution of open source projects with a special focus on Apache.
Coming from a research background the keynote given by Daniel Crichton from NASA was very interesting to me: According to the speaker scientists are facing challenges that are all to known to large and distributed corporations.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 23:19:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</guid><description>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd # The first Apache Con day featured several presentations on NoSQL databases (track sponsored by Day software), a Hadoop track as well as presentations on Httpd and an Open source business track. Since its inception Hadoop always was intended to be run in trusted environments firewalled from hostile users or even attackers. As such it never really supported any security features. This is about the change with the new Hadoop release including better Kerberos based security.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Hackathon days</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hackathon-days12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 23:17:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hackathon-days12/</guid><description>Apache Con – Hackathon days # This year on Halloween I left for a trip to Atlanta/GA. Apache Con US was supposed to take place there featuring two presentations on Apache Mahout – one by Grant Ingersoll explaining how to use Mahout to provide better search features in Solr, one by myself with a general introduction to what features Mahout provides, giving a bit more detailed information on how to use Mahout for classificaiton.</description></item><item><title>Travelling</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 23:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</guid><description>Travelling # Currently on my way back from a series of conferences in the past three weeks in the IC from Schiphol. After three weeks of conferences, lots of new input and lots of interesting projects I learned about it is finally time to head back and put the stuff I have learned to good use.
View Travelling in a larger map
As seems normal with open source conferences I got far more input on interesting projects than I can expect to ever get applied in on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:56:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3 # Friday was the last conference day. I enjoyed the Apache pioneers panel with a brief history of the Apache Software Foundation as well as lots of stories on how people first got in contact with the ASF.
After lunch I went to the testing and cloud session. I enjoyed the talk on continuum and its uses by Wendy Smoak. She gave a basic overview of why one would want a CI system and provided a brief introduction to continuum.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:42:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2 # Thursday morning started with an interesting talk on open source collaboration tools and how they can help resolving some collaboration overhead on commercial software projects. Four goals can be reached with the help of the right tools: Sharing the project vision, tracking the current status of the project, finding places to help the project and documenting the project history as well as the reasons for decisions along the way.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 18:41:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1 # The past week members, committers and users of Apache software projects gathered in Amsterdam for another Apache Con EU
and to celebrate the 10th birthday of the ASF. One week dedicated to the development and use of Free Software and the Apache Way.
Monday was BarCamp day for me, the first BarCamp I ever attended. Unfortunately not all participants proposed talks. So some of the atmosphere of an unconference was missing.</description></item></channel></rss>