<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>strataconf on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/strataconf/</link><description>Recent content in strataconf on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 20:05:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/strataconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>O'Reilly Strata coming to London</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-coming-to-london304/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 20:05:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-coming-to-london304/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata coming to London # O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata is coming to London. The first edition of Strata back in 2011 brought Big Data developers, designers, scientists and decision makers together to discuss all things scalable. This year in October the conference comes to Europe: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata EU will take place in London.
Date: October 1st - 2nd 2012
Venue: Hilton London Metropole, 225 Edgware Road, London W2 1JU, UK</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 22:18:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures # Big data at startups - Info ChimpsAs a startup to get good people there is no other option then to grow your own: Offer the option to gain a lot of experience in return for a not so great wage. Start out with really great hires:
People who have the &amp;quot;get shit done gene&amp;quot;: They discover new projects, are proud to contribute to team efforts, are confident in making changes to a code base probably not known before hand.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 20:17:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes # Day two of Strata started with a very inspiring insight from the host itself that extended the vision discussed earlier in the tutorials: It's not at all about the tools, the current data analytics value lies in the data itself and in the conclusions and actions drawn from analysing it.
Bit.ly keynoteThe first key note was presented by bit.ly - for them there are four dimensions to data analytics:</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 20:17:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics # Acting based on dataIt comes as no surprise to hear that also in the data analytics world engineers are unwilling to share details of how their analysis works with higher management - with on the other side not much interest on learning how analytics really works. This culture leads to a sort of black art, witch craft attitude to data analytics that hinders most innovation.</description></item></channel></rss>