<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache/</link><description>Recent content in Apache on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:06:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Board of Directors - a retrospective</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-board-of-directors-a-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:06:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-board-of-directors-a-retrospective/</guid><description>Apache Board of Directors - a retrospective # Last term I had the honour of serving on the ASF board of directors, better explained in context of the ASF governance structure. As quite a few directors (myself included) declined to run for the board this year again, I thought it would be a good idea to think about the past term, write that down and publish those thoughts. As I wanted to give every board member a chance to respond, I shared some guiding questions but left it to board members to choose the channel they deemed most appropriate to share their responses on.</description></item><item><title>DataworksSummit Berlin - Wednesday morning</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dataworkssummit-berlin-wednesday-morning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 08:50:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dataworkssummit-berlin-wednesday-morning/</guid><description>DataworksSummit Berlin - Wednesday morning # Data strategy - cloud strategy - business strategy: Aligning the three was one of the main themes (initially put forward in his opening keynote by CTO of Hortonworks Scott Gnau) thoughout this weeks Dataworks Summit Berlin kindly organised and hosted by Hortonworks. The event was attended by over 1000 attendees joining from 51 countries.
The inspiration hat was put forward in the first keynote by Scott was to take a closer look at the data lifecycle - including the fact that a lot of data is being created (and made available) outside the control of those using it: Smart farming users are using a combination of weather data, information on soil conditions gathered through sensors out in the field in order to inform daily decisions.</description></item><item><title>Apache Breakfast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 09:39:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-breakfast/</guid><description>Apache Breakfast # In case you missed it but are living in Berlin - or are visiting Berlin/ Germany this week: A handful of Apache people (committers/ members) are meeting over breakfast on Friday morning this week. If you are interested in joining, please let me know (or check yourself - in the archives of the mailing list party@apache.org)</description></item><item><title>FOSS Backstage - Schedule online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-schedule-online/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 09:27:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-schedule-online/</guid><description>FOSS Backstage - Schedule online # In January the CfP for FOSS Backstage opened. By now reviews have been done, speakers notified and a schedule created. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to find both - a lot of friends from the Apache Software Foundation but also a great many speakers that aren&amp;rsquo;t affiliated with the ASF among the speakers. If you want to know how Open Source really works, if you want to get a glimpse behind the stage, do not wait for too long to grab your ticket now and join us in summer in Berlin/ Germany.</description></item><item><title>My board nomination statement 2018</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-board-nomination-statement-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 08:21:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-board-nomination-statement-2018/</guid><description>My board nomination statement 2018 # Two days ago the Apache Software Foundation members meeting started. One of the outcomes of each members meeting is an elected board of directors. The way that works is explained here: Annual Apache members meeting. As explained in the linked post, members accepting their nomination to become a director are supposed to provide a nomination statement. This year they were also asked to answer a set of questions so members could better decide who to vote for.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 20:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe # ApacheCon is the ``User Conference of the Apache Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. What
should that mean? If you are going to Apache Con you have the chance of meeting
committers of your favourite projects as well as members of the foundation
itself. Though there are a lot of talks that are interesting from a technical
point of view the goal really is to turn you into an active member of the</description></item><item><title>Moving to a new domain</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 12:30:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</guid><description>Moving to a new domain # Executive summary: This is to warn those of you who are subscribed to this blog - the domain to reach this blog w/o redirects will soon change to by isabel-drost-fromm.de - you might want to adjust your rss subscription accordingly.
Longer version: This blog post is scheduled to go live some time after lunch-time on September 12th 2012. You might have heart rumors before - that date Ms.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con returns to Europe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-coming-to-europe22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 20:41:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-coming-to-europe22/</guid><description>Apache Con returns to Europe # In November Apache Con will come back to Europe. The event will take place in Sinsheim inviting foundation members, project committers, contributors and users to meet, discuss and have fun during the one week event.
Several meetups will be held the weekend before the main conference kicks off, watch out for announcements on your favourite project mailing list.
ApacheCon is still open for submissions until August 3rd - head over to the Call for submissions for more information.</description></item><item><title>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 20:59:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</guid><description>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin # Interested in Apache Sling and/or Apache Jackrabbit? Then you might be interested in hearing that on September 26th to 28th there will be an event in town on these two topics - mainly organised by Adobe, but labeled as community event, meaning that there will be a number of active community members attending the conference: adaptTo().
From their website:
In late September 2012 Berlin will become the global heart beat for developers working on the Adobe CQ technical stack.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.6 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-06-released66/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 21:33:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-06-released66/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.6 released # As of Monday, February 6th a new Apache Mahout version was released. The new package features
Lots of performance improvments:
A new LDA implementation using Collapsed Variational Bayes 0th Derivative Approximation - try that out if you have been bothered by the way less than optimal performance of the old version.
Improved Decision Tree performance and added support for regression problems
Reduced runtime of dot product between vectors - many algorithms in Mahout rely on that, so these performance improvements will affect anyone using them.</description></item><item><title>Talking people into submitting patches - results</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches-results389/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 18:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches-results389/</guid><description>Talking people into submitting patches - results # Back in November I gave a talk at Apache Con NA in Vancouver on talking friends and colleagues into contributing patches to open source projects. The intended audience for this talk were experienced committers to Apache projects, the goal was to learn more on their tricks for talking people into patching. First of all thanks for an interesting discussion on the topic - it was great to get into the room with barely enough slides to fill 10 min and still have a lively discussion 45min later.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:38:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</guid><description>Open Source Expo # Title: Open Source Expo
Location: Karlsruhe
Link out: Click here
Description: There will be a booth at Open source expo introducing interested visitors to the Apache projects Lucene and Mahout. Of course we are also happy to answer any questions on the ASF in general.
Start Date: 2009-11-15
End Date: 2009-11-16</description></item></channel></rss>