<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Httpd on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Httpd/</link><description>Recent content in Httpd on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Httpd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheConNA: Misc</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Misc # In his talk on Spdy Mathew Steele explained how he implemented the spdy protocol
as an Apache httpd module - working around most of the safety measures and
design decisions in the current httpd version. Essentially to get httpd to
support the protocol all you need now is mod_spdy plus a modified version of
mod_ssl.
The keynote on the last day was given by the Puppet founder.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:23:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat # Monitoring - a task generally neglected - or over done - during development.
But still vital enough to wake up people from well earned sleep at night when
done wrong. Rainer Jung provided some valuable insights on how to monitor Apache httpd and Tomcat.
Of course failure detection, alarms and notifications are all part of good
monitoring. However so is avoidance of false positives and metric collection,</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 03</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0390/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 20:27:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0390/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 03 # Tuesday started early with a plenary - run by the sponsor, not too many news there, except for the very last slide that raised a question that is being discussed often also within the ASF - namely how to define oneself compared to non-ASF projects. What is the real benefit for our users - and what is the benefit for people to go with the ASF.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 23:19:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</guid><description>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd # The first Apache Con day featured several presentations on NoSQL databases (track sponsored by Day software), a Hadoop track as well as presentations on Httpd and an Open source business track. Since its inception Hadoop always was intended to be run in trusted environments firewalled from hostile users or even attackers. As such it never really supported any security features. This is about the change with the new Hadoop release including better Kerberos based security.</description></item></channel></rss>