<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ApacheConNA on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConNA/</link><description>Recent content in ApacheConNA on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConNA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheConNA: Misc</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 20:26:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-misc101/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Misc # In his talk on Spdy Mathew Steele explained how he implemented the spdy protocol
as an Apache httpd module - working around most of the safety measures and
design decisions in the current httpd version. Essentially to get httpd to
support the protocol all you need now is mod_spdy plus a modified version of
mod_ssl.
The keynote on the last day was given by the Puppet founder.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Hadoop metrics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-hadoop-metrics99/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 20:25:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-hadoop-metrics99/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Hadoop metrics # Have you ever measured the general behaviour of your Hadoop jobs? Have you
sized your cluster accordingly? Do you know whether your work load really is IO
bound or CPU bound? Legend has it noone expecpt Allen Wittenauer over at
Linked.In, formerly Y! ever did this analysis for his clusters.
Steve Watt gave a pitch for actually going out into your datacenter measuring
what is going on there and adjusting the deployment accordingly: In small</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:23:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat # Monitoring - a task generally neglected - or over done - during development.
But still vital enough to wake up people from well earned sleep at night when
done wrong. Rainer Jung provided some valuable insights on how to monitor Apache httpd and Tomcat.
Of course failure detection, alarms and notifications are all part of good
monitoring. However so is avoidance of false positives and metric collection,</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On Security</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-security105/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 20:22:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-security105/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On Security # During the security talk at Apache Con a topic commonly glossed over by
developers was covered in quite some detail: With software being developed that
is being deployed rather widely online (over 50% of all websites are powered
by the Apache webserver) natually security issues are of large concern.
Currently there are eight trustworthy people on the foundation-wide security
response team, subscribed to security@apache.org. The team was started by</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On documentation</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-documentation104/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 20:20:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-on-documentation104/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On documentation # In her talk on documentation on OSS Noirin gave a great wrap up of the topic of
what documentation to create for a project and how to go about that task.
One way to think about documentation is to keep in mind that it fulfills
different tasks: There is conceptual, procedural and task-reference
documentation. When starting to analyse your docs you may first want to debug</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: On delegation</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-delegation103/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 20:19:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-delegation103/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: On delegation # In her talk on delegation Deb Nicholson touched upon a really important topic in
OSS: Your project may live longer than you are willing to support it yourself.
The first important point about delegation is to delegate - and to not wait
until you have to do it. Soon you will realise that mentoring and delegation
actually is a way to multiply your resources.
In order to delegate people to delegate to are needed.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: First keynote</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-first-keynote98/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 20:13:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-first-keynote98/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: First keynote # All three ApacheCon keynotes were focussed around the general theme of open
source communities. The first on given by Theo had very good advise to the
engineer not only striving to work on open source software but become an
excellent software developer:
Be loyal to the problem instead of to the code: You shouldn't be
addicted to any particular programming language or framework and refuse to work</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 20:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe # ApacheCon is the ``User Conference of the Apache Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. What
should that mean? If you are going to Apache Con you have the chance of meeting
committers of your favourite projects as well as members of the foundation
itself. Though there are a lot of talks that are interesting from a technical
point of view the goal really is to turn you into an active member of the</description></item><item><title>Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-na21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 10:50:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-na21/</guid><description>Apache Con NA # Title: Apache Con NA
Location: Vancouver
Link out: Click here
Start Date: 2011-11-07&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;End Date: 2011-11-11</description></item><item><title>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 13:49:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</guid><description>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011 # Mid November Apache hosts its famous yearly conference - this time in Vancouver/Canada. They kindly accepted my presentations on Apache Mahout for intelligent data analysis (mostly focused on introducing the project to new comers and showing what happened within the project in the past year - if you have any wish concerning topics you would like to see covered in particular, please let me know) as well as a more committer focused one on Talking people into creating patches (with the goal of highlighting some of the issues new-comers to free software projects that want to contribute run into and initiating a discussion on what helps to convince them to keep up the momentum and over come and obstacles).</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Podcast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 21:21:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Podcast # During Apache Con ATL Michael Coté interviewed Grant Ingersoll on Apache Mahout. The interview is available online as podcast. The interview covers the goals and current use cases of the project, goes into some detail on the reasons for initially starting it. If you are wondering what Mahout is all about, what you can do with it and which direction development is heading, the interview is a great option to find out more.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 20:39:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</guid><description>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA # The upcoming Apache Con NA to take place in Atlanta will feature several tracks relevant to users of Apache Mahout, Lucene and Hadoop: There will be a full track on Hadoop as well as one on NoSQL on Wednesday featuring talks on the framework itself, Pig and Hive as well as presentations from users on special use cases and on their way of getting the system to production.</description></item></channel></rss>