<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hbase on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/hbase/</link><description>Recent content in hbase on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:43:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/hbase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:43:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</guid><description>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05 # On MySQL
Second day at FOSDEM for me started with the MySQL dev room. One thing that made me smile was in the MySQL new features talk: The speaker announced support for “NoSQL interfaces” to MySQL. That is kind of fun in two dimensions: A) What he really means is support for the memcached interface. Given the vast number of different interfaces to databases today, announcing anything as “supports NoSQL interfaces” sounds kind of silly.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 05</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-592/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 20:47:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-592/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 05 # The afternoon featured several talks on HBase - both it&amp;rsquo;s implementation as well as schema optimisation. One major issue in schema design in the choice of key. Simplest recommendation is to make sure that keys are designed such that on reading data load will be evenly distributed accross all nodes to prevent region-server hot-spotting. General advise here are hashing or reversing urls.
When it comes to running your own HBase cluster make sure you know what is going on in the cluster at any point in time:</description></item><item><title>Cloudera in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloudera-in-berlin142/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 20:24:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloudera-in-berlin142/</guid><description>Cloudera in Berlin # Cloudera is hosting another round of trainings in Berlin in November this year. In addition to the trainings on Apache Hadoop this time around there will also be trainings on Apache HBase.
Register online via:
http://www.eventbrite.com/event/2315126606
http://www.eventbrite.com/event/2349094204</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</guid><description>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging # Nicolas Spiegelberg gave an awesome introduction not only to the architecture that powers Facebook messaging but also to the design decisions behind their use of Apache HBase as a storage backend. Disclaimer: HBase is being used for message storage, for attachements with Haystack a different backend is used.
The reasons to go for HBase include its strong consistency model, support for auto failover, load balancing of shards, support for compression, atomic read-modify-write support and the inherent Map/Reduce support.</description></item><item><title>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</guid><description>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale # This is to announce the Berlin Buzzwords 2011. The second edition of the successful conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany,
taking place in Berlin.
Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - Search, Store, Scale
6/7 June 2011
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 21:25:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase # Devoxx featured several interesting case studies of how HBase and Hadoop can be used to scale data analysis back ends as well as data serving front ends. Twitter
Dmitry Ryaboy from Twitter explained how to scale high load and large data systems using Cassandra. Looking at the sheer amount of tweets generated each day it becomes obvious that with a system like MySQL alone this site cannot be run.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day two – Hadoop and HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-two-hadoop-and-hbase158/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 21:24:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-two-hadoop-and-hbase158/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day two – Hadoop and HBase # In his session on the current state of Hadoop Tom went into a little more detail not only on the features released in the latest release or on the roadmap for upcoming releases (including Kerberos based security, append support, warm standby namenode and others).
He also gave a very interesting view on the current Hadoop ecosystem. More and more projects are currently being created that either extend Hadoop or are built on top of Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 21:20:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</guid><description>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase # During the morning session FIXME Ellison gave an introduction to the distributed NoSQL database Cassandra. Being generally based on the Dynamo paper from Amazon the key-value store distributes key/value pairs according to a consistent hashing schema. Nodes can be added dynamically making the system well suited for elastic scaling. In contrast to Dynamo, Cassandra can be tuned for the required consistency level. The system is tuned for storing moderately sized key/value pairs.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:17:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</guid><description>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase # The first day at Devoxx featured several tutorials – most interesting to me was the pragramatic programmer. The speaker also is the author of the equally named book at O&amp;rsquo;Reilly. The book was the result of the observation that developers today are more and more IDE bound, no longer able to use the command line effectively. The result are developers that are unnecessarily slow when creating software.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 23:19:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</guid><description>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd # The first Apache Con day featured several presentations on NoSQL databases (track sponsored by Day software), a Hadoop track as well as presentations on Httpd and an Open source business track. Since its inception Hadoop always was intended to be run in trusted environments firewalled from hostile users or even attackers. As such it never really supported any security features. This is about the change with the new Hadoop release including better Kerberos based security.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track # This year&amp;rsquo;s Devoxx will feature several presentations coming from the Apache Hadoop ecosystem including Tom White on the basics of Hadoop: HDFS, MapReduce, Hive and Pig as well as Michael Stack on HBase.
&amp;lt; br&amp;gt;
In addition there will be a brief Tools in Action presentation on Monday evening featuring Apache Mahout.
Please let me know if you are going to Devoxx - would be great to meet some more Apache people there, maybe have dinner at one of the conference days.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop in Debian Squeeze</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-in-debian-squeeze61/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 12:04:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-in-debian-squeeze61/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop in Debian Squeeze # After using Mandrake for quite a while (still blaming my boyfriend Thilo for infecting not only my computer but also myself first with that system, then with the more general idea of Free Software
but that&amp;rsquo;s another story.) after finishing my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis I started using GNU Debian Linux (back then in the version code-named Woody). Since I always had a GNU Debian on my private box as my main operating system - even installed it on my MacBook following the steps in the Debian Wiki.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 03:41:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</guid><description>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase # At the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Bob Schulze from eCircle in Munich gave a presentation on “Tips and patterns with HBase”. The talk has been video recorded. The result is now available online:
HBase Bob Schulze from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video. Thanks to Bob for an awesome talk on eCircle’s usage of HBase - and on providing some background information on how HBase was applied to solve your problems.</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>Slides are available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:49:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</guid><description>Slides are available # Slides for the last Hadoop Get Together are available online:
Spatial Search by Chris Male
HBase Patterns by Bob Schulze
Scaling product search with Hadoop and Lucene by Dragan Milosevic
My own little introduction, just in case you are interested.
Videos will follow as soon as the are ready. Watch this space for further updates.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:40:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010 # Today (or more correctly, yesterday) the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in newthinking store. I arrived rather early to have some time to do some planning for Berlin Buzzwords - got there nearly one hour before the meetup. However it did not take very long until first guests came to the store. So I quickly got my introductory slides in place - Martin from newthinking already had the room setup, camera in place and audio working.</description></item></channel></rss>