<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>teddy on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/teddy/</link><description>Recent content in teddy on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:04:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/teddy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teddy in London</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-london399/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:04:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-london399/</guid><description>Teddy in London # While I was at the conference – Teddy spent some time exploring the surroundings of the conference hotel. Looks like in particular Hyde park was attractive:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Down Under</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-down-under397/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 20:24:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-down-under397/</guid><description>Teddy in Down Under # The last two September weeks Teddy was in Down Under. He spent the first few days exploring Sydney: Taking the ferry from Manly to the city each morning, followed by beautiful sunny weather, warm enough to already go swimming.
The following days took him to the Blue Mountains and into Kangaroo Valley for some hiking, animal watching and kayaking:
Of course Teddy also made some new friends:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Meißen</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-meisen400/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 20:19:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-meisen400/</guid><description>Teddy in Meißen # Taken earlier this year in Meißen the picture shows a detail of the beautiful cathedral:
Teddy after a busy day:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Sweden</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-sweden404/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 19:22:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-sweden404/</guid><description>Teddy in Sweden # Some picture taken all the way up in northern Sweden:
Those picture were taken mid-June. That means what looks like Teddy sitting in the afternoon sun actually was taken 20min before midnight some 40km south of the arctic circle at Camp Frevisören - an incredible spot to start the day on a canoo:
View Larger Map
(That little half-isle that stretches into the ocean.)
If you ever travel that far north, make sure to stop by at Hulkoff.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-zurich405/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 20:20:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-zurich405/</guid><description>Teddy in Zürich # A few beautiful sunny though windy days in Zurich late April:
View from the path between Ütliberg and Adliswil/Felsenegg:
Strolling through the city and sitting next to Zürichsee enjoying the sun afterwards:
A boat trip to Rapperswil - started cold and cloudy, finished warm and sunny:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Poznan</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-poznan402/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 20:03:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-poznan402/</guid><description>Teddy in Poznan # Some images taken in Poznan after GeeCon - big Thanks! to Dawid for giving advise on where to go for sightseeing, exhibitions and going-out.
The tour started close to river Warta - it being a sunny day it seemed like a perfect fit to just walk through the city, starting along the river headed towards the cathedral:
After that Poznan Citadel was a great place to spend lunch time - sitting somewhere green and shady:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Chicago</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-chicago396/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 21:56:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-chicago396/</guid><description>Teddy in Chicago # Last week I spent several days in Chicago mainly to attend a few meetings at the local Nokia/Navteq office. Though the schedule was pretty packed, a few hours remained to explore the then frosty and windy city:
Top three images: Some impressions of the city. Bottom left: Teddy&amp;rsquo;s new friend. Bottom right: Situation at ORD when flying out - fortunately both, the airport as well as the airline (Swiss) have quite some experience with challenging weather conditions so that we could leave without too much delay.</description></item><item><title>Night Trains</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 05:40:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</guid><description>Night Trains # It was several years ago that a frequent traveller told me about it being more comfortable and time saving to travel mid-sized distances (e.g. from Berlin to Amsterdam) by train - night train that is - instead of flying. Back then without decent knowledge of which combination of booking early and discount card make prizes of trips by train somewhat comparable to those offered by airlines that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an option for me.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam391/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 20:16:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam391/</guid><description> Teddy in Amsterdam # On his trip from SFO back to Europe teddy spent a few days in Amsterdam. He brought back the following pictures of bikes, cheese and the canals: Going to Amsterdam usually is pretty darn dangerous: I tend to return with some toys added to my collection of puzzles. Somehow I tend to be drawn to the shop called Gamekeeper selling them even when I do not remember the exact address or even just the street name:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 20:13:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</guid><description>Teddy in San Francisco # Before attending O'Reilly Strata there were a few days left to adjust to the different time zone, meet up with friends and generally spend some days in the Greater San Francisco area. As was to be expected, those were way to few days. The weekend was a bit rainy, still packed with visiting China town right after the plane had landed and spending some time at .</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 21:30:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</guid><description>Teddy in Antwerp # When at Devoxx Teddy went to the city taking a few pictures of the Grote Markt, the Haven as well as the main train station.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:11:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</guid><description>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol # Caught Teddy just before the plane took off:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Lisbon</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 21:09:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</guid><description>Teddy in Lisbon # After Apache Con I spent a few days in Lisbon for Codebits. The conference is not developers-only. It is more of a mixture of hacking event, conference, exhibition. Though the location was not optimal for giving presentations (large exhibition hall with now a rather noisy presentation area) the whole event brought quite an interesting mixture of people together in one place in the capital of Portugal.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Atlanta</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 23:24:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</guid><description>Teddy in Atlanta # While I was happily attending Apache Con US in Atlanta/GA my teddy had a closer look at the city: He first went to the centennial olympic park, took a picture of the world of coca-cola (wondering what strange kinds of museums there are in the US. After that he headed over to Midtown having a quiet time in the Piedmont park. And finally had a closer look at the private houses still decorated for Halloween.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Portugal</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 20:32:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</guid><description>Teddy in Portugal # During the past two weeks my teddy was on vacation. As destination he chose to fly to Portugal. One day was reserved for a visit to Lisboa, the capital city of the country. He also took a few really nice pictures there:
On his return, he was no longer alone. Seems like he found a cute little portugese girl friend:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/teddyGirlFriend.png&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
In addition he brought the following image.</description></item></channel></rss>