<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>release on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/release/</link><description>Recent content in release on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:21:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.4 release</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:21:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.4 release # On last Sunday the Apache Mahout project published the 0.4 release. Nearly every piece of the code has been refactored and improved since the last 0.3 release. The release was timed to happen exactly before Apache Con NA in Atlanta. As such it was published on October 31st - the Halloween release, sort-of.
Especially mentionable are the following improvements:
Model refactoring and CLI changes to improve integration and consistency</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.3 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-03-released64/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 15:22:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-03-released64/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.3 released # This week, Apache Mahout 0.3 was released. First of all thanks to all committers and contributors who made that possible: Thanks for all your hard work on making the code even faster and integrating even more algorithms.
To the highlights:
New: math and collections modules based on the high performance Colt library Faster Frequent Pattern Growth(FPGrowth) using FP-bonsai pruning
Parallel Dirichlet process clustering (model-based clustering algorithm)</description></item><item><title>Mahout 0.2 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 10:52:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</guid><description>Mahout 0.2 released # Apache Mahout 0.2 has been released and is now available for public download at http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/lucene/mahout
Up to date maven artifacts can be found in the Apache repository at
https://repository.apache.org/cont ent/repositories/releases/org/apache/mahout/
Apache Mahout is a subproject of Apache Lucene with the goal of delivering scalable machine learning algorithm implementations under the Apache license. http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
Mahout is a machine learning library meant to scale: Scale in terms of community to support anyone interested in using machine learning.</description></item></channel></rss>