<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Solr on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Solr/</link><description>Recent content in Solr on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:54:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Solr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheCon EU - part 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:54:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</guid><description>ApacheCon EU - part 09 # In the Solr track Elastic Search and Solr Cloud went into competition. The comparison itself was slightly apples-and-oranges like as the speaker compared the current ES version based on Lucene 3.x and Solr Cloud based on Lucene 4.0. During the comparison it still turned out that both solutions are more or less comparable - so choice again depends on your application. However I did like the conclusion: The speaker did not pick a clear winner in terms of projects.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 07</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 20:51:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 07 # Julien Nioche shared some details on the nutch crawler. Being the mother of all Hadoop projects (as in Hadoop was born out of developments inside of nutch) the project has become rather quite with a steady stream of development in the recent past. Julien himself uses the nutch for gathering crawled data for several customer projects - feeding this data into an NLP pipeline based on Behemoth that glues Mahout, UIMA and Gate together.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - Solr at Allegro</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-solr-at-allegro206/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 08:07:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-solr-at-allegro206/</guid><description>GeeCon - Solr at Allegro # One particularly interesting to me was on Allegro&amp;rsquo;s (polish Ebay) Solr usage. In terms of numbers: They have 20Mio offers in Poland, another 10Mio active offers in partnering countries. In addition in their index there are 50Mio inactive offers in Poland and 40 Mio closed offers outside that country. They serve 8Mio updates a day, that is 100 updates a second. Those are related to start/end of bidding phase, buy now actions, cancelled bids, bids themselves.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – last day</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 23:23:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</guid><description>Apache Con – last day # Day three of Apache Con started with interesting talks on Tomcat 7, including an introduction to the new features of that release. Those include better memory leak prevention and detection capabilities – the implementation of these capabilities have lead to the discovery of various leaks that appear under more or less weird circumstances in famous open source libraries and the JVM itself. But also better management and reporting facilities are part of the new release.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Some pictures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 11:00:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</guid><description>Some pictures # Uwe and Simon were so kind to take some pictures of the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_1.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_5.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
Thanks for the pictures.</description></item><item><title>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 20:42:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</guid><description>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene # Last week the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. Last speaker was Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene and Solr. The video is now available online:
Lucene Chris Male from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video to anyone who might be interested. Thank you Chris, for traveling over from Amsterdam for an awesome talk on spatial search.</description></item><item><title>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 15:09:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</guid><description>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords # Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Search, Store, Scale
7/8 June 2010
This is to announce the opening of the Berlin Buzzwords 2010 call for presentations. Berlin Buzzwords is the first conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany, taking place in Berlin.
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Slides are available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:49:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</guid><description>Slides are available # Slides for the last Hadoop Get Together are available online:
Spatial Search by Chris Male
HBase Patterns by Bob Schulze
Scaling product search with Hadoop and Lucene by Dragan Milosevic
My own little introduction, just in case you are interested.
Videos will follow as soon as the are ready. Watch this space for further updates.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:40:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010 # Today (or more correctly, yesterday) the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in newthinking store. I arrived rather early to have some time to do some planning for Berlin Buzzwords - got there nearly one hour before the meetup. However it did not take very long until first guests came to the store. So I quickly got my introductory slides in place - Martin from newthinking already had the room setup, camera in place and audio working.</description></item><item><title>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 08:40:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</guid><description>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: March 10th, 4p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 09:09:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</guid><description>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers # On Lucid Imaginations Blog Jay Hill published a great article on The seven deadly sins of solr. Basically it is a collection of his experiences &amp;ldquo;analyzing and evaluating a great many instances of Solr implementations, running in some of the largest Fortune 500 companies&amp;rdquo;. It is a collection of common mistakes, mis-configurations and pitfalls in Solr installations in production use.</description></item><item><title>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 22:07:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</guid><description>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr # The article was first published on Sesat Weblog. As the whole site went down several days ago, I retrieved the content from the Google cache and posted it here for perservation.
Update: Original site is up again.</description></item><item><title>Moving from Fast to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:34:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</guid><description>Moving from Fast to Solr # Sesat has published a nice in-depth report on why to move from Fast to Solr. The article also includes a description of the steps taken to move over as well as several statistics:
http://sesat.no/moving-from-fast-to-solr-review.html
On a related topic, the following article details, where Apple is using Lucene/Solr to power it&amp;rsquo;s search. Spoiler: Look at Spotlight, their desktop search, as well as on the iTunes search with about 800 QPS.</description></item><item><title>Solr at AOL</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 13:06:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</guid><description>Solr at AOL # Grant Ingersoll has posted a very interesting interview with Ian Holsman on Solr at Relegance, now AOL. It describes the business side of the decission to switch to an open source solution, provides some inside on the size of the installation and details which technological reasons have driven the decission to switch from a proprietary implementation to Solr:
http://www.lucidimagination.com/Community/Hear-from-the-Experts/Podcasts-and-Videos/Interview-Ian-Holsman-Relegence&amp;lt;/ a&amp;gt;</description></item></channel></rss>