<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>legal on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/legal/</link><description>Recent content in legal on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 20:41:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 20:41:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</guid><description>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04 # The panel started with a bit of history of the AGPL: Born in the age of growing ASP (application service provider) businesses AGPL tried to fix the hosting loop whole in GPL in the early 2000s. More than ten years later it turns out the license hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite caught traction: On the one hand the license does have a few wording issues.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 22:39:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</guid><description>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03 # In the next talk Gervase Markham talked about his experience working for Mozilla on legal and license questions. First the speaker summarized what kind of requests he gets most:
There are lots of technical support requests.
Next on the top list is the question for whether or not shipping Mozilla with a set of modifications is ok.
Next is an internal question, namely: Can I use this code?</description></item><item><title>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:38:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</guid><description>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02 # So the first talk I went to ended up being in the legal dev room on trademarks in open source projects. The speaker had a background mainly in US American trademark law and quite some background when it comes to open source licenses.
To start Pamela first showed a graphic detailing the various types of trademarks: In the pool of generic names there is a large group of trademarks that are in use but not registered.</description></item></channel></rss>