<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FrOSCon on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/FrOSCon/</link><description>Recent content in FrOSCon on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:34:49 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/FrOSCon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FrOSCon 2018</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:34:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2018 # A more general summary: https://tech.europace.de/froscon-2018/ of the conference written in German. Below a more detailed summary of the keynote by Lorena Jaume-Palasi.
In her keynote &amp;ldquo;Blessed by the algorithm - the computer says no!&amp;rdquo; Lorena detailed the intersection of ethics and technology when it comes to automated decision making systems. As much as humans with a technical training shy away from questions related to ethics, humans trained in ethics often shy away from topics that involve a technical layer.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - on teaching</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-on-teaching194/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 08:17:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-on-teaching194/</guid><description>FrOSCon - on teaching # The last talk I went to during FrOSCon was Selena&amp;rsquo;s keynote on &amp;ldquo;Mistakes were made&amp;rdquo;. She started by explaining how she taught computer science (or even just computer-) concepts to teachers herself - emphasizing how exhausting teaching can be, how many even trivial concepts were unknown to her students. After that Selena briefly sketched how she herself came to IT - emphasizing how providing mostly the information she needed to accomplish the current task at hand and telling how to get more information helped her make her first steps a great deal.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - Git Goodies</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-git-goodies193/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 20:34:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-git-goodies193/</guid><description>FrOSCon - Git Goodies # In his talk on Git Goodies Sebastian Harl introduced not only some of the lesser known git tooling but also gave a brief introduction as to how git organises its database. Starting with an explanation of how patches essentially are treated as blobs identified by SHA1 hashes (thus avoiding duplication not only in the local database but allover the git universe), pointed to by trees that are in turn generated and extended by commits that are in turn referenced by branches (updates on new commits) and tags (don&amp;rsquo;t update on new commits).</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - Robust Linux embedded platform</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-robust-linux-embedded-platform195/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 20:05:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-robust-linux-embedded-platform195/</guid><description>FrOSCon - Robust Linux embedded platform # The second talk I went to at FrOSCon was given by Thilo Fromm on Building a robust embedded Linux platform. For more information on the underlying project see also projec HidaV on github. Slides of the talk Building a robust Linux embedded platform are already online.
Inspired by a presentation on safe upgrade prodedures in embedded devices by Arnaut Vandecappelle in the Embedded Dev Room FOSDEM earlier this year Thilo extended the scope of the presentation a bit to cover safe kernel upgrades as well as package updates in embedded systems.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon 2012 - REST</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012-rest198/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 19:33:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012-rest198/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2012 - REST # Together with Thilo I went to FrOSCon last weekend. Despite a few minor glitches and the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; long BBQ line the conference was very well organised and again brought together a very diverse crowd of people including but not limited to Debian developers, OpenOffice people, FSFE representatives, KDE and Gnome developers, people with background in Lisp, Clojure, PHP, Java, C and HTML5.
The first talk we went to was given by JThijssen on REST in practice.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012197/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 20:25:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012197/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2012 # On August 25th/26th the Free and Open Source Conference (FrOSCon) will again kick off in Sankt Augustin/ Germany. The event is completely community organised, hosted by the FH Sankt Augustin. It covers a broad range of free software topics like Arduino microcontrollers, git goodies, politics, strace, open nebula, wireshark and others.
Three highlights that are on my schedule:
I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure I do not miss Thilo Fromm&amp;rsquo;s presentation on building a platform project on top of Open Embedded.</description></item><item><title>Flying back home from Cologne</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:40:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</guid><description>Flying back home from Cologne # Last weekend FrOSCon took place in Sankt Augustin, near Cologne. FrOSCon is organized on a yearly basis at the university of applied sciences in Sankt Augustin. It is a volunteer driven event with the goal of bringing developers and users of free software projects together. This year, the conference featured 5 tracks, two examples being cloud computing and the Java track.
Unfortunately this year the conference started with a little surprise for me and my boyfriend: Being both speakers, we had booked a room in Hotel Regina via the conference committee.</description></item></channel></rss>