<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>conferences on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/conferences/</link><description>Recent content in conferences on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:34:49 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FrOSCon 2018</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:34:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2018 # A more general summary: https://tech.europace.de/froscon-2018/ of the conference written in German. Below a more detailed summary of the keynote by Lorena Jaume-Palasi.
In her keynote &amp;ldquo;Blessed by the algorithm - the computer says no!&amp;rdquo; Lorena detailed the intersection of ethics and technology when it comes to automated decision making systems. As much as humans with a technical training shy away from questions related to ethics, humans trained in ethics often shy away from topics that involve a technical layer.</description></item><item><title>On geeks growing up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-geeks-growing-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 05:49:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-geeks-growing-up/</guid><description>On geeks growing up # I&amp;rsquo;m a regular visitor of the Chemnitzer Linuxtage in March - at first going to talks learning lots of interesting stuff I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about like aspect oriented programming, strace, squeak, which open source licenses are best for different strategies. As of late I had been there mostly to help out with the FSFE booth. For context: The conference itself is hosted by the technical university in Chemnitz, it takes place on a weekend, they charge the tiny amount of 5 Euros for admission.</description></item><item><title>Some thoughts on a conf taxonomy</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-thoughts-on-a-conf-taxonomy380/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 12:53:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-thoughts-on-a-conf-taxonomy380/</guid><description>Some thoughts on a conf taxonomy # One common way for open source developers to meet face-to-face is to attend conferences relevant to their subject of interest. A common way to have one near you if there ain&amp;rsquo;t none yet is to go and organise one yourself. The most obvious stuff to resolve for that task:
Most likely there will be some financial transactions involved - sponsors wanting to support you, attendees paying for their tickets, you paying for the venue and for food.</description></item></channel></rss>