<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning To Rank on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Learning-To-Rank/</link><description>Recent content in Learning To Rank on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 11:38:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Learning-To-Rank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A short, incomprehensive history of spam and counter measures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/spam-spam-spam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 11:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/spam-spam-spam/</guid><description>A short, incomprehensive history of spam and counter measures # &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; it should be clear that improvements in communication tend to divide mankind &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; by Harold Innis in Changing Concepts of Time
This post was triggered by multiple conversations in my big data circle of friends. All conversations agreed on some important topics: Social media sites these days are influential on the daily life of people globally. With that influence comes an incentive to use these sites to influence behaviour and public opinion.</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>Learning to Rank Challenge</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:49:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</guid><description>Learning to Rank Challenge # In one of his recent blog posts, Jeff Dalton published an article on currently running machine learning challenges. Especially interesting for those working on search engines and interested in learning new rankings from data should be the Yahoo! Learning to Rank Challenge to be held in conjunction with this year&amp;rsquo;s ICML 2010 in Haifa, Israel. The goal is to show that your algorithm does not only scale on real-world data provided by Yahoo!</description></item></channel></rss>