<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>review on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/review/</link><description>Recent content in review on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 11:21:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 11:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</guid><description>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords # Disclaimer: Intentionally posting on my private blog - these are my own criteria, not general advice from the review committee.
Berlin Buzzwords is in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth year. Probably the most tedious task of all is having to select talks to make it into the final schedule. With roughly 120 submissions and roughly 30 slots to fill the result is that three quarters of all submissions have to be rejected.</description></item><item><title>On Taming Text</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</guid><description>On Taming Text # This time of the year I would usually post pictures of my bicycle standing in the snow somewhere in Tierpark. This year however I was tricked into using public transport instead: a) After my husband found a new job, we now share some of the route to work - and he isn&amp;rsquo;t crazy going by bike when it&amp;rsquo;s snowing. b) I got myself a Nexus7 earlier this month which obsoleted having to take paper books with me when using public transport.</description></item><item><title>Book: Search Patterns</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/book-search-patterns127/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 20:41:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/book-search-patterns127/</guid><description>Book: Search Patterns # I got the book months ago during FOSDEM - the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly book table always is a pretty dangerous place as a meeting point for me: Search Patterns - Design for Discovery is one of those small, deceivingly beautiful books that manages to explain effective search engine design by focusing on the end user needs but going into some detail concerning the basics of search engine backends as well.</description></item></channel></rss>