<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Atlanta on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Atlanta/</link><description>Recent content in Atlanta on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 23:27:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Atlanta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Con – Wrap up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 23:27:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-wrap-up16/</guid><description>Apache Con – Wrap up # After one week of lots of interesting input the ASF&amp;rsquo;s user conference was over. With a focus on Apache software users quite a few talks are not too well suited for conference regulars but more or less targeted at newbies who want to know who too successfully apply the software. As a developer of Mahout with close ties to the Lucene and Hadoop community what is of course most interesting to me are stories of users putting the software into production.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Atlanta</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 23:24:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-atlanta394/</guid><description>Teddy in Atlanta # While I was happily attending Apache Con US in Atlanta/GA my teddy had a closer look at the city: He first went to the centennial olympic park, took a picture of the world of coca-cola (wondering what strange kinds of museums there are in the US. After that he headed over to Midtown having a quiet time in the Piedmont park. And finally had a closer look at the private houses still decorated for Halloween.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 23:19:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-hadoop-hbase-httpd13/</guid><description>Apache Con – Hadoop, HBase, Httpd # The first Apache Con day featured several presentations on NoSQL databases (track sponsored by Day software), a Hadoop track as well as presentations on Httpd and an Open source business track. Since its inception Hadoop always was intended to be run in trusted environments firewalled from hostile users or even attackers. As such it never really supported any security features. This is about the change with the new Hadoop release including better Kerberos based security.</description></item></channel></rss>