<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux Foundation on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Linux-Foundation/</link><description>Recent content in Linux Foundation on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:35:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Linux-Foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Source Summit - Day 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:35:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</guid><description>Open Source Summit - Day 3 # Open source summit Wednesday started with a keynote by members of the Banks family telling a packed room on how they approached raising a tech family. The first hurdle that Keila (the teenage daughter of the family) talked about was something I personally had never actually thought about: Communication tools like Slack that are in widespread use come with an age restriction excluding minors.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 13:18:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</guid><description>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1 # Open Source Summit, formerly known as LinuxCon, this year took place in Prague. Drawing some 2000 attendees to the lovely Czech city, the conference focussed on all things Linux kernel, containers, community and governance. The first day started with three crowded keynotes: First one by Neha Narkhede on Keynotes Apache Kafka and the Rise of the Streaming Platform. Second one by Reuben Paul (11 years old) on how hacking today really is just childs play: The hack itself might seem like toying around (getting into the protocol of children's toys in order to make them do things without using the app that was intended to control them).</description></item></channel></rss>