<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>codebits on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/codebits/</link><description>Recent content in codebits on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:11:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/codebits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:11:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</guid><description>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol # Caught Teddy just before the plane took off:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Lisbon</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 21:09:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</guid><description>Teddy in Lisbon # After Apache Con I spent a few days in Lisbon for Codebits. The conference is not developers-only. It is more of a mixture of hacking event, conference, exhibition. Though the location was not optimal for giving presentations (large exhibition hall with now a rather noisy presentation area) the whole event brought quite an interesting mixture of people together in one place in the capital of Portugal.</description></item><item><title>Travelling</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 23:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</guid><description>Travelling # Currently on my way back from a series of conferences in the past three weeks in the IC from Schiphol. After three weeks of conferences, lots of new input and lots of interesting projects I learned about it is finally time to head back and put the stuff I have learned to good use.
View Travelling in a larger map
As seems normal with open source conferences I got far more input on interesting projects than I can expect to ever get applied in on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 09:36:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits # Second week of November I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few days in Lisbon - never would have thought that I&amp;rsquo;d return so quickly when I visited this beautiful city this summer during vacation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for Codebits - thanks to Sapo for inviting me to be there.
Back in summer I learned only after I returned to Germany that there was someone form Portugal seeking to meet with other Apache people exactly when I was down there.</description></item></channel></rss>