<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lean on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/lean/</link><description>Recent content in lean on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 17:53:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/lean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agile, inner source, open development, open source development</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/agile-inner-source-open-development-open-source-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 17:53:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/agile-inner-source-open-development-open-source-development/</guid><description>Agile, inner source, open development, open source development # Last week I had the honour of giving a keynote at Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Open Source Summit EU in Basel. Among many interesting talks they hosted a panel to answer questions around all things open source, strategy, inner source, open development. One of the questions I found intersting is how inner source/ open development and agile are related.
To get everyone on the same page, what do I mean when talking about inner source/ open development?</description></item><item><title>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 21:38:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</guid><description>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin # This evening Mary Poppendieck gave a presentation on Design Thinking in Berlin. &amp;ldquo;What does the US Military have in common with Apple?&amp;rdquo; In her talk Mary went into more detail about how increasing complexity calls for a need to rethink design. Slides are available online. Thanks for sharing them.
Mary started with a question for the audience on who in your company decides what is to be developed: Is it the PO?</description></item><item><title>Berlin Scrumtisch - February 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-february-2011122/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 21:33:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-february-2011122/</guid><description>Berlin Scrumtisch - February 2011 # The February Scrumtisch Berlin featured a talk by Lyssa Adkins, famously known for her publications on Coaching Agile teams. A mixture of fifty developers, scrum masters, coaches and product owner as well as one project manager followed Marion Eikmann&amp;rsquo;s invitation. Thanks for organising the event, as well as thank you to Hypoport for providing the venue.
In her one-hour presentation she mainly focussed on two core topics: On the roles agile coaches have to fullfill as well as on the skill set needed by agile coaches.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch with Mary and Tom Poppendiek</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-with-mary-and-tom-poppendiek360/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:07:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-with-mary-and-tom-poppendiek360/</guid><description>Scrumtisch with Mary and Tom Poppendiek # Yesterday evening the Scrumtisch Berlin hosted a talk by Mary Poppendiek on Lean Development. Mary started the session with a talk on what lean development is all about and why it goes further than Scrum ever did. Some of the core principles she explained:
The first goal of every lean project should be to strive for customer satisfaction. The low hanging fruit is to do exactly what the customer wanted to have.</description></item></channel></rss>