<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ApacheConEU09 on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConEU09/</link><description>Recent content in ApacheConEU09 on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:56:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConEU09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:56:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3 # Friday was the last conference day. I enjoyed the Apache pioneers panel with a brief history of the Apache Software Foundation as well as lots of stories on how people first got in contact with the ASF.
After lunch I went to the testing and cloud session. I enjoyed the talk on continuum and its uses by Wendy Smoak. She gave a basic overview of why one would want a CI system and provided a brief introduction to continuum.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:42:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2 # Thursday morning started with an interesting talk on open source collaboration tools and how they can help resolving some collaboration overhead on commercial software projects. Four goals can be reached with the help of the right tools: Sharing the project vision, tracking the current status of the project, finding places to help the project and documenting the project history as well as the reasons for decisions along the way.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 18:41:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1 # The past week members, committers and users of Apache software projects gathered in Amsterdam for another Apache Con EU
and to celebrate the 10th birthday of the ASF. One week dedicated to the development and use of Free Software and the Apache Way.
Monday was BarCamp day for me, the first BarCamp I ever attended. Unfortunately not all participants proposed talks. So some of the atmosphere of an unconference was missing.</description></item></channel></rss>