<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lucene on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Lucene/</link><description>Recent content in Lucene on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 20:17:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Lucene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello elasticsearch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hello-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 20:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hello-elasticsearch/</guid><description>Hello elasticsearch # First of all a disclaimer: I had a little bit of time left during the last few weeks. As a result my blog migrated from dynamic wordpress content to statically hosted pages. If anything looks odd, in case you find any encoding issues, if you miss specific functionality - please do let me know. I&amp;rsquo;ll switch from this beta url back to the old sub-domain in a week or so unless there are major complaints.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Search meetup Berlin – January 2013</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin-january-2013168/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 18:34:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin-january-2013168/</guid><description>Elastic Search meetup Berlin – January 2013 # The first meetup this year I went to started with a large bag of good news for Elastic Search users. In the offices of Sys Eleven (thanks for hosting) the meetup started at 7p.m. last Tuesday. Simon Willnauer gave an overview of what to expect of the upcoming major release of Elastic Search:
For all 0.20.x version ES features a shard allocator version that is ignorant of which index shards belong to, machine properties, usage patterns.</description></item><item><title>On Taming Text</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</guid><description>On Taming Text # This time of the year I would usually post pictures of my bicycle standing in the snow somewhere in Tierpark. This year however I was tricked into using public transport instead: a) After my husband found a new job, we now share some of the route to work - and he isn&amp;rsquo;t crazy going by bike when it&amp;rsquo;s snowing. b) I got myself a Nexus7 earlier this month which obsoleted having to take paper books with me when using public transport.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Search meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:39:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</guid><description>Elastic Search meetup Berlin # Today Retresco hosted the (to my knowledge fourth) Elastic Search User Group Berlin - a group dedicated to using Lucene as part of Elastic Search. With roughly fifteen attendees the meetup attracted a decent crowd - most interestingly many of the people there were already using the software either in production or for closed beta projects.
The fist talk given was by people from ferret-go - a company doing media monitoring for brands focused on the German market.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 10</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-1096/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 20:34:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-1096/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 10 # In the next session Jukka introduced Tika - a toolkit for parsing content from files including a heuristics based component for guessing the file type: Based on file extension, magic and certain patterns in the file the file type can be guessed rather reliably. Some anecdotes:
not all mime types are registered with IANA, there are of course conflicting file extensions,
Microsoft Word not only localises their interface but also the magic in the file,</description></item><item><title>ApacheCon EU - part 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 20:54:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-eu-part-0987/</guid><description>ApacheCon EU - part 09 # In the Solr track Elastic Search and Solr Cloud went into competition. The comparison itself was slightly apples-and-oranges like as the speaker compared the current ES version based on Lucene 3.x and Solr Cloud based on Lucene 4.0. During the comparison it still turned out that both solutions are more or less comparable - so choice again depends on your application. However I did like the conclusion: The speaker did not pick a clear winner in terms of projects.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 07</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 20:51:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part-0794/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 07 # Julien Nioche shared some details on the nutch crawler. Being the mother of all Hadoop projects (as in Hadoop was born out of developments inside of nutch) the project has become rather quite with a steady stream of development in the recent past. Julien himself uses the nutch for gathering crawled data for several customer projects - feeding this data into an NLP pipeline based on Behemoth that glues Mahout, UIMA and Gate together.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - Solr at Allegro</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-solr-at-allegro206/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 08:07:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-solr-at-allegro206/</guid><description>GeeCon - Solr at Allegro # One particularly interesting to me was on Allegro&amp;rsquo;s (polish Ebay) Solr usage. In terms of numbers: They have 20Mio offers in Poland, another 10Mio active offers in partnering countries. In addition in their index there are 50Mio inactive offers in Poland and 40 Mio closed offers outside that country. They serve 8Mio updates a day, that is 100 updates a second. Those are related to start/end of bidding phase, buy now actions, cancelled bids, bids themselves.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 10:29:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now # As of beginning of last week the Berlin Buzzwords schedule is online. The Program Committee has completed reviewing all submissions and set up the schedule containing a great lineup of speakers for this years Berlin Buzzwords program. Among the speakers we have Leslie Hawthorn (Red Hat), Alex Lloyd (Google), Michael Busch (Twitter) as well as Nicolas Spiegelberg (Facebook). Checkout our program in the online schedule.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 16:20:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over # Apache Hadoop receives lots of attention from large US corporations who are using the project to scale their data processing pipelines:
“Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive extensively to process large data sets. [&amp;hellip;]” (Ashish Thusoo, Engineering Manager at Facebook), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop is a key ingredient in allowing LinkedIn to build many of our most computationally difficult features [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo; (Jay Kreps, Principal Engineer, LinkedIn), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop enables [Twitter] to store, process, and derive insights from our data in ways that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise be possible.</description></item><item><title>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</guid><description>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale # This is to announce the Berlin Buzzwords 2011. The second edition of the successful conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany,
taking place in Berlin.
Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - Search, Store, Scale
6/7 June 2011
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>WiFi at the Apache Hadoop Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wifi-at-the-apache-hadoop-get-together433/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 20:40:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wifi-at-the-apache-hadoop-get-together433/</guid><description>WiFi at the Apache Hadoop Get Together # Just a brief reminder: The next Apache Hadoop Get Together is scheduled to take place on Thursday, January 27th at 6p.m. at the Zanox Event Campus at Media Spree Berlin.
We have three very interesting talks, though thirty guests registered already, we still have a few free seats. Head over to the xing event page to register if you have not done so yet.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 16:31:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by Cloudera and Zanox that will take place in the Zanox Event Campus in Berlin.
When: January 27th 2011, 6p.m.
Where: zanox Event Campus (Please mark the changed event location.)
&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Größere Kartenansicht
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss.</description></item><item><title>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 06:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</guid><description>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011 # Call for Presentations: Data Analysis Dev Room, FOSDEM
http://fosdem.org
5 February 2011
1pm to 7pm
Brussels, Belgium
This is to announce the Data Analysis DevRoom co-located with FOSDEM. The first Meetup on analysing and learning from data, taking place in Brussels, Belgium.
Important Dates (all dates in GMT +2):
Submission deadline: 2010-12-17
Notification of accepted speakers: 2010-12-20
Publication of final schedule: 2011-01-10</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 20:39:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</guid><description>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA # The upcoming Apache Con NA to take place in Atlanta will feature several tracks relevant to users of Apache Mahout, Lucene and Hadoop: There will be a full track on Hadoop as well as one on NoSQL on Wednesday featuring talks on the framework itself, Pig and Hive as well as presentations from users on special use cases and on their way of getting the system to production.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:54:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</guid><description>Apache Dinner June 2010 # After Berlin Buzzwords was over yesterday - and as there is an svn conference in the city that starts tomorrow, we thought we could easily put together a smallish Apache Dinner for tonight. So Torsten mailed a few people, booked some space at Heinz Minki in Kreuzberg. We announced it at the end of the conference and invited people to join us.
So after a beautiful day out I spent the evening with a bunch of Apache related guys and girls having drinks and great pizza: We had several svn committers, Greg Stein met us there - he arrived today for the svn conference.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Going to Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 08:46:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</guid><description>Going to Berlin Buzzwords # Meet me in two weeks at Berlin Buzzwords. As you may have noticed, together with Simon Willnauer, Jan Lehnardt and newthinking communications I am organising Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scalable search, data analysis and storage.
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://berlinbuzzwords.de/sites/berlinbuzzwords.de/files/buzzwords_banner.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to Berlin Buzzwords
the conference on searching, processing and storing data.&amp;rdquo;/&amp;gt;
There are a few regular tickets left, so don&amp;rsquo;t wait too long to register.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 15:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin # The Berlin Buzzwords schedule was published a few days ago. There are tracks specific to the three tags search, store and scale. We have a fantastic mixture of developers and users of open source software projects that make scaling data processing today possible.
There is Steve Loughran, Aaron Kimball and Stefan Groschupf from the Apache Hadoop community. We have Grant Ingersoll, Robert Muir and the &amp;ldquo;Generics Policeman&amp;rdquo; Uwe Schindler from the Lucene community.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 14:55:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer # One week to go for submitting a talk on your favourite NoSQL topic, your favourite search application or your most interesting data analysis task: The call for presentations for Berlin Buzzwords ends on April 17th, that is Sunday next week.
Shortly after the last talk was submitted we will start announcing speakers - final list of speakers is to be expected by the start of May, final schedule will be published shortly after that.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 20:42:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</guid><description>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene # Last week the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. Last speaker was Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene and Solr. The video is now available online:
Lucene Chris Male from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video to anyone who might be interested. Thank you Chris, for traveling over from Amsterdam for an awesome talk on spatial search.</description></item><item><title>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 15:09:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</guid><description>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords # Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Search, Store, Scale
7/8 June 2010
This is to announce the opening of the Berlin Buzzwords 2010 call for presentations. Berlin Buzzwords is the first conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany, taking place in Berlin.
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Slides are available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:49:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</guid><description>Slides are available # Slides for the last Hadoop Get Together are available online:
Spatial Search by Chris Male
HBase Patterns by Bob Schulze
Scaling product search with Hadoop and Lucene by Dragan Milosevic
My own little introduction, just in case you are interested.
Videos will follow as soon as the are ready. Watch this space for further updates.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:40:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010 # Today (or more correctly, yesterday) the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in newthinking store. I arrived rather early to have some time to do some planning for Berlin Buzzwords - got there nearly one hour before the meetup. However it did not take very long until first guests came to the store. So I quickly got my introductory slides in place - Martin from newthinking already had the room setup, camera in place and audio working.</description></item><item><title>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 18:34:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</guid><description>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open # Silently registration was opened in the past days for Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scaling search, data processing and storage taking place on June 7th/8th in Berlin/ Germany. First 100 tickets will be sold for 250 Euros + tax. Registration is possible at later dates as well, however expect prizes to rise shortly before the conference starts.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010 # As announced at FOSDEM: Early June (currently scheduled for 7th/8th) a conference on the topics scalable search, storage and processing will take place in Kalkscheune/Berlin. The conference is co-organised by newthinking store, Jan Lehnardt, Simon Willnauer, Thilo Fromm, and Isabel Drost.
The focus will be on NoSQL databases like CouchDB, Jackrabbit, MongoDB, HBase. Search tracks will cover topics like Lucene, Solr, katta and others.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop at Heise c't</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 13:37:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</guid><description>Hadoop at Heise c&amp;rsquo;t # &amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising&amp;gt;
Interesting for those readers speaking German: Heise published an introductory article on Hadoop in its latest issue. Have fun reading.
&amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising/&amp;gt;
Thanks to Simon for proof-reading and providing valuable input. Thanks to Thilo Fromm for the hadoop graphics (unfortunately none of them got published in its original form), the catchy title, proof-reading the text over and over again and for keeping me sane during several past and coming months.</description></item><item><title>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 09:09:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</guid><description>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers # On Lucid Imaginations Blog Jay Hill published a great article on The seven deadly sins of solr. Basically it is a collection of his experiences &amp;ldquo;analyzing and evaluating a great many instances of Solr implementations, running in some of the largest Fortune 500 companies&amp;rdquo;. It is a collection of common mistakes, mis-configurations and pitfalls in Solr installations in production use.</description></item><item><title>With a little help from my friends</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 23:55:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</guid><description>With a little help from my friends # The end of the year 2009 is quickly approaching. To me it feels a little like it ran away far too quickly. So instead of taking part in the annual review of past events, I would like to use it as an opportunity to say thank you: The past twelve months were a lot of fun with lots of interesting, nice people from all over the world.</description></item><item><title>Moving from Fast to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:34:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</guid><description>Moving from Fast to Solr # Sesat has published a nice in-depth report on why to move from Fast to Solr. The article also includes a description of the steps taken to move over as well as several statistics:
http://sesat.no/moving-from-fast-to-solr-review.html
On a related topic, the following article details, where Apple is using Lucene/Solr to power it&amp;rsquo;s search. Spoiler: Look at Spotlight, their desktop search, as well as on the iTunes search with about 800 QPS.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</guid><description>Open Source Expo 09 # I spent last Sunday and the following Monday at Open Source Expo Karlsruhe - co-located with web-tech and php-conference organized by the Software-and-Support Verlag. Together with Simon Willnauer I ran the Lucene/Mahout booth at the expo.
So far the conference is still very small (about 400 visitors) compared to free software community events. However the focus was set to be more on professional users, accordingly several projects showed that free software can be used successfully for various business use cases.</description></item><item><title>Lucene Meetup Oakland</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-meetup-oakland269/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 06:05:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-meetup-oakland269/</guid><description>Lucene Meetup Oakland # Though pretty late in the evening the room is packed with some 100 people. Most of them solr or pure lucene java users. There are quite a few Lucene committers at the meetup from all over the world. Several even have heard about Mahout - some even used it :)
Some introductiory questions to index sizes and query volumn: 1 Mio documents seem pretty standard for Lucene deployments - several people run 10 Mio neither.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:38:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</guid><description>Open Source Expo # Title: Open Source Expo
Location: Karlsruhe
Link out: Click here
Description: There will be a booth at Open source expo introducing interested visitors to the Apache projects Lucene and Mahout. Of course we are also happy to answer any questions on the ASF in general.
Start Date: 2009-11-15
End Date: 2009-11-16</description></item><item><title>Lucene 2.9 White Paper</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-white-paper268/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 21:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-white-paper268/</guid><description>Lucene 2.9 White Paper # Lucid recently published a white paper that explains the changes and improvements that the new 2.9 release incorporates. Interesting for all who are thinking about upgrading to the new lucene version or generally want to know what is going on at Lucene.</description></item><item><title>Videos are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/videos-are-up429/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 07:31:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/videos-are-up429/</guid><description>Videos are up # As of yesterday the videos of the last Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are available online.
Th anks to the speakers for providing insight in their projects and thanks to Cloudera for sponsoring the videos.
The next meetup will be announced soon - three talks have already been proposed. In addition, StudiVZ offered to sponsor video taping of the next Get Together. Looking forward to seeing you in Berlin in December.</description></item><item><title>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 18:13:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</guid><description>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise # After last week&amp;rsquo;s Hadoop Get Together heise published an in-depth article on the changes and improvements that come with the latest Lucene 2.9 release.
Thanks to Simon Willnauer for helping me write this article and patiently explaining several new features. Thanks also to Uwe Schindler for kindly proof-reading the article before it was sent out to Heise.</description></item><item><title>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 19:00:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</guid><description>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is a friendly reminder that the next Apache Hadoop Get Together takes place next week on Tuesday, 29th of September* at newthinking store (Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin).
Thorsten Schuett, Solving Puzzles with MapReduce.
Thilo Götz, Text analytics on jaql.
Uwe Schindler, Lucene 2.9 Developments.
Big thanks goes to newthinking store for providing the venue for free and to Cloudera for sponsoring videos of the talks.</description></item><item><title>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 09:11:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</guid><description>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The newthinking store Berlin is hosting the Hadoop Get Together user group meeting. It features talks on Hadoop, Lucene, Solr, UIMA, katta, Mahout and various other projects that deal with making large amounts of data accessible and processable. The event brings together leaders from the developer and user communities. The speakers present projects that build on top of Hadoop, case studies of applications being built and deployed on Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Lucene slides online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 10:04:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</guid><description>Lucene slides online # The slides of the Lucene talk at the last Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are available online: Lucene Slides. Especially interesting to me are the last few slides which detail both index size and machine setup:
The installation is running on two standard PCs with 2 dual-core processors (usual speed, bought in January 2008 for about 4000 Euro). They have 32GB RAM, 24 GB are used as ramdisk for the index.</description></item></channel></rss>