<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Buzzwords on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Buzzwords/</link><description>Recent content in Buzzwords on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:29:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Buzzwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PyCon/ PyData DE - Invited to give a keynote</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/2025_04_pyconde/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:29:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/2025_04_pyconde/</guid><description>How I was invited to give a keynote in Darmstadt # It was autumn 2009 at an ApacheCon in Oakland/ California: I asked one of my fellow ASF people what it would take to get him to visit Berlin. The flippant, not quite serious, joking answer: &amp;ldquo;Someone to fund for my flight tickets.&amp;rdquo; Fast forward six months. I got back to that lovely person with a newly created Berlin Buzzwords conference and enough sponsorship budget to pay for keynote speaker travel.</description></item><item><title>Presentation shortening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/presentation-shortening328/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 20:23:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/presentation-shortening328/</guid><description>Presentation shortening # In an effort to make more room for more talks in our schedule for this year&amp;rsquo;s Berlin Buzzwords we&amp;rsquo;ve asked quite a few people to shorten their presentation from 40min down to 20min. The thought behind it is to not only give more people a chance to talk on their work but also have those shorter talks focused down to the absolute essential information for people to learn.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 15:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin # The Berlin Buzzwords schedule was published a few days ago. There are tracks specific to the three tags search, store and scale. We have a fantastic mixture of developers and users of open source software projects that make scaling data processing today possible.
There is Steve Loughran, Aaron Kimball and Stefan Groschupf from the Apache Hadoop community. We have Grant Ingersoll, Robert Muir and the &amp;ldquo;Generics Policeman&amp;rdquo; Uwe Schindler from the Lucene community.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:40:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010 # Today (or more correctly, yesterday) the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in newthinking store. I arrived rather early to have some time to do some planning for Berlin Buzzwords - got there nearly one hour before the meetup. However it did not take very long until first guests came to the store. So I quickly got my introductory slides in place - Martin from newthinking already had the room setup, camera in place and audio working.</description></item></channel></rss>