<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NOSQL on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/NOSQL/</link><description>Recent content in NOSQL on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 17:10:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/NOSQL/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wonder if you should switch from your RDBMS to Apache Hadoop: Don't!</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wonder-if-you-should-switch-from-your-rdbms-to-apache-hadoop-dont436/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 17:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wonder-if-you-should-switch-from-your-rdbms-to-apache-hadoop-dont436/</guid><description>Wonder if you should switch from your RDBMS to Apache Hadoop: Don&amp;rsquo;t! # Last weekend I spend a lot of fun time at FrOSCon* in Sankt Augustin - always great to catch up with friends in the open source space. As always there were quite a few talks on NoSQL, Hadoop, but also really solid advise on tuning your system for stuff like MySQL (including a side note on PostgreSQL and Oracle) from Kristian Köhntopp.</description></item><item><title>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 20:59:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</guid><description>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin # Interested in Apache Sling and/or Apache Jackrabbit? Then you might be interested in hearing that on September 26th to 28th there will be an event in town on these two topics - mainly organised by Adobe, but labeled as community event, meaning that there will be a number of active community members attending the conference: adaptTo().
From their website:
In late September 2012 Berlin will become the global heart beat for developers working on the Adobe CQ technical stack.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 16:20:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over # Apache Hadoop receives lots of attention from large US corporations who are using the project to scale their data processing pipelines:
“Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive extensively to process large data sets. [&amp;hellip;]” (Ashish Thusoo, Engineering Manager at Facebook), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop is a key ingredient in allowing LinkedIn to build many of our most computationally difficult features [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo; (Jay Kreps, Principal Engineer, LinkedIn), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop enables [Twitter] to store, process, and derive insights from our data in ways that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise be possible.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 21:25:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase # Devoxx featured several interesting case studies of how HBase and Hadoop can be used to scale data analysis back ends as well as data serving front ends. Twitter
Dmitry Ryaboy from Twitter explained how to scale high load and large data systems using Cassandra. Looking at the sheer amount of tweets generated each day it becomes obvious that with a system like MySQL alone this site cannot be run.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 21:20:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</guid><description>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase # During the morning session FIXME Ellison gave an introduction to the distributed NoSQL database Cassandra. Being generally based on the Dynamo paper from Amazon the key-value store distributes key/value pairs according to a consistent hashing schema. Nodes can be added dynamically making the system well suited for elastic scaling. In contrast to Dynamo, Cassandra can be tuned for the required consistency level. The system is tuned for storing moderately sized key/value pairs.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx University – MongoDB, Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-mongodb-mahout160/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 21:19:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-mongodb-mahout160/</guid><description>Devoxx University – MongoDB, Mahout # The second tutorial was given by Roger Bodamer on MongoDB. It concentrates on being horizontally scalable by avoiding joins and complex, multi document transactions. It supports a new data model that allows for flexible, changeable &amp;ldquo;schemas&amp;rdquo;. The exact data layout is determined by the types of operations you expect for your application, by the access patterns (reading vs. writing data; types of updates and types of queries).</description></item><item><title>Devoxx Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 21:16:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</guid><description>Devoxx Antwerp # With 3000 attendees Devoxx is the largest Java Community conference world-wide. Each year in autumn it takes place in Antwerp/ Belgium, in recent years in the Metropolis cinema. The conference tickets were sold out long before doors were opened this year.
The focus of the presentations are mainly on enterprise Java featuring talks by famous Joshua Bloch, Mark Reihnhold and others on new features of the upcoming JDK release as well as intricacies of the Java programming language itself.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 20:39:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</guid><description>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA # The upcoming Apache Con NA to take place in Atlanta will feature several tracks relevant to users of Apache Mahout, Lucene and Hadoop: There will be a full track on Hadoop as well as one on NoSQL on Wednesday featuring talks on the framework itself, Pig and Hive as well as presentations from users on special use cases and on their way of getting the system to production.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 06:38:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</guid><description>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening # This evening at Volkspark Friedrichshain, Café Schoenbrunn the next NoSQL summer Berlin (organised by Tim Lossen) is meeting to discuss the paper on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Dynamo &amp;ldquo;Dynamo: Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Highly Available Key-value Store&amp;rdquo;. The group is planning to meet at 19:30 for some beer and discussions on the publication.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Going to Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 08:46:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</guid><description>Going to Berlin Buzzwords # Meet me in two weeks at Berlin Buzzwords. As you may have noticed, together with Simon Willnauer, Jan Lehnardt and newthinking communications I am organising Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scalable search, data analysis and storage.
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://berlinbuzzwords.de/sites/berlinbuzzwords.de/files/buzzwords_banner.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to Berlin Buzzwords
the conference on searching, processing and storing data.&amp;rdquo;/&amp;gt;
There are a few regular tickets left, so don&amp;rsquo;t wait too long to register.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 15:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin # The Berlin Buzzwords schedule was published a few days ago. There are tracks specific to the three tags search, store and scale. We have a fantastic mixture of developers and users of open source software projects that make scaling data processing today possible.
There is Steve Loughran, Aaron Kimball and Stefan Groschupf from the Apache Hadoop community. We have Grant Ingersoll, Robert Muir and the &amp;ldquo;Generics Policeman&amp;rdquo; Uwe Schindler from the Lucene community.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 14:55:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer # One week to go for submitting a talk on your favourite NoSQL topic, your favourite search application or your most interesting data analysis task: The call for presentations for Berlin Buzzwords ends on April 17th, that is Sunday next week.
Shortly after the last talk was submitted we will start announcing speakers - final list of speakers is to be expected by the start of May, final schedule will be published shortly after that.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 15:09:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</guid><description>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords # Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Search, Store, Scale
7/8 June 2010
This is to announce the opening of the Berlin Buzzwords 2010 call for presentations. Berlin Buzzwords is the first conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany, taking place in Berlin.
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 18:34:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</guid><description>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open # Silently registration was opened in the past days for Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scaling search, data processing and storage taking place on June 7th/8th in Berlin/ Germany. First 100 tickets will be sold for 250 Euros + tax. Registration is possible at later dates as well, however expect prizes to rise shortly before the conference starts.</description></item><item><title>Open Community Camp 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 13:07:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</guid><description>Open Community Camp 2010 # The following information just reached my via Marten Vijn. Thought it might be interesting to you:
I am pleased to announce OpenCommunityCamp 2010.
The camp is from 10th to 18th July, in Oegstgeest, the Netherlands.
The website[1] is refreshed and the first speakers are booked.
It is time to register[2] if you plan be there (please do this
quickly). Currently we need to find more people to attend, self-organizing groups</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010 # As announced at FOSDEM: Early June (currently scheduled for 7th/8th) a conference on the topics scalable search, storage and processing will take place in Kalkscheune/Berlin. The conference is co-organised by newthinking store, Jan Lehnardt, Simon Willnauer, Thilo Fromm, and Isabel Drost.
The focus will be on NoSQL databases like CouchDB, Jackrabbit, MongoDB, HBase. Search tracks will cover topics like Lucene, Solr, katta and others.</description></item><item><title>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:58:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</guid><description>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany # On October 22nd 2009 the first NoSQL Meetup Germany is going to take place in newthinking store/ Berlin: http://nosqlberlin.de
Please submit your presentation proposals until September 22nd, accepted speakers will be notified soon after.
If you would like to sponsor the event, feel free to contact us: We would be very happy to provide videos after the event and free drinks for everyone during the event.</description></item></channel></rss>