<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Relocating to Berlin on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Relocating-to-Berlin/</link><description>Recent content in Relocating to Berlin on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 20:42:47 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Relocating-to-Berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ABC - die Katze lief im Schnee</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/abc-die-katze-lief-im-schnee5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 20:42:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/abc-die-katze-lief-im-schnee5/</guid><description>ABC - die Katze lief im Schnee # Seen this morning in Berlin:
A little impression from what the city looked like the weeks before it turned green on Christmas:
For winter images of other years see also previous posts. Title taken from a children&amp;rsquo;s song:</description></item><item><title>Learning German</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 08:07:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</guid><description>Learning German # For some reason I got that question multiple times now from people that moved to Germany but work in companies where English is the language to use for communication - how to best learn German (in addition finding people to talk to).
When thinking about how I got started with English there were a few things that helped: As a child I got some &amp;ldquo;made for learning English&amp;rdquo; crime stories to read.</description></item><item><title>Last minute Getting Around information for Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/last-minute-getting-around-information-for-berlin-buzzwords260/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 12:47:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/last-minute-getting-around-information-for-berlin-buzzwords260/</guid><description>Last minute Getting Around information for Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing information on how to get around in Berlin more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like to type it out - putting it here for future reference.
Before going to Berlin make sure to put an app on your phone that helps with finding the right public transport mix to use for going from one place to another:
Nokia Public Transit for WP7 phones</description></item><item><title>Music in Berlin early June</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/music-in-berlin-early-june289/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 18:20:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/music-in-berlin-early-june289/</guid><description>Music in Berlin early June # A little bit of inspiration on what to do the weekend before and after Buzzwords in Berlin:
Ballet in June at the Staatsballett Berlin
Concerts in June at &amp;lt;a href=&amp;ldquo; http://www.konzerthaus.de/programm/?datetimeAnf=1338501600&amp;datetimeEnd=1341093600&amp;id_language=1&amp;month=6&amp;year=2012"
Konzerthaus Berlin
Opera in June at Staatsoper Berlin
Opera in June at Deutsche Oper Berlin
Concerts in June at the Philharmoniker Berlin
Opera in June at Komische Oper Berlin
Theater (German-only, sorry, but open-air) at Hexenkessel Hoftheater</description></item><item><title>Visiting Berlin Buzzwords - where to go for drinks and food</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/visiting-berlin-buzzwords-where-to-go-for-drinks-and-food430/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 19:39:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/visiting-berlin-buzzwords-where-to-go-for-drinks-and-food430/</guid><description>Visiting Berlin Buzzwords - where to go for drinks and food # There are literally hundreds of bars and restaurants in easy walking distance to the conference venue. And if that is now enough for you, hop on U-Bahn and head east to either Kreuzberg or Friedrichshain to find more. For inspiration check out Tip Berlin - they have a decent, reliable restaurant list.
For quick orientation: Berlin is no one city center but many districts that all have their own look and feel to them.</description></item><item><title>Walking through Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/walking-through-berlin431/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 18:27:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/walking-through-berlin431/</guid><description>Walking through Berlin # Ever made the mistake of booking a flight to a city and trying to decide on what to do only after you arrived? That type of planning does work for Berlin - though you may end up with quite a different schedule than originally intended.
The only thing that needs a bit of planning ahead (about a month) is visiting the Bundestag - fast way to discover it is to just go up to it&amp;rsquo;s dome.</description></item><item><title>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</guid><description>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of several people who are not quite sure yet whether they should visit Berlin Buzzwords or not - in particular when having to travel far and cross 9 time zones to attend. My general recommendation is to plan to spend some more days in Europe. The conference is conveniently scheduled on Monday and Tuesday which gives you one weekend before to explore the city and the whole week afterwards to go and see more either in the city or around.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Tech Meetups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 22:32:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</guid><description>Berlin Tech Meetups # Berlin currently is of growing interest for software engineers, has a very active startup scene and as a result several community organised meetups. Listed below is a short, &amp;ldquo;highly objective&amp;rdquo; selection of local user groups - showing just the breadth of topics discussed.
Berlin Hadoop Get Together
Berlin DevOps
Berlin Buzzwords (conference, no meetup)
Berlin Scrumtisch
Java User Group Berlin/Brandenburg
Berlin Google Technology User Group</description></item></channel></rss>