<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kanban on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Kanban/</link><description>Recent content in Kanban on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:14:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Kanban/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - February 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-february-201242/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:14:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-february-201242/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - February 2012 # Today the first Hadoop Get Together Berlin 2012 took place - David got the event hosted by and at Axel Springer who kindly also paid for the (soon to be published) videos. Thanks also to the unbelievable Machine company for the tasty buffet after the meetup. Another thanks to Open Source Press for donating three of their Hadoop books.
Today&amp;rsquo;s selection was quite diverse: The event started with a presentation by Markus Andrezak who gave an overview of Kanban and how it helped him change the development workflow over at eBay/mobile.</description></item><item><title>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 20:34:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</guid><description>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get-Together is scheduled for 22. February, 6 p.m. - taking place at Axel Springer, Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10888 Berlin. Thanks to Springer for sponsoring the location!
Note: It is important to indicate attendance. Due to security restrictions at the venue only registered visitors will be permitted. Get your ticket here: https://www.xing.com/events/hadoop-22-02-859807
Talks scheduled thus far:
Markus Andrezak : &amp;ldquo;Queue Management in Product Development with Kanban - enabling flow and fast feedback along the value chain&amp;rdquo; - It&amp;rsquo;s a truism today that fast feedback from your market is a key advantage.</description></item></channel></rss>