<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mahout on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Mahout/</link><description>Recent content in Mahout on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Mahout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Taming Text</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</guid><description>On Taming Text # This time of the year I would usually post pictures of my bicycle standing in the snow somewhere in Tierpark. This year however I was tricked into using public transport instead: a) After my husband found a new job, we now share some of the route to work - and he isn&amp;rsquo;t crazy going by bike when it&amp;rsquo;s snowing. b) I got myself a Nexus7 earlier this month which obsoleted having to take paper books with me when using public transport.</description></item><item><title>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 12:40:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</guid><description>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012 # Earlier this month I attended the fourth Recommender Stammtisch in Berlin. The event was kindly hosted by Soundcloud - who on top of organising the speakers provided a really yummy buffet by Kochzeichen D.
With Paul Lamere the evening started with a very entertaining but also very packed talk on why music recommendation is special - or put more generally why all recommender systems are special:</description></item><item><title>Fourth #Recsys Stammtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fourth-recsys-stammtisch-berlin191/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 22:38:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fourth-recsys-stammtisch-berlin191/</guid><description>Fourth #Recsys Stammtisch Berlin # This evening the 4th #recsys Stammtisch (German for &amp;ldquo;a meetup involving beer&amp;rdquo;) was kindly organised by Alan Said, Zeno Gantner and Till Plumbaum. The event was hosted by Aklamio with beers and drinks provided by Plista. They had three talks:
@AlanSaid gave an overview of the topics covered in this year&amp;rsquo;s RecSys conference in Dublin. Instead of going into too much technical detail the presentation gave a whirl-wind tour of the topics that are currently under discussion, the competitions to participate in and links to people relevant to the topic to follow up with.</description></item><item><title>Speaking at ApacheCon EU 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/speaking-at-apachecon-eu-2012381/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 12:47:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/speaking-at-apachecon-eu-2012381/</guid><description>Speaking at ApacheCon EU 2012 # I&amp;rsquo;ll be at ApacheCon EU in November. Looking forward to an interesting conference on all things Apache that is finally returning back to Europe. Go there if you want to learn more on Tomcat, Hadoop, httpd, HBase, Camel, Open Office, Mahout, Lucene and more.
Now on to prepare the two talks I submitted:
&amp;ldquo;Choosing the right tool for your data analysis task - Apache Mahout in context&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Recsys meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-meetup-berlin330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 01:31:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-meetup-berlin330/</guid><description>Recsys meetup Berlin # Planning a meetup in Berlin: 8 people register, a table for 14 people is booked, 16+ people arrive - all of that even if no pre-defined topic or talk is announced. Seems like building recommender systems is a hot topic currently in Berlin.
Thanks to Zeno Gantner from MyMedialight for organising the event - looking forward to the next edition.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.6 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-06-released66/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 21:33:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-06-released66/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.6 released # As of Monday, February 6th a new Apache Mahout version was released. The new package features
Lots of performance improvments:
A new LDA implementation using Collapsed Variational Bayes 0th Derivative Approximation - try that out if you have been bothered by the way less than optimal performance of the old version.
Improved Decision Tree performance and added support for regression problems
Reduced runtime of dot product between vectors - many algorithms in Mahout rely on that, so these performance improvements will affect anyone using them.</description></item><item><title>Learning Machine Learning with Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-video-collection262/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 22:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-video-collection262/</guid><description>Learning Machine Learning with Apache Mahout # Once in a while I get questions like Where to start learning more on machine learning. Other than the official sources I think there is quite good coverage also in the Mahout community: Since it was founded several presentations have been given that give an overview of Apache Mahout, introduce special features or even go into more details on particular implementations. Below is an attempt to create a collection of talks given so far without any claim to contain links to all videos or lectures.</description></item><item><title>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 13:49:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</guid><description>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011 # Mid November Apache hosts its famous yearly conference - this time in Vancouver/Canada. They kindly accepted my presentations on Apache Mahout for intelligent data analysis (mostly focused on introducing the project to new comers and showing what happened within the project in the past year - if you have any wish concerning topics you would like to see covered in particular, please let me know) as well as a more committer focused one on Talking people into creating patches (with the goal of highlighting some of the issues new-comers to free software projects that want to contribute run into and initiating a discussion on what helps to convince them to keep up the momentum and over come and obstacles).</description></item><item><title>GoTo Con</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con215/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 20:49:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con215/</guid><description>GoTo Con # Location: Amsterdam
Link out: Click here
Start Date: 2011-10-12
End Date: 2011-10-14
This week late Tuesday night I am going to leave for GoTo con in Amsterdam. Train tickets are already booked - this is going to be my first trip with City Night line, will see how great they are.
GoTo Amsterdam features a special Apache track as well as several talk on scaling up, searching, but also includes stuff in general architectural decisions.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Hackathon Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-hackathon-berlin-271/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 21:39:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-hackathon-berlin-271/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Hackathon Berlin # Last year Sebastian Schelter from Berlin was added to the list of committers for Apache Mahout. With two committers in town the idea was born to meet some day, work on Mahout. So why not just announce that meeting publicly and invite others who might be interested in learning more about the framework? I got in touch with c-base - a hacker space in Berlin well suited to host a Hackathon - and quickly got their ok for the event.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:18:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam # Last week I was honoured to be invited as one of the two speakers on Apache Mahout at the Mahout meetup in Amsterdam at JTeams offices. After free beer, cola and pizza Frank Scholten gave an overview of Mahout's clustering capabilities. After a brief introduction to Mahout itself he went into a little more detail on how clustering works in general. After that with a selection of Seinfeld scripts he used a fun data set to guide the audience through the process of choosing the right data preparation steps, coming up with good training parameters and finally evaluating clustering quality.</description></item><item><title>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</guid><description>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale # This is to announce the Berlin Buzzwords 2011. The second edition of the successful conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany,
taking place in Berlin.
Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - Search, Store, Scale
6/7 June 2011
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata Conference</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 04:34:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference # Title: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference
Location: Santa Clara
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Description: Early next February O&amp;rsquo;Reilly is planning to put on a very interesting conference on the topic of data analysis and the business of generating value from raw digital data. I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to have received the acceptance notification for my presentation and travel sponsorship from the DICODE project. So see you in Santa Clara.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 16:31:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by Cloudera and Zanox that will take place in the Zanox Event Campus in Berlin.
When: January 27th 2011, 6p.m.
Where: zanox Event Campus (Please mark the changed event location.)
&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Größere Kartenansicht
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Hackathon Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-hackathon-berlin70/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:50:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-hackathon-berlin70/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Hackathon Berlin # Early next year - on February 19th/20th to be more precise - the first Apache Mahout Hackathon is scheduled to take place at c-base. The Hackathon will take one weekend. There will be plenty of time to hack on your favourite Mahout issue, to get in touch with two of the Mahout committers and get your machine learning project off the ground.
Please contact isabel@apache.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Podcast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 21:21:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Podcast # During Apache Con ATL Michael Coté interviewed Grant Ingersoll on Apache Mahout. The interview is available online as podcast. The interview covers the goals and current use cases of the project, goes into some detail on the reasons for initially starting it. If you are wondering what Mahout is all about, what you can do with it and which direction development is heading, the interview is a great option to find out more.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 21:25:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase # Devoxx featured several interesting case studies of how HBase and Hadoop can be used to scale data analysis back ends as well as data serving front ends. Twitter
Dmitry Ryaboy from Twitter explained how to scale high load and large data systems using Cassandra. Looking at the sheer amount of tweets generated each day it becomes obvious that with a system like MySQL alone this site cannot be run.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Meetup in San Jose</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-in-santa-clara82/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 07:48:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-in-santa-clara82/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Meetup in San Jose # A few hours ago the Mahout Meetup at MapR Technologies in San Jose/CA ended. Two photos taken at the event leaked - happy to be able to publish them here.
More information on the discussions and more technical details to follow. Stay tuned.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx University – MongoDB, Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-mongodb-mahout160/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 21:19:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-mongodb-mahout160/</guid><description>Devoxx University – MongoDB, Mahout # The second tutorial was given by Roger Bodamer on MongoDB. It concentrates on being horizontally scalable by avoiding joins and complex, multi document transactions. It supports a new data model that allows for flexible, changeable &amp;ldquo;schemas&amp;rdquo;. The exact data layout is determined by the types of operations you expect for your application, by the access patterns (reading vs. writing data; types of updates and types of queries).</description></item><item><title>Devoxx Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 21:16:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</guid><description>Devoxx Antwerp # With 3000 attendees Devoxx is the largest Java Community conference world-wide. Each year in autumn it takes place in Antwerp/ Belgium, in recent years in the Metropolis cinema. The conference tickets were sold out long before doors were opened this year.
The focus of the presentations are mainly on enterprise Java featuring talks by famous Joshua Bloch, Mark Reihnhold and others on new features of the upcoming JDK release as well as intricacies of the Java programming language itself.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Lisbon</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 21:09:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-lisbon398/</guid><description>Teddy in Lisbon # After Apache Con I spent a few days in Lisbon for Codebits. The conference is not developers-only. It is more of a mixture of hacking event, conference, exhibition. Though the location was not optimal for giving presentations (large exhibition hall with now a rather noisy presentation area) the whole event brought quite an interesting mixture of people together in one place in the capital of Portugal.</description></item><item><title>Mahout in Action</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-in-action-2276/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 21:07:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-in-action-2276/</guid><description>Mahout in Action # Flying to Atlanta I finally had a few hours of time to finalize the review of the Mahout in Action MEAP edition. The book is intended for potential users of the Apache Mahout, a project focussing on implementing scalable algorithms for machine learning.
Describing machine learning algorithms and their application to practioners is a non-trivial task: Usually there is more than one algorithm available for seemingly identically problem settings.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con – Mahout, commons and Lucene</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-mahout-commons-and-lucene15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 23:21:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-mahout-commons-and-lucene15/</guid><description>Apache Con – Mahout, commons and Lucene # The second day the track interesting to me provided an overview of some of the Apache commons projects. So seemingly small in scope and light-weight in implementation and dependencies these projects provide vital features not yet well supported by the Sun JVM. There is a commons math implementation featuring a fair amount of algebraic, numeric and trigonometric functions (among others), the commons exec framework for executing processes externally to the JVM w/o running into the danger of creating dead-locks or wasting resources.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.4 release</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:21:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.4 release # On last Sunday the Apache Mahout project published the 0.4 release. Nearly every piece of the code has been refactored and improved since the last 0.3 release. The release was timed to happen exactly before Apache Con NA in Atlanta. As such it was published on October 31st - the Halloween release, sort-of.
Especially mentionable are the following improvements:
Model refactoring and CLI changes to improve integration and consistency</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track # This year&amp;rsquo;s Devoxx will feature several presentations coming from the Apache Hadoop ecosystem including Tom White on the basics of Hadoop: HDFS, MapReduce, Hive and Pig as well as Michael Stack on HBase.
&amp;lt; br&amp;gt;
In addition there will be a brief Tools in Action presentation on Monday evening featuring Apache Mahout.
Please let me know if you are going to Devoxx - would be great to meet some more Apache people there, maybe have dinner at one of the conference days.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 09:36:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits # Second week of November I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few days in Lisbon - never would have thought that I&amp;rsquo;d return so quickly when I visited this beautiful city this summer during vacation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for Codebits - thanks to Sapo for inviting me to be there.
Back in summer I learned only after I returned to Germany that there was someone form Portugal seeking to meet with other Apache people exactly when I was down there.</description></item><item><title>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 06:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</guid><description>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011 # Call for Presentations: Data Analysis Dev Room, FOSDEM
http://fosdem.org
5 February 2011
1pm to 7pm
Brussels, Belgium
This is to announce the Data Analysis DevRoom co-located with FOSDEM. The first Meetup on analysing and learning from data, taking place in Brussels, Belgium.
Important Dates (all dates in GMT +2):
Submission deadline: 2010-12-17
Notification of accepted speakers: 2010-12-20
Publication of final schedule: 2011-01-10</description></item><item><title>Video: Max Heimel on sequence tagging w/ Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-heimel-on-sequence-tagging-w-apache-mahout425/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 19:58:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-heimel-on-sequence-tagging-w-apache-mahout425/</guid><description>Video: Max Heimel on sequence tagging w/ Apache Mahout # Some time ago Max Heimel from TU Berlin gave presentation of the new HMM support in the Mahout 0.4 release at the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin:
Mahout Max Heimel from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to JTeam for sponsoring video taping, thanks to newthinking for providing the location and thanks to Martin Schmidt from newthinking for producing the video.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:51:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</guid><description>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin # This evening the first Machine Learning Gossip meeting is scheduled to take place at 9p.m. at Victoriabar: Professionals working in research advancing machine learning algorithms and industry projects putting machine learning algorithms to practical use meet for some drinks, food and hopefully lots of interesting discussions.
If successful the meeting is supposed to take place on a regular schedule. Ask Michael Brückner for the date and location of the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>Video: Sebastian Schelter on Recommendation w/ Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-sebastian-schelter-on-recommendation-w-apache-mahout427/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 13:55:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-sebastian-schelter-on-recommendation-w-apache-mahout427/</guid><description>Video: Sebastian Schelter on Recommendation w/ Apache Mahout # A few weeks ago we had the autumn edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together in newthinking store in Berlin. I am glad to announce the first video online:
Mahout Sebastian Schelter from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to JTeam for sponsoring video taping, thanks to newthinking for providing the location and thanks to Martin Schmidt from newthinking for producing the video.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 20:39:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</guid><description>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA # The upcoming Apache Con NA to take place in Atlanta will feature several tracks relevant to users of Apache Mahout, Lucene and Hadoop: There will be a full track on Hadoop as well as one on NoSQL on Wednesday featuring talks on the framework itself, Pig and Hive as well as presentations from users on special use cases and on their way of getting the system to production.</description></item><item><title>Slides available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-available373/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 09:19:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-available373/</guid><description>Slides available # Yesterday evening the Autumn Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. The meetup this time focussed mainly on latest developments at Apache Mahout. The meetup was kindly sponsored by JTeam, providing video taping of the presentations as well as for free drinks. Thanks a lot for that.
After the meetup the group went over to Cafe Aufsturz for drinks, food and lots of interesting discussions - I left them there as I still have to get rid of a persistent cold.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 09:52:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today # Just a brief reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is supposed to take place today in newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48 at 5p.m.
The meeting features two talks on Apache Mahout: Committer Sebastian Schelter will explain how to scale recommender systems with Mahout. Contributor Max Heimel is going to give an introduction to the sequence labeling facilities available in Mahout.
As usual the group will move over to Cafe Aufsturz after the meetup is over.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 07:31:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by JTeam that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: October 7th, 5p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin, Tucholksystr. 48
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Teaching Free Software Development</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 12:55:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</guid><description>Teaching Free Software Development # In Summer last year I was invited to give a presentation on Apache Mahout at TU Berlin. After the talk was over some of the research group members asked me to design and give a course on scalable machine learning with open source software during the winter semester.
The project attracted four to five students - not very many - but then again it is a course people can take voluntarily.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 14:55:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer # One week to go for submitting a talk on your favourite NoSQL topic, your favourite search application or your most interesting data analysis task: The call for presentations for Berlin Buzzwords ends on April 17th, that is Sunday next week.
Shortly after the last talk was submitted we will start announcing speakers - final list of speakers is to be expected by the start of May, final schedule will be published shortly after that.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Working on Mahout as part of your studies at TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/working-on-mahout-as-part-of-your-studies-at-tu-berlin437/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 14:37:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/working-on-mahout-as-part-of-your-studies-at-tu-berlin437/</guid><description>Working on Mahout as part of your studies at TU Berlin # Did you ever wonder, who those weird people working on free software projects are? Did you ever ask yourself how these developers organise their work, how they collaborate, which values are important to them? Did you ever think about participating in a free software project yourself but never really had time to do so because your studies were just too time-consuming?</description></item><item><title>GSoC - one day to go for your application</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 14:37:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</guid><description>GSoC - one day to go for your application # If you are a student interested in participating in Google Summer of Code: Registration closes tomorrow (as in &amp;ldquo;April 9, 19:00 UTC&amp;rdquo;). You hopefully published and discussed your proposal at your favourite project already so you have a clear plan of where to go and which milestones to achieve in summer.
If you are interested in Apache Mahout: Yes, as last years, we are again looking for students willing to work on awesome student projects this summer.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.3 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-03-released64/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 15:22:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-03-released64/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.3 released # This week, Apache Mahout 0.3 was released. First of all thanks to all committers and contributors who made that possible: Thanks for all your hard work on making the code even faster and integrating even more algorithms.
To the highlights:
New: math and collections modules based on the high performance Colt library Faster Frequent Pattern Growth(FPGrowth) using FP-bonsai pruning
Parallel Dirichlet process clustering (model-based clustering algorithm)</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code starting</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 19:10:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</guid><description>Google Summer of Code starting # As published on the Google Open Source blog the application period for mentoring organizations for GSoC starts now. The ASF is already in the process of applying. If you are a student, looking for an interesting project to work on during the coming summer - you might consider participating in GSoC. It does give you are great opportunity to get in touch with successful free software projects, learn how to work in global teams, improve your communication skills and last but not least show and publish your fantastic coding skills.</description></item><item><title>Learning to Rank Challenge</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:49:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</guid><description>Learning to Rank Challenge # In one of his recent blog posts, Jeff Dalton published an article on currently running machine learning challenges. Especially interesting for those working on search engines and interested in learning new rankings from data should be the Yahoo! Learning to Rank Challenge to be held in conjunction with this year&amp;rsquo;s ICML 2010 in Haifa, Israel. The goal is to show that your algorithm does not only scale on real-world data provided by Yahoo!</description></item><item><title>Mahout at Berlin ignite</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-ignite274/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 22:24:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-ignite274/</guid><description>Mahout at Berlin ignite # This evening the first Berlin ignite event took place in the &amp;ldquo;Festsaal&amp;rdquo; in Berlin X-Berg. Organiser of the event was Matt Biddulph from Nokia Gate 5. We had eleven fantastic talks (ok, to be more precise: At least ten fantastic ones, my own can only be judged by the audience ;) ).
Topics included things you can learn when starting to collect data, themes from (agile) project management, RepRap machines (see also the Rep Rap FOSDEM 2010 talk), bots and robots.</description></item><item><title>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 19:13:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</guid><description>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin # Today first talks scheduled for ignite Berlin were published. If you yourself would like to give a talk: Submission seems to still be open.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 19:33:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM # The final schedule of FOSDEM 2010 is up: Looks like bad news - 306 interesting talks within just one weekend. Lots of interesting talks in the main track including Greg Kroah-Hartman on &amp;ldquo;Write and Submit your first Linux kernel Patch&amp;rdquo;, David Recordon from Facebook on &amp;ldquo;Scaling Facebook with OpenSource tools&amp;rdquo;, Bernard Li on &amp;ldquo;Ganglia: 10 years of monitoring clusters and grids&amp;rdquo;, Andrew Tanenbaum with his &amp;ldquo;MINIX 3: a Modular, Self-Healing POSIX-compatible Operating System&amp;rdquo; talk, Benoît Chesneau on &amp;ldquo;CouchDB!</description></item><item><title>Mahout in Action</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-in-action275/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 20:22:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-in-action275/</guid><description>Mahout in Action # As noted earlier by Grant Ingersoll, the first chapters of Mahout in Action are already online at Manning:
Sean, Robin, keep up the great work! I would love to read more of the book in the near future.</description></item><item><title>With a little help from my friends</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 23:55:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</guid><description>With a little help from my friends # The end of the year 2009 is quickly approaching. To me it feels a little like it ran away far too quickly. So instead of taking part in the annual review of past events, I would like to use it as an opportunity to say thank you: The past twelve months were a lot of fun with lots of interesting, nice people from all over the world.</description></item><item><title>Mahout 0.2 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 10:52:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</guid><description>Mahout 0.2 released # Apache Mahout 0.2 has been released and is now available for public download at http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/lucene/mahout
Up to date maven artifacts can be found in the Apache repository at
https://repository.apache.org/cont ent/repositories/releases/org/apache/mahout/
Apache Mahout is a subproject of Apache Lucene with the goal of delivering scalable machine learning algorithm implementations under the Apache license. http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
Mahout is a machine learning library meant to scale: Scale in terms of community to support anyone interested in using machine learning.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</guid><description>Open Source Expo 09 # I spent last Sunday and the following Monday at Open Source Expo Karlsruhe - co-located with web-tech and php-conference organized by the Software-and-Support Verlag. Together with Simon Willnauer I ran the Lucene/Mahout booth at the expo.
So far the conference is still very small (about 400 visitors) compared to free software community events. However the focus was set to be more on professional users, accordingly several projects showed that free software can be used successfully for various business use cases.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con US Wrap Up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:10:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</guid><description>Apache Con US Wrap Up # some weeks ago I attended ApacheConUS09 in Oakland/ California. In the mean time, videos of one of the sessions have been published online:
You can find a wrap up of the most prominent topics at the conference at heise (unfortunately Germany-only).
By far the largest topics at the conference:
Lucene - there was a meetup with over 100 attendees as well as two main tracks with Lucene focussed talks.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:38:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</guid><description>Open Source Expo # Title: Open Source Expo
Location: Karlsruhe
Link out: Click here
Description: There will be a booth at Open source expo introducing interested visitors to the Apache projects Lucene and Mahout. Of course we are also happy to answer any questions on the ASF in general.
Start Date: 2009-11-15
End Date: 2009-11-16</description></item><item><title>Mahout@TU WS 09/10</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 23:08:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</guid><description>Mahout@TU WS 09/10 # Title: Mahout@TU WS 09/10
There is going to be a project/seminar course at TU Berlin on Apache Mahout. The goal is to introduce students to the work on a free software project, interact with the community and build production ready software.
Students will be given several potential tasks ranging from optimizing existing implementations, implementing new algorithms and (depending on their prior knowledge) improving, scaling and parallelizing existing algorithms.</description></item><item><title>GSoC at Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-at-mahout219/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 22:22:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-at-mahout219/</guid><description>GSoC at Mahout # GSoC 2009 is about to finish: Final evaluations are through, most of the code submitted by Mahout&amp;rsquo;s students has been committed to svn, code samples are on their way to Google.
In Mahout, we had three students joining the project: Robin working on an HBase based Naive Bayes extension and on frequent itemset discovery. David contributing a distributed LDA implementation. Deneche was working on a Random Forest implementation.</description></item><item><title>Inglourious Basterds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/inglourious-basterds238/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 22:48:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/inglourious-basterds238/</guid><description>Inglourious Basterds # This evening I went to the cinema Odeon in Berlin Schöneberg. It is a pretty traditional, old-fashioned and very lovely cinema that has specialised on showing non-dubbed, original versions of movies.
Showing the great movie Inglourious Basterds, the cinema was completely sold out today. Fortunately we were able to grab some of the last tickets.
Just in case the entrance seemed familiar to those who have attended a Mahout presentation in the recent past - a picture of the Odeon usually visualises one part of my motivation on the Mahout slides ;)</description></item><item><title>Flying back home from Cologne</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:40:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</guid><description>Flying back home from Cologne # Last weekend FrOSCon took place in Sankt Augustin, near Cologne. FrOSCon is organized on a yearly basis at the university of applied sciences in Sankt Augustin. It is a volunteer driven event with the goal of bringing developers and users of free software projects together. This year, the conference featured 5 tracks, two examples being cloud computing and the Java track.
Unfortunately this year the conference started with a little surprise for me and my boyfriend: Being both speakers, we had booked a room in Hotel Regina via the conference committee.</description></item><item><title>Back from Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 16:58:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</guid><description>Back from Zürich # I spend the last five days in Zurich. I wanted to visit the city again - and still owed one of my friends there a visit. I am really happy the weather was quite nice over the weekend. That way I could spend quite some time in town (got another one of those puzzles) and go for a hike on the Ütli mountain: I took the steep way up that had quite a lot of stairs.</description></item><item><title>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 08:54:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</guid><description>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK # A few weeks after the Hadoop User Group UK is over, there are quite a few postings on the event online. I will try to keep this page updated if there are any further reviews. The one I found so far:
http://huguk.org/2009/04/huguk-2-wrap-up.html - the wrap-up of the event itself.
http://blog.oskarsson.nu/2009_04_01_archive.html - a short summary by the organiser - Thanks again for a great event.</description></item><item><title>Mahout on EC2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-on-ec2281/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 21:00:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-on-ec2281/</guid><description>Mahout on EC2 # Amazon released Elastic Map Reduce only a few weeks ago. EMR is based on a hosted Hadoop environment and offers machines to run map reduce jobs against data in S3 on demand.
Last week Stephen Green has spent quite some effort to get Mahout running on EMR. Thanks to his work Mahout is running on EMR since last Thursday night. Read the weblog of Tim Bass for further information.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop User Group UK</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-user-group-uk-2226/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 20:34:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-user-group-uk-2226/</guid><description>Hadoop User Group UK # On Tuesday the 14th the second Hadoop User Group UK took place in London. This time venue and pizza was sponsored by Sun. The room quickly filled http://www.thecepblog.com/2009/04/19/kmeans-clustering-now-running-on-elastic-mapreduce/with approximately 70 people.
Tom opened the session with a talk on 10 practical tips on how to get the most benefit from Apache Hadoop. The first question users should ask themselves is which type of programming language they want to use.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 15:11:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</guid><description>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1 # This morning I received Grant&amp;rsquo;s release mail of Apache Mahout. I am really happy that after little more than one year we now have our first release out there to test and scrutinate by anyone interested in the project. Thanks to all the committers who have helped make this possible. A special thanks to Grant Ingersoll for putting so much time into getting many release issues out of the way as well as to those who reviewed the release candidates and all the major and minor problems.</description></item></channel></rss>