<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GSoC on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/GSoC/</link><description>Recent content in GSoC on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 14:37:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/GSoC/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GSoC - one day to go for your application</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 14:37:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</guid><description>GSoC - one day to go for your application # If you are a student interested in participating in Google Summer of Code: Registration closes tomorrow (as in &amp;ldquo;April 9, 19:00 UTC&amp;rdquo;). You hopefully published and discussed your proposal at your favourite project already so you have a clear plan of where to go and which milestones to achieve in summer.
If you are interested in Apache Mahout: Yes, as last years, we are again looking for students willing to work on awesome student projects this summer.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code starting</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 19:10:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</guid><description>Google Summer of Code starting # As published on the Google Open Source blog the application period for mentoring organizations for GSoC starts now. The ASF is already in the process of applying. If you are a student, looking for an interesting project to work on during the coming summer - you might consider participating in GSoC. It does give you are great opportunity to get in touch with successful free software projects, learn how to work in global teams, improve your communication skills and last but not least show and publish your fantastic coding skills.</description></item><item><title>GSoC: Student applications.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:57:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</guid><description>GSoC: Student applications. # Title: GSoC: Student applications closed
Link out: Click here
Description: After this date no more student applications are accepted. Internal ranking at Apache starts 7 days earlier. The ranking process finishes at 16th of April.
Date: 2009-04-03</description></item><item><title>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:54:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</guid><description>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects # Title: Students begin coding for their GSoC projects
Link out: Click here
Description: GSoC time.
Date: 2009-05-26</description></item></channel></rss>