<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Dinner Berlin on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Dinner-Berlin/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Dinner Berlin on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 06:06:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Dinner-Berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 06:06:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin # Title: Apache Dinner Berlin
Location: Good Morning Vietnam X-Berg&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Start Time: 19:00
Date: 2011-02-28
Please contact Simon Willnauer if you would like to attend for further information.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 08:16:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</guid><description>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam # The Apache Dinner Berlin will take place today. As always, everybody is invited even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the poll ( http://doodle.com/8bi2456enwe6z2g6). This time around the dinner was organised by Daniel Naber. Thanks!
When: Monday, 2010-10-04, 19:30
Where: Lindencafe, Rudolf-Breitscheid-Str. 47/48, 14482 Potsdam-Babelsberg, This is directly next to the S-Bahn (S7, Babelsberg).
Looking forward to meeting you there!</description></item><item><title>Apache dinner wrap-up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-wrap-up38/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 22:19:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-wrap-up38/</guid><description>Apache dinner wrap-up # Today three Lucene committers, two Mahout committers (one of them also being committer of Lucene: Hi Karl, was great having you here - see you at the next Hadoop Get Together, or maybe some day for lunch.), several users of Lucene and Hadoop together with their family (including a very cute, unbelievably quiet three weeks old baby) met at Jamerica - a restaurant offering American as well as Jamaican food in Schöneberg.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 08:00:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</guid><description>Apache Dinner this evening # This evening the September Apache Dinner takes place in Jamerica Schöneberg. I have booked a table for ten to fifteen people - we&amp;rsquo;ll see whether that is sufficient this time :)
Looking forward to see you there at 7p.m.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 21:54:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</guid><description>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap # This evening yet another Apache Dinner took place in Berlin (this time Schöneberg), location booked by Simon Willnauer. As it was announced less then a week ago (see post below) we were expecting no more then some 7 people &amp;hellip; we ended up being a group of 15 attendees: There was Michi Busch from Twitter together with Tanja, Uwe Schindler from Bremen joined us.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin - August 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-august-201131/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 14:52:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-august-201131/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin - August 2010 # Simon (Willnauer) just sent around the following e-mail. If you have some time left next Monday evening, come join us in Yogihaus: For tasty Indian food, geeky discussions and a generally beautiful evening.
Unlike the other dinner mails this one is not a poll, it&amp;rsquo;s an announcement. Some Apache folks are in town next monday (9th of August) so we decided to have a Apache Dinner with a short term notice.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:54:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</guid><description>Apache Dinner June 2010 # After Berlin Buzzwords was over yesterday - and as there is an svn conference in the city that starts tomorrow, we thought we could easily put together a smallish Apache Dinner for tonight. So Torsten mailed a few people, booked some space at Heinz Minki in Kreuzberg. We announced it at the end of the conference and invited people to join us.
So after a beautiful day out I spent the evening with a bunch of Apache related guys and girls having drinks and great pizza: We had several svn committers, Greg Stein met us there - he arrived today for the svn conference.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 08:52:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</guid><description>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords # Staying in town after Berlin Buzzwords? Interested in meeting with the Apache folks here? Torsten Curdt kindly organises an Apache Dinner on Wednesday evening after Berlin Buzzwords. If you would like to participate, contact Torsten for details on when and where it will take place.
Though named Apache dinner, there is no need to be Apache committer or even member to participate: Being generally interested in Apache projects and in meeting the guys behind the project is totally sufficient.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - May 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:50:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - May 2010 # This evening a bunch of Apache committers and friends gathered in Berlin Kreuzberg at &amp;ldquo;Goodmorning Vietnam&amp;rdquo; for tasty food, nice drinks - or put another way, for a very nice evening. Simon had booked the table - we were expecting no more than eight people. However, as with any user group these meetup tends to grow. Shortly after the appointed time we had to move to another table to fit everyone around.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - April 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:43:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - April 2010 # Today, the April Apache Dinner took place in Berlin. We met at Sadhu - an Indian restaurant in Berlin X-Berg. We were six people: Lars Trieloff from Day Software, Simon Willnauer and Vera from Lucene, Torsten Curdt - currently Freelancer and Daniel Naber from Lucene as well.
With great food, nice discussions and a first glimpse on the submissions for Berlin Buzzwords it quickly got later and later :)</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 08:00:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday # Next Monday at 7p.m. the April Apache Dinner Berlin is scheduled to take place. Thanks to Torsten Curdt for organising the dinner - as in: Contacting people, finding a suitable data, booking the location etc.
Looking forward to another nice evening at an awesome restaurant with tasty indian food. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to join us, please contact Torsten to be included in the next announcement mail.</description></item><item><title>Third Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 22:04:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</guid><description>Third Apache Dinner Berlin # Today the third Dinner for Apache committers and friends took place in Berlin. We met in Schöneberg at Marcello Berlin for pizza, pasta, wine, beer &amp;hellip; and lots of discussions.
It always surprises me to see how many Apache related people there are in Berlin. This time we had Peter from Tomcat, Daniel and Simon with Vera from Lucene, Eric from http components, four guys from the svn project (Welcome again at the ASF), Oswald and myself and Thilo.</description></item></channel></rss>