<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tomcat on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/tomcat/</link><description>Recent content in tomcat on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:23:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/tomcat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 20:23:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconna-monitoring-httpd-and-tomcat102/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Monitoring httpd and Tomcat # Monitoring - a task generally neglected - or over done - during development.
But still vital enough to wake up people from well earned sleep at night when
done wrong. Rainer Jung provided some valuable insights on how to monitor Apache httpd and Tomcat.
Of course failure detection, alarms and notifications are all part of good
monitoring. However so is avoidance of false positives and metric collection,</description></item><item><title>ApacheConEU - part 06</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part0693/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 20:48:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apacheconeu-part0693/</guid><description>ApacheConEU - part 06 # For the next session I joined the Tomcat crowd in Marc Thomas&amp;rsquo; to learn more on Tomcat reverse proxy configurations. One rather common setup is to have Tomcat connected to an httpd instance. One common issue encountered with this setup in particular when running httpd with the event mpm is the problem of thread exhaustion on tomcat&amp;rsquo;s side. Fixes include always having more active tomcat threads than there can be httpd threads at any one time and to disable persistent connections.</description></item><item><title>Tomcat Tuesday talk</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 09:07:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</guid><description>Tomcat Tuesday talk # Since several months at neofonie we have a talk given by external or internal developers on various subjects each Tuesday. Usually these presentations are a nice way to get an overview of new emerging technologies, to get an overview of current conference topics or to gain insight into interesting internal projects.
This week we had Apache Tomcat Committer and PMC Peter Rossbach here at neofonie to talk about the Tomcat architecture and Tomcat clustering solutions.</description></item></channel></rss>