<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scrumtisch on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/scrumtisch/</link><description>Recent content in scrumtisch on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 23:10:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/scrumtisch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin357/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 23:10:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin357/</guid><description>Scrumtisch Berlin # After quite some time off I went to the Scrumtisch Berlin. The event was incredibly well visited - roughly 50 people filled the upper floor at Cafe Hundertwasser. Today&amp;rsquo;s event was organised such that participants first collected discussion topics, prioritised them together and then discussed the top three items in a timebox of 15 minutes each.
Topics collected were:
Best tricks to make teams self organised (20 votes)</description></item><item><title>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 21:38:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</guid><description>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin # This evening Mary Poppendieck gave a presentation on Design Thinking in Berlin. &amp;ldquo;What does the US Military have in common with Apple?&amp;rdquo; In her talk Mary went into more detail about how increasing complexity calls for a need to rethink design. Slides are available online. Thanks for sharing them.
Mary started with a question for the audience on who in your company decides what is to be developed: Is it the PO?</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch August Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 16:26:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</guid><description>Scrumtisch August Berlin # Just seen it - the next Scrumtisch Berlin has been scheduled for 25th August 2010 at 18:30 Uhr. So far, no official talk has been scheduled, so please expect two topics on Scrum and its application to be selected for discussion according to Marion&amp;rsquo;s agile topic selection algorithm.
Please talk to Marion Eickmann if you would like to attend the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>Coaching self-organising teams</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 21:58:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</guid><description>Coaching self-organising teams # Today, the Scrumtisch organised by Marion Eickmann from Agile 42 met in Berlin Friedrichshain. Though no talk was scheduled for this evening the room was packed with guests from various companies and backgrounds interested in participating in discussions on Scrum.
As usual we started collecting topics (timeboxed to five minutes). The list was rather short, however it contained several interesting pieces:
(6) Management buy-in
(6+) CSP - Certified Scrum Professional - what changes compared to the practitioner?</description></item></channel></rss>