<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Dinner on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Dinner/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Dinner on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 06:06:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Dinner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 06:06:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin # Title: Apache Dinner Berlin
Location: Good Morning Vietnam X-Berg&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Start Time: 19:00
Date: 2011-02-28
Please contact Simon Willnauer if you would like to attend for further information.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track # This year&amp;rsquo;s Devoxx will feature several presentations coming from the Apache Hadoop ecosystem including Tom White on the basics of Hadoop: HDFS, MapReduce, Hive and Pig as well as Michael Stack on HBase.
&amp;lt; br&amp;gt;
In addition there will be a brief Tools in Action presentation on Monday evening featuring Apache Mahout.
Please let me know if you are going to Devoxx - would be great to meet some more Apache people there, maybe have dinner at one of the conference days.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 08:16:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</guid><description>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam # The Apache Dinner Berlin will take place today. As always, everybody is invited even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the poll ( http://doodle.com/8bi2456enwe6z2g6). This time around the dinner was organised by Daniel Naber. Thanks!
When: Monday, 2010-10-04, 19:30
Where: Lindencafe, Rudolf-Breitscheid-Str. 47/48, 14482 Potsdam-Babelsberg, This is directly next to the S-Bahn (S7, Babelsberg).
Looking forward to meeting you there!</description></item><item><title>Apache dinner wrap-up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-wrap-up38/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 22:19:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-wrap-up38/</guid><description>Apache dinner wrap-up # Today three Lucene committers, two Mahout committers (one of them also being committer of Lucene: Hi Karl, was great having you here - see you at the next Hadoop Get Together, or maybe some day for lunch.), several users of Lucene and Hadoop together with their family (including a very cute, unbelievably quiet three weeks old baby) met at Jamerica - a restaurant offering American as well as Jamaican food in Schöneberg.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 08:00:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</guid><description>Apache Dinner this evening # This evening the September Apache Dinner takes place in Jamerica Schöneberg. I have booked a table for ten to fifteen people - we&amp;rsquo;ll see whether that is sufficient this time :)
Looking forward to see you there at 7p.m.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 08:52:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</guid><description>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords # Staying in town after Berlin Buzzwords? Interested in meeting with the Apache folks here? Torsten Curdt kindly organises an Apache Dinner on Wednesday evening after Berlin Buzzwords. If you would like to participate, contact Torsten for details on when and where it will take place.
Though named Apache dinner, there is no need to be Apache committer or even member to participate: Being generally interested in Apache projects and in meeting the guys behind the project is totally sufficient.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner January 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 22:48:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</guid><description>Apache Dinner January 2010 # This evening in X-Berg several local committers met for the second &amp;ldquo;Apache Dinner&amp;rdquo; - an informal gathering of local Apache committers, friends and associates for food, beer and interesting discussions. Next one is probably to be scheduled some time in February. Feel free to send a message to Torsten Curdt to be included on the next invitation mail. Thanks for organizing a nice evening, Torsten.</description></item><item><title>First Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-apache-dinner-berlin174/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 02:33:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-apache-dinner-berlin174/</guid><description>First Apache Dinner Berlin # A few days ago, I received a mail from Torsten Curdt that read something like: &amp;ldquo;[&amp;hellip;] For a long time now I wanted to organise an Apache Dinner Berlin. What do you think, when would be a good time for that?&amp;rdquo;. As that was about the third time I heard of that idea (and the third person mentioning the idea), I included some Berlin-based Apache-people asking whether they would be interested in having an Apache Dinner on November 24st in X-Berg.</description></item></channel></rss>