<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pig on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Pig/</link><description>Recent content in Pig on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:30:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Pig/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:30:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012 # Despite beautiful summer weather roughly 50 people gathered at ImmobilienScout24 for the August 2012 edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together (Thanks again for hosting the event and sponsoring drinks and pizza to ImmoScout as well as to David Obermann for organising the meetup.
Today there were three talks: In the first presentation Dragan Milosevic (also known from his talk at the Hadoop GetTogether and his presentation at Berlin Buzzwords) provided more insight as to how Zanox is managing their internal RPC protocols in particular when it comes to versioning and upgrading protocol versions.</description></item><item><title>Video: Max Jacob on Pig for NLP</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-jacob-on-pig-for-nlp426/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:26:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-jacob-on-pig-for-nlp426/</guid><description>Video: Max Jacob on Pig for NLP # Max Jacob: Pig for Natural Language Processing from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Slides online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-online375/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 06:55:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-online375/</guid><description>Slides online # Slides of this week&amp;rsquo;s Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are online at:
Douwe Osinga: Overview of the Data Processing Pipeline at Triposo
Max Jacob: Pig for Natural Language Processing
Overall a great event, well organised - looking forward to seeing you at the next Get Together. If you want to get in touch with our participants, learn about new events or simply chat between meetups join our Apache Hadoop Get Together Linked.</description></item></channel></rss>