<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncategorized on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Uncategorized/</link><description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 21:38:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building online communities - from the 0MQ trenches</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/building-online-communities-from-the-0mq-trenches130/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 21:38:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/building-online-communities-from-the-0mq-trenches130/</guid><description>Building online communities - from the 0MQ trenches # After seeing several talks on how open source communitites are organised at FOSDEM, on how to license open source software strategically at Chemnitzer Linuxtage and on how to nurture open source communities at Berlin Buzzwords over the past couple of years during the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve come to read quite a few articles and books on the art of building online communities.</description></item><item><title>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 20:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/meet-the-indian-tribe100/</guid><description>ApacheConNA: Meet the indian tribe # ApacheCon is the ``User Conference of the Apache Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;. What
should that mean? If you are going to Apache Con you have the chance of meeting
committers of your favourite projects as well as members of the foundation
itself. Though there are a lot of talks that are interesting from a technical
point of view the goal really is to turn you into an active member of the</description></item><item><title>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 11:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</guid><description>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords # Disclaimer: Intentionally posting on my private blog - these are my own criteria, not general advice from the review committee.
Berlin Buzzwords is in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth year. Probably the most tedious task of all is having to select talks to make it into the final schedule. With roughly 120 submissions and roughly 30 slots to fill the result is that three quarters of all submissions have to be rejected.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/about6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 08:55:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/about6/</guid><description>About # This is the blog of Isabel. I am committer at Apache Mahout. In my free time I am working on Apache Mahout, organising the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin and speaking at various conferences explaining the ins and outs of Hadoop in general and Mahout in particular.
Disclaimer: I am writing this blog with my “Apache hat” on my head. The opinions expressed herein are my own personal opinions and do not represent my employer’s view in any way.</description></item></channel></rss>