<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fast on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/fast/</link><description>Recent content in fast on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 23:23:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/fast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Con – last day</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 23:23:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-last-day14/</guid><description>Apache Con – last day # Day three of Apache Con started with interesting talks on Tomcat 7, including an introduction to the new features of that release. Those include better memory leak prevention and detection capabilities – the implementation of these capabilities have lead to the discovery of various leaks that appear under more or less weird circumstances in famous open source libraries and the JVM itself. But also better management and reporting facilities are part of the new release.</description></item><item><title>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 22:07:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</guid><description>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr # The article was first published on Sesat Weblog. As the whole site went down several days ago, I retrieved the content from the Google cache and posted it here for perservation.
Update: Original site is up again.</description></item><item><title>Moving from Fast to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:34:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</guid><description>Moving from Fast to Solr # Sesat has published a nice in-depth report on why to move from Fast to Solr. The article also includes a description of the steps taken to move over as well as several statistics:
http://sesat.no/moving-from-fast-to-solr-review.html
On a related topic, the following article details, where Apple is using Lucene/Solr to power it&amp;rsquo;s search. Spoiler: Look at Spotlight, their desktop search, as well as on the iTunes search with about 800 QPS.</description></item></channel></rss>