<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Mahout on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Mahout/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Mahout on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 07:10:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Mahout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machine learning problem settings</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-problem-settings272/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 07:10:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-problem-settings272/</guid><description>Machine learning problem settings # Together with Sebastian Schelter I held a Nokia sponsored (Thank you!) lecture on large scale data analysis and data mining during the past few months. After supervising a few successful university projects based on Apache Mahout the goal of this lecture was to introduce students to some of the basic concepts and problems encountered today in a world where huge datasets are generally available and are easy to process with Apache Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:18:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam # Last week I was honoured to be invited as one of the two speakers on Apache Mahout at the Mahout meetup in Amsterdam at JTeams offices. After free beer, cola and pizza Frank Scholten gave an overview of Mahout's clustering capabilities. After a brief introduction to Mahout itself he went into a little more detail on how clustering works in general. After that with a selection of Seinfeld scripts he used a fun data set to guide the audience through the process of choosing the right data preparation steps, coming up with good training parameters and finally evaluating clustering quality.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout in Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-in-amsterdam80/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 20:00:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-in-amsterdam80/</guid><description>Apache Mahout in Amsterdam # On February 7th there will be an Apache Mahout meetup in Amsterdam kindly organised by JTeam. There will be two presentations - one by myself on classification with Apache Mahout as well as a second one by Frank Scholten on clustering with Apache Mahout.
Time: 18:00
Location: Frederiksplein 1, 1017XK Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Looking forward to a few days in Amsterdam.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM II 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 15:46:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</guid><description>FOSDEM II 2011 # It&amp;rsquo;s already sort of a nice little tradition for me to spend the first weekend in February in Brussels for FOSDEM. This year I am particulary happy that there will be a Data Analytics Dev Room at FOSDEM. A huge Thanks to @ogrisel and @nmaillot who have done most of the heavy lifting of getting the schedule in place.
Looking forward to an interesting Cloud Track, to meeting Peter Hintjens who is going to give a talk on 0MQ, the DevOps presentation and lots of very interesting DevRooms.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata Conference</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 04:34:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference # Title: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference
Location: Santa Clara
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Description: Early next February O&amp;rsquo;Reilly is planning to put on a very interesting conference on the topic of data analysis and the business of generating value from raw digital data. I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to have received the acceptance notification for my presentation and travel sponsorship from the DICODE project. So see you in Santa Clara.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Podcast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 21:21:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Podcast # During Apache Con ATL Michael Coté interviewed Grant Ingersoll on Apache Mahout. The interview is available online as podcast. The interview covers the goals and current use cases of the project, goes into some detail on the reasons for initially starting it. If you are wondering what Mahout is all about, what you can do with it and which direction development is heading, the interview is a great option to find out more.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout 0.4 release</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 15:21:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-halloween-release65/</guid><description>Apache Mahout 0.4 release # On last Sunday the Apache Mahout project published the 0.4 release. Nearly every piece of the code has been refactored and improved since the last 0.3 release. The release was timed to happen exactly before Apache Con NA in Atlanta. As such it was published on October 31st - the Halloween release, sort-of.
Especially mentionable are the following improvements:
Model refactoring and CLI changes to improve integration and consistency</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 09:36:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits # Second week of November I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few days in Lisbon - never would have thought that I&amp;rsquo;d return so quickly when I visited this beautiful city this summer during vacation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for Codebits - thanks to Sapo for inviting me to be there.
Back in summer I learned only after I returned to Germany that there was someone form Portugal seeking to meet with other Apache people exactly when I was down there.</description></item></channel></rss>