<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get Together on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Get-Together/</link><description>Recent content in Get Together on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:39:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Get-Together/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Elastic Search meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:39:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</guid><description>Elastic Search meetup Berlin # Today Retresco hosted the (to my knowledge fourth) Elastic Search User Group Berlin - a group dedicated to using Lucene as part of Elastic Search. With roughly fifteen attendees the meetup attracted a decent crowd - most interestingly many of the people there were already using the software either in production or for closed beta projects.
The fist talk given was by people from ferret-go - a company doing media monitoring for brands focused on the German market.</description></item><item><title>Video up: Dragan Milosevic on "Robust Communication Mechanisms"</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-robust-communication-mechanisms423/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 08:06:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-robust-communication-mechanisms423/</guid><description>Video up: Dragan Milosevic on &amp;ldquo;Robust Communication Mechanisms&amp;rdquo; # Dragan Milosevic: "Robust Communication Mechanisms in zanox Reporting Systems" from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Video: Stefan Hübner on Cascalog</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-stefan-hubner-on-cascalog428/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:49:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-stefan-hubner-on-cascalog428/</guid><description>Video: Stefan Hübner on Cascalog # Stefan Hübner: "Introducing Cascalog: Functional Data Processing for Hadoop" from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Video: "Accessing Hadoop data with HCatalog and PostgreSQL"</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-accessing-hadoop-data-with-hcatalog-and-postgresql424/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 20:53:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-accessing-hadoop-data-with-hcatalog-and-postgresql424/</guid><description>Video: &amp;ldquo;Accessing Hadoop data with HCatalog and PostgreSQL&amp;rdquo; # Manuel Meßner, Stephan Friese, Dr. Stefanie Huber: "Accessing Hadoop data with HCatalog and PostgreSQL" from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:30:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012 # Despite beautiful summer weather roughly 50 people gathered at ImmobilienScout24 for the August 2012 edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together (Thanks again for hosting the event and sponsoring drinks and pizza to ImmoScout as well as to David Obermann for organising the meetup.
Today there were three talks: In the first presentation Dragan Milosevic (also known from his talk at the Hadoop GetTogether and his presentation at Berlin Buzzwords) provided more insight as to how Zanox is managing their internal RPC protocols in particular when it comes to versioning and upgrading protocol versions.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Hadoop Get Together (April 2012)- videos are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-april-2012-videos-are-up119/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 14:22:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-april-2012-videos-are-up119/</guid><description>Berlin Hadoop Get Together (April 2012)- videos are up # Sebastian Schelter: Introducing Apache Giraph for Large Scale Graph Processing
Dr. Falk-Florian Henrich: Applying Compiler Technology to Event Stream Processing Dr. Mikio Braun: TWIMPACT: On Real-Time Twitter Analysis</description></item><item><title>Berlin Hadoop Get Together - videos are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-videos-are-up120/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 20:08:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-videos-are-up120/</guid><description>Berlin Hadoop Get Together - videos are up # Markus Andrezak on Queue management with Kanban:
Queue Management in Product Development with Kanban - enabling flow and fast feedback along the value chain from David Obermann on Vimeo.
Martin Scholl on Storm:
On Firehoses and Storms: Event Thinking, Event Processing from David Obermann on Vimeo.
Fabian Hüske on Stratosphere:
Large-Scale Data Analysis Beyond Map/Reduce from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - February 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-february-201242/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:14:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-february-201242/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - February 2012 # Today the first Hadoop Get Together Berlin 2012 took place - David got the event hosted by and at Axel Springer who kindly also paid for the (soon to be published) videos. Thanks also to the unbelievable Machine company for the tasty buffet after the meetup. Another thanks to Open Source Press for donating three of their Hadoop books.
Today&amp;rsquo;s selection was quite diverse: The event started with a presentation by Markus Andrezak who gave an overview of Kanban and how it helped him change the development workflow over at eBay/mobile.</description></item><item><title>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 20:34:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</guid><description>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get-Together is scheduled for 22. February, 6 p.m. - taking place at Axel Springer, Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10888 Berlin. Thanks to Springer for sponsoring the location!
Note: It is important to indicate attendance. Due to security restrictions at the venue only registered visitors will be permitted. Get your ticket here: https://www.xing.com/events/hadoop-22-02-859807
Talks scheduled thus far:
Markus Andrezak : &amp;ldquo;Queue Management in Product Development with Kanban - enabling flow and fast feedback along the value chain&amp;rdquo; - It&amp;rsquo;s a truism today that fast feedback from your market is a key advantage.</description></item><item><title>Video up: Douwe Osinga</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-douwe-osinga422/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 22:01:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-douwe-osinga422/</guid><description>Video up: Douwe Osinga # Douwe Osinga: Overview of the Data Processing Pipeline at Triposo from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Video: Max Jacob on Pig for NLP</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-jacob-on-pig-for-nlp426/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:26:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-jacob-on-pig-for-nlp426/</guid><description>Video: Max Jacob on Pig for NLP # Max Jacob: Pig for Natural Language Processing from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Slides online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-online375/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 06:55:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-online375/</guid><description>Slides online # Slides of this week&amp;rsquo;s Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are online at:
Douwe Osinga: Overview of the Data Processing Pipeline at Triposo
Max Jacob: Pig for Natural Language Processing
Overall a great event, well organised - looking forward to seeing you at the next Get Together. If you want to get in touch with our participants, learn about new events or simply chat between meetups join our Apache Hadoop Get Together Linked.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin December 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-december-201159/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 01:50:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-december-201159/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin December 2011 # First of all a huge Thank You to David Obermann for organising today&amp;rsquo;s Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin: After a successful Berlin Buzzwords and a rather long pause following that finally a Christmas meetup took place today at Smarthouse, kindly sponsored by Axel Springer and organised by David Obermann from idealo. About 40 guests from Neofonie, Nokia, Amen, StudiVZ, Gameduell, TU Berlin, nurago, Soundcloud, nugg.</description></item><item><title>December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-2149/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 20:14:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-2149/</guid><description>December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # First of all please note that meetup organisation is being transitioned over to our xing meetup group. So in order to be notified of future meetings, make sure to join that group. Please make also sure to register for the December event as in contrast to past meetups this time space will be limited, so make sure to grab a ticket. If you cannot make it, please let the organiser know so he can issue additional tickets.</description></item><item><title>Cloudera in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloudera-in-berlin142/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 20:24:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloudera-in-berlin142/</guid><description>Cloudera in Berlin # Cloudera is hosting another round of trainings in Berlin in November this year. In addition to the trainings on Apache Hadoop this time around there will also be trainings on Apache HBase.
Register online via:
http://www.eventbrite.com/event/2315126606
http://www.eventbrite.com/event/2349094204</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 16:20:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over # Apache Hadoop receives lots of attention from large US corporations who are using the project to scale their data processing pipelines:
“Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive extensively to process large data sets. [&amp;hellip;]” (Ashish Thusoo, Engineering Manager at Facebook), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop is a key ingredient in allowing LinkedIn to build many of our most computationally difficult features [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo; (Jay Kreps, Principal Engineer, LinkedIn), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop enables [Twitter] to store, process, and derive insights from our data in ways that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise be possible.</description></item><item><title>Video is up: Paolo Negri on scaling by one order of magnitude</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-paolo-negri-on-scaling-by-one-order-of-magnitude421/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 21:23:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-paolo-negri-on-scaling-by-one-order-of-magnitude421/</guid><description> Video is up: Paolo Negri on scaling by one order of magnitude #</description></item><item><title>Video is up - Simon Willnauer on Lucene 4 Performance improvements</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-simon-willnauer-on-lucene-4-performance-improvements420/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 21:21:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-simon-willnauer-on-lucene-4-performance-improvements420/</guid><description> Video is up - Simon Willnauer on Lucene 4 Performance improvements #</description></item><item><title>Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 21:19:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</guid><description> Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia #</description></item><item><title>Slides of yesterday's Apache Hadoop Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-of-yesterdays-apache-hadoop-get-together374/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 21:40:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-of-yesterdays-apache-hadoop-get-together374/</guid><description>Slides of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Apache Hadoop Get Together # This time with little less than 24 hours delay - the usual, by some impatiently expected, summary of the Apache Hadoop Get Together. The meetup took place at Zanox&amp;rsquo; event campus. The room was well filled with some fourty attendees from various companies, experience with Hadoop ranging from interested beginners to experienced users.
Slides of all presentations:
Josh Devins on Hadoop at Nokia</description></item><item><title>WiFi at the Apache Hadoop Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wifi-at-the-apache-hadoop-get-together433/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 20:40:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/wifi-at-the-apache-hadoop-get-together433/</guid><description>WiFi at the Apache Hadoop Get Together # Just a brief reminder: The next Apache Hadoop Get Together is scheduled to take place on Thursday, January 27th at 6p.m. at the Zanox Event Campus at Media Spree Berlin.
We have three very interesting talks, though thirty guests registered already, we still have a few free seats. Head over to the xing event page to register if you have not done so yet.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 16:31:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by Cloudera and Zanox that will take place in the Zanox Event Campus in Berlin.
When: January 27th 2011, 6p.m.
Where: zanox Event Campus (Please mark the changed event location.)
&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Größere Kartenansicht
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop - Trainings by Cloudera in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-trainings-by-cloudera-in-berlin39/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 23:53:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-trainings-by-cloudera-in-berlin39/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop - Trainings by Cloudera in Berlin # Cloudera is offering trainings both for Administrators as well as for Developers early next year in Berlin. If your are getting started in using Apache Hadoop this might be a great option to get your developers and operations up to speed with the framework. If you are a regular of the local Apache Hadoop Get Together a discount code should have been sent to you by mail.</description></item><item><title>Video: Max Heimel on sequence tagging w/ Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-heimel-on-sequence-tagging-w-apache-mahout425/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 19:58:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-max-heimel-on-sequence-tagging-w-apache-mahout425/</guid><description>Video: Max Heimel on sequence tagging w/ Apache Mahout # Some time ago Max Heimel from TU Berlin gave presentation of the new HMM support in the Mahout 0.4 release at the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin:
Mahout Max Heimel from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to JTeam for sponsoring video taping, thanks to newthinking for providing the location and thanks to Martin Schmidt from newthinking for producing the video.</description></item><item><title>Video: Sebastian Schelter on Recommendation w/ Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-sebastian-schelter-on-recommendation-w-apache-mahout427/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 13:55:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-sebastian-schelter-on-recommendation-w-apache-mahout427/</guid><description>Video: Sebastian Schelter on Recommendation w/ Apache Mahout # A few weeks ago we had the autumn edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together in newthinking store in Berlin. I am glad to announce the first video online:
Mahout Sebastian Schelter from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to JTeam for sponsoring video taping, thanks to newthinking for providing the location and thanks to Martin Schmidt from newthinking for producing the video.</description></item><item><title>Slides available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-available373/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 09:19:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-available373/</guid><description>Slides available # Yesterday evening the Autumn Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. The meetup this time focussed mainly on latest developments at Apache Mahout. The meetup was kindly sponsored by JTeam, providing video taping of the presentations as well as for free drinks. Thanks a lot for that.
After the meetup the group went over to Cafe Aufsturz for drinks, food and lots of interesting discussions - I left them there as I still have to get rid of a persistent cold.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 09:52:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today # Just a brief reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is supposed to take place today in newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48 at 5p.m.
The meeting features two talks on Apache Mahout: Committer Sebastian Schelter will explain how to scale recommender systems with Mahout. Contributor Max Heimel is going to give an introduction to the sequence labeling facilities available in Mahout.
As usual the group will move over to Cafe Aufsturz after the meetup is over.</description></item><item><title>A Get Together Checklist</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/a-get-together-checklist4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 19:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/a-get-together-checklist4/</guid><description>A Get Together Checklist # Still on the list of potentially interesting books: The Checklist Manifesto - explaining why checklists can still be valuable - especially for complex problems and tasks.
Though not very complex, I chose to come up with a checklist for running a Hadoop Get Together in Berlin as an exercise. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stick with advise provided by the Checklist for Checklists.
Parties involved
Find two to three speakers two months in advance.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 07:31:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by JTeam that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: October 7th, 5p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin, Tucholksystr. 48
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Some pictures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 11:00:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</guid><description>Some pictures # Uwe and Simon were so kind to take some pictures of the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_1.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_5.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
Thanks for the pictures.</description></item><item><title>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 03:41:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</guid><description>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase # At the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Bob Schulze from eCircle in Munich gave a presentation on “Tips and patterns with HBase”. The talk has been video recorded. The result is now available online:
HBase Bob Schulze from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video. Thanks to Bob for an awesome talk on eCircle’s usage of HBase - and on providing some background information on how HBase was applied to solve your problems.</description></item><item><title>Dragan Milosevic on Product Search and Reporting with Hadoop</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-product-search-and-reporting-with-hadoop164/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 20:30:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-product-search-and-reporting-with-hadoop164/</guid><description>Dragan Milosevic on Product Search and Reporting with Hadoop # At the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Dragan Milosevic from zanox in Berlin gave a presentation on &amp;ldquo;Product Search and Reporting powered by Hadoop&amp;rdquo;. The talk has been video recorded. The result is now available online:
&amp;lt;param name=&amp;ldquo;allowscriptaccess&amp;rdquo; value=&amp;ldquo;always&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;Hadoop Dragan Milosevic from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video. Thanks to Dragan for a fantastic talk on Zanox&amp;rsquo; usage of Hadoop - and on providing some background information on why and how you introduced Hadoop into your systems.</description></item><item><title>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 20:42:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chris-male-on-spatial-search-with-lucene137/</guid><description>Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene # Last week the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. Last speaker was Chris Male on spatial search with Lucene and Solr. The video is now available online:
Lucene Chris Male from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video to anyone who might be interested. Thank you Chris, for traveling over from Amsterdam for an awesome talk on spatial search.</description></item><item><title>Slides are available</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:49:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-available371/</guid><description>Slides are available # Slides for the last Hadoop Get Together are available online:
Spatial Search by Chris Male
HBase Patterns by Bob Schulze
Scaling product search with Hadoop and Lucene by Dragan Milosevic
My own little introduction, just in case you are interested.
Videos will follow as soon as the are ready. Watch this space for further updates.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:40:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-201060/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together March 2010 # Today (or more correctly, yesterday) the March 2010 Hadoop Get Together took place in newthinking store. I arrived rather early to have some time to do some planning for Berlin Buzzwords - got there nearly one hour before the meetup. However it did not take very long until first guests came to the store. So I quickly got my introductory slides in place - Martin from newthinking already had the room setup, camera in place and audio working.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - March 2010 - Update</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-2010-update44/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 14:25:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-2010-update44/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - March 2010 - Update # Due to conflicts in the schedule of newthinking store, we had to change the time of the Get Together slightly. We will start one hour earlier than announced.
When: March 10th, 4p.m.
Where: newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin Mitte
Looking forward to seeing you there.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop trainings in Europe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-trainings-in-europe224/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 19:23:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-trainings-in-europe224/</guid><description>Hadoop trainings in Europe # Recently I received this mail from Christophe Bisciglia on Cloudera Hadoop trainings. Thought it might be interesting to the Hadoop Berlin community: Hadoop Fans,
Over the next year, you&amp;rsquo;ll see new options for Hadoop training and
certification from Cloudera. One of the first things you&amp;rsquo;ll see will
be live sessions outside the US, tentatively planned for the April /
May time frame.
We&amp;rsquo;ve seen strong interest in Hadoop on all of our international</description></item><item><title>Hadoop at Heise c't</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 13:37:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</guid><description>Hadoop at Heise c&amp;rsquo;t # &amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising&amp;gt;
Interesting for those readers speaking German: Heise published an introductory article on Hadoop in its latest issue. Have fun reading.
&amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising/&amp;gt;
Thanks to Simon for proof-reading and providing valuable input. Thanks to Thilo Fromm for the hadoop graphics (unfortunately none of them got published in its original form), the catchy title, proof-reading the text over and over again and for keeping me sane during several past and coming months.</description></item><item><title>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 08:40:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</guid><description>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: March 10th, 4p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Third "December Hadoop Get Together" video online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-december-hadoop-get-together-video-online408/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 19:29:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-december-hadoop-get-together-video-online408/</guid><description>Third &amp;ldquo;December Hadoop Get Together&amp;rdquo; video online # In the following video taken at the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Jörg Möllenkamp explains why Hadoop is interesting for Sun - and why Sun Hardware might be a good fit for Hadoop applications:
Hadoop Jörg Möllenkamp from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
In a blog post published after the event, Jörg gives more details on his idea of Parasitic Hadoop he introduced at the meetup.</description></item><item><title>Second December Hadoop Get Together video</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/second-december-hadoop-get-together-video361/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 14:57:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/second-december-hadoop-get-together-video361/</guid><description>Second December Hadoop Get Together video # Richard Hutton from nugg.ad explained how they scaled their ad recommendation system to an increasing number of users with the help of Hadoop. To learn more on their use case and details on which problems they solved with Hadoop, watch the video below:
Hadoop Richard Hutton from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 20:27:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</guid><description>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online # The video of Nikolaus&amp;rsquo; Pohle&amp;rsquo;s talk at the December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is online already - more to come soon.
hadoop nikolaus pohle from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to Martin from newthinking for video taping and uploading. Thanks to StudiVZ for sponsoring the video.</description></item><item><title>Summary - December Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/summary-december-get-together386/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 22:23:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/summary-december-get-together386/</guid><description>Summary - December Get Together # Today the seventh Apache Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. The room was again packed with more than 40 people from various companies with and without practical experience with Hadoop: There were people from Nokia Gate 5, Sun, nurago, StudiVZ, Dawanda, Last.fm, nugg.ad. There were people from academia, e.g. HPI Potsdam. And a few Freelancers interested in the topic or providing help with Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>On Wednesday: December Apache Hadoop @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-berlin311/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 20:15:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-berlin311/</guid><description>On Wednesday: December Apache Hadoop @ Berlin # This week on Wednesday at 5p.m. the December Hadoop Get Together takes place in newthinking store Berlin.
Talks scheduled so far:
Richard Hutton (nugg.ad): “Moving from five days to one hour.” Jörg Möllenkamp (Sun): “Hadoop on Sun” Nikolaus Pohle (nurago): “M/R for MR - Online Market Research powered by Apache Hadoop. Enable consultants to analyze online behavior for audience segmentation, advertising effects and usage patterns.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together next week</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-next-week333/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 20:16:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-next-week333/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together next week # Just a tiny little reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is scheduled to take place next week on Wednesday.
When: 16th of December 8PM
Where: newthinking store Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin Mitte
Kindly sponsored by: newthinking store (location) and StudiVZ (videos).
Please regist er (or use Xing for registration) so planning becomes a bit easier.
Talks scheduled: Richard Hutton (nugg.ad): &amp;ldquo;Moving from five days to one hour.</description></item><item><title>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 18:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</guid><description>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # As announced at ApacheCon US, the next Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is scheduled for December 2009.
When: Wednesday December 16, 2009 at 5:00pm Where: newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 21:05:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</guid><description>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp # This is my first real day at ApacheCon US 2009. I arrived yesterday afternoon, was kept awake by three Lucene committers until midnight: &amp;ldquo;Otherwise you will have a very bad jetlag&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Admittedly it did work out: I slept like a baby until about 08:00a.m. the next morning and am not that tired today.
Today Hackthon, Trainings and barcamp Apache happen in parallel.</description></item><item><title>Videos are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/videos-are-up429/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 07:31:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/videos-are-up429/</guid><description>Videos are up # As of yesterday the videos of the last Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are available online.
Th anks to the speakers for providing insight in their projects and thanks to Cloudera for sponsoring the videos.
The next meetup will be announced soon - three talks have already been proposed. In addition, StudiVZ offered to sponsor video taping of the next Get Together. Looking forward to seeing you in Berlin in December.</description></item><item><title>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 18:13:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</guid><description>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise # After last week&amp;rsquo;s Hadoop Get Together heise published an in-depth article on the changes and improvements that come with the latest Lucene 2.9 release.
Thanks to Simon Willnauer for helping me write this article and patiently explaining several new features. Thanks also to Uwe Schindler for kindly proof-reading the article before it was sent out to Heise.</description></item><item><title>Slides are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-up372/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 09:02:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-up372/</guid><description>Slides are up # The slides for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s talks just arrived. They are available online at:
Isabel Drost: Brief introduction.
Thorsten Schuett: Solving puzzles with map reduce.
Thilo Goetz: An introduction to jaql.
Uwe Schindler: Lucene 2.9 developments.
Videos will be online early next week.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-248/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 16:38:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-248/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The Get Together started just a few minutes ago. The room is packed with more than 35 people this time. This is the first Hadoop Get Together in Berlin that will be recorded on video, thanks to Martin from newthinking for doing the recording and post processing as well as to Cloudera for sponsoring the videos.
The first talk was given by Thorsten Schuett on solving puzzles with map reduce.</description></item><item><title>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 19:00:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</guid><description>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is a friendly reminder that the next Apache Hadoop Get Together takes place next week on Tuesday, 29th of September* at newthinking store (Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin).
Thorsten Schuett, Solving Puzzles with MapReduce.
Thilo Götz, Text analytics on jaql.
Uwe Schindler, Lucene 2.9 Developments.
Big thanks goes to newthinking store for providing the venue for free and to Cloudera for sponsoring videos of the talks.</description></item><item><title>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</guid><description>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is to take place on September 29th in newthinking store. Details are up on the web page at upcoming and will be sent out to the mailing list soon.</description></item><item><title>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 09:11:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</guid><description>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The newthinking store Berlin is hosting the Hadoop Get Together user group meeting. It features talks on Hadoop, Lucene, Solr, UIMA, katta, Mahout and various other projects that deal with making large amounts of data accessible and processable. The event brings together leaders from the developer and user communities. The speakers present projects that build on top of Hadoop, case studies of applications being built and deployed on Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Lucene slides online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 10:04:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</guid><description>Lucene slides online # The slides of the Lucene talk at the last Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are available online: Lucene Slides. Especially interesting to me are the last few slides which detail both index size and machine setup:
The installation is running on two standard PCs with 2 dual-core processors (usual speed, bought in January 2008 for about 4000 Euro). They have 32GB RAM, 24 GB are used as ramdisk for the index.</description></item><item><title>Data serialization</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-serialization146/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 08:39:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-serialization146/</guid><description>Data serialization # XML, JSON and others are currently standard data exchange formats. Being human-readable but still structured enough to be easily parsable by programs is their main benefit. Problems are overhead in size and parsing time. In addition at least xml is not really as human-readable as it could be.
An alternative are binary formats. Yet those often are not platform independent (either C++ or Java or Python bindings) or are not upgradable (what if your boss comes along and wants you to add yet another field?</description></item><item><title>March 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin283/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 19:50:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin283/</guid><description>March 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin # Since last summer, newthinking store Berlin is hosting a Hadoop Meetup every quarter of the year. The scope of these user group meetings is not only on Hadoop projects but deals with technologies necessary with storing, processing and searching large amounts of data.
The meeting last Thursday featured a talk by Lars George on his experiences using HBase in customer projects as early as in 2007.</description></item></channel></rss>