<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>General on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/General/</link><description>Recent content in General on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 11:24:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/General/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thanks for all the help</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/thanks-for-all-the-help406/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 11:24:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/thanks-for-all-the-help406/</guid><description>Thanks for all the help # This year was a blast: It started with the ever great FOSDEM in Brussels (see you there in 2013?), an invitation to GeeCon in Poznan (if you ever get an invitation to speak there - do accept, the organisers do an amazing job at that event). In summer we had Berlin Buzzwords in Berlin for the third time with 700 attendees (to retain the community feel to the conference we decided to limit tickets in 2013, so make sure you get your&amp;rsquo;s early).</description></item><item><title>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 12:40:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</guid><description>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012 # Earlier this month I attended the fourth Recommender Stammtisch in Berlin. The event was kindly hosted by Soundcloud - who on top of organising the speakers provided a really yummy buffet by Kochzeichen D.
With Paul Lamere the evening started with a very entertaining but also very packed talk on why music recommendation is special - or put more generally why all recommender systems are special:</description></item><item><title>Strata EU - part 4</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-4385/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 20:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-4385/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 4 # The rest of the day was mainly reserved for more technical talks: Tom Wight introducing the merits of MR2, also known as YARN. Steve Loughran gave a very insightful talk on the various failure modes of Hadoop – though the Namenode is like the most obvious single point of failure there are a few more traps waiting for those depending on their Hadoop clusters: Hadoop does just find with single harddisks failing.</description></item><item><title>Strata EU - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-3384/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 20:16:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-3384/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 3 # The first Tuesday morning keynote put the hype around big data into historical context: According to wikipedia big data apps are defined by their capability of coping with data set sizes that are larger than can be handled with commonly available machines and algorithms. Going from that definition we can look back to history and will realize that the issue of big data actually isn&amp;rsquo;t that new: Even back in the 1950s people had to deal with big data problems.</description></item><item><title>Strata EU - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-2383/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 20:15:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-2383/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 2 # The second keynote touched upon the topic of data literacy: In an age in which growing amounts of data are being generated being able to make sense of these becomes a crucial skill for citizens just like reading, writing and computing. The speaker&amp;rsquo;s message was two-fold: a) People currently are not being taught how to deal with that data but are being taught that all that growing data is evil.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata London - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-london-part-1306/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 20:13:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-london-part-1306/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata London - part 1 # A few weeks ago I attended O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata EU. As I had the honour of being on the program committee I remember how hard it was to decide on which talks to accept and which ones to decline. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see that potential turned into an awesome conference on all things Big Data.
I arrived a bit late as I flew in only Monday morning.</description></item><item><title>Some thoughts on a conf taxonomy</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-thoughts-on-a-conf-taxonomy380/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 12:53:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-thoughts-on-a-conf-taxonomy380/</guid><description>Some thoughts on a conf taxonomy # One common way for open source developers to meet face-to-face is to attend conferences relevant to their subject of interest. A common way to have one near you if there ain&amp;rsquo;t none yet is to go and organise one yourself. The most obvious stuff to resolve for that task:
Most likely there will be some financial transactions involved - sponsors wanting to support you, attendees paying for their tickets, you paying for the venue and for food.</description></item><item><title>Moving to a new domain</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 12:30:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</guid><description>Moving to a new domain # Executive summary: This is to warn those of you who are subscribed to this blog - the domain to reach this blog w/o redirects will soon change to by isabel-drost-fromm.de - you might want to adjust your rss subscription accordingly.
Longer version: This blog post is scheduled to go live some time after lunch-time on September 12th 2012. You might have heart rumors before - that date Ms.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - on teaching</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-on-teaching194/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 08:17:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-on-teaching194/</guid><description>FrOSCon - on teaching # The last talk I went to during FrOSCon was Selena&amp;rsquo;s keynote on &amp;ldquo;Mistakes were made&amp;rdquo;. She started by explaining how she taught computer science (or even just computer-) concepts to teachers herself - emphasizing how exhausting teaching can be, how many even trivial concepts were unknown to her students. After that Selena briefly sketched how she herself came to IT - emphasizing how providing mostly the information she needed to accomplish the current task at hand and telling how to get more information helped her make her first steps a great deal.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - understanding Linux with strace</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-understanding-linux-with-strace196/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 20:29:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-understanding-linux-with-strace196/</guid><description>FrOSCon - understanding Linux with strace # Being a Java child I had only dealt with strace once before: Trying to figure out whether any part of the Mahout tests happens to use /dev/random for initialisation in a late night debugging session with my favourite embedded Linux developer. Strace itself is a great tool to actually see what your program is doing in terms of system calls, giving you the option to follow on a very detailed level what is going on.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon - Robust Linux embedded platform</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-robust-linux-embedded-platform195/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 20:05:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-robust-linux-embedded-platform195/</guid><description>FrOSCon - Robust Linux embedded platform # The second talk I went to at FrOSCon was given by Thilo Fromm on Building a robust embedded Linux platform. For more information on the underlying project see also projec HidaV on github. Slides of the talk Building a robust Linux embedded platform are already online.
Inspired by a presentation on safe upgrade prodedures in embedded devices by Arnaut Vandecappelle in the Embedded Dev Room FOSDEM earlier this year Thilo extended the scope of the presentation a bit to cover safe kernel upgrades as well as package updates in embedded systems.</description></item><item><title>Clojure Berlin - March 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-berlin-march-2012139/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:37:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-berlin-march-2012139/</guid><description>Clojure Berlin - March 2012 # In today&amp;rsquo;s Clojure meetup Stefan Hübner gave an introduction to Cascalog - a Clojure library based on Cascading for large scale data processing on Apache Hadoop without hassle.
After a brief overview of what he is using the tool for to do log processing at his day job for http://maps.nokia.com Stefan went into some more detail on why he chose Cascalog over other project that provide abstraction layers on top of Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s plain map/reduce library: Both Pig and Hive provide easy to learn SQL-like languages to quickly write analysis jobs.</description></item><item><title>HowTo: Meetups in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/howto-meetups-in-berlin237/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 20:23:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/howto-meetups-in-berlin237/</guid><description>HowTo: Meetups in Berlin # I get that question once in a while - and need the list below myself every now and then: How to actually setup a meetup in Germany. Essentially it all boils down to three questions: Which channels to use for PR? Where to do the meeting? What other benefits to offer to attendees?
When it comes to PR there are several options: Announce the meetup on relevant mailing lists</description></item><item><title>Clojure in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-in-berlin140/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:01:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-in-berlin140/</guid><description>Clojure in Berlin # Though I had the chance to tinker with some Clojure code only briefly it&amp;rsquo;s programming model and the resulting compact programs do fascinate me. As the resulting code runs on a JVM and does integrate well with existing Java libraries migration is comparably cheap and easy.
Today I finally managed to attend the local Berlin Clojure meetup, co-organised by Stefan Hübner and Fronx. Timing couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been much better: In this evenings event Philip Potter from Thoughtworks introduced Overtone - a library for making music with Clojure.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Chicago</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-chicago396/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 21:56:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-chicago396/</guid><description>Teddy in Chicago # Last week I spent several days in Chicago mainly to attend a few meetings at the local Nokia/Navteq office. Though the schedule was pretty packed, a few hours remained to explore the then frosty and windy city:
Top three images: Some impressions of the city. Bottom left: Teddy&amp;rsquo;s new friend. Bottom right: Situation at ORD when flying out - fortunately both, the airport as well as the airline (Swiss) have quite some experience with challenging weather conditions so that we could leave without too much delay.</description></item><item><title>#28c3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/28c33/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 02:07:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/28c33/</guid><description>#28c3 # Restate my assumptions. One: Mathematics is the language of nature.
Two: Everything around us can be represented and understood through numbers.
Three: If you graph the numbers of any system, patterns emerge. Therefore, there are patterns everywhere in nature.
The above is a quote from today's "Hackers in movies" talk at 28c3 - which amongst others also showed a brief snippet of the movie Pi. For several years I stayed well away from that one famous Hackers' conference in Berlin that takes place annually between Christmas and New Year.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Tech Meetups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 22:32:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</guid><description>Berlin Tech Meetups # Berlin currently is of growing interest for software engineers, has a very active startup scene and as a result several community organised meetups. Listed below is a short, &amp;ldquo;highly objective&amp;rdquo; selection of local user groups - showing just the breadth of topics discussed.
Berlin Hadoop Get Together
Berlin DevOps
Berlin Buzzwords (conference, no meetup)
Berlin Scrumtisch
Java User Group Berlin/Brandenburg
Berlin Google Technology User Group</description></item><item><title>GoTo Con AMS - Day 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-amsterdam-day-2217/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 10:47:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-amsterdam-day-2217/</guid><description>GoTo Con AMS - Day 2 # Day two of GoTo Con Amsterdam started with a keynote by former Squeak developer Dan Ingalls. He introduced the Lively kernel - a component architecture for HTML5 that runs in any browser and allows easy composition, sharing and programming of items. Having seen Squeak years ago and being thrilled by its concepts even back then it was amazing to see what you can do with Lively kernel in a browser.</description></item><item><title>GoTo Con AMS - Day 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-ams-day-1216/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 20:44:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-ams-day-1216/</guid><description>GoTo Con AMS - Day 1 # Last week GoTo Con took place in Amsterdam. Being a sister conference to GoTo in Aarhus the Amsterdam event focused on the broad topics of agile development, architectural challenges, backend and frontend development, platforms like the JVM and .NET. In addition the Amsterdam event featured a special Apache track tailored towards presentations focusing on the development model at Apache and the technologies developed at Apache.</description></item><item><title>Night Trains</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 05:40:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</guid><description>Night Trains # It was several years ago that a frequent traveller told me about it being more comfortable and time saving to travel mid-sized distances (e.g. from Berlin to Amsterdam) by train - night train that is - instead of flying. Back then without decent knowledge of which combination of booking early and discount card make prizes of trips by train somewhat comparable to those offered by airlines that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an option for me.</description></item><item><title>GoTo Con</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con215/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 20:49:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con215/</guid><description>GoTo Con # Location: Amsterdam
Link out: Click here
Start Date: 2011-10-12
End Date: 2011-10-14
This week late Tuesday night I am going to leave for GoTo con in Amsterdam. Train tickets are already booked - this is going to be my first trip with City Night line, will see how great they are.
GoTo Amsterdam features a special Apache track as well as several talk on scaling up, searching, but also includes stuff in general architectural decisions.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:18:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-meetup-amsterdam81/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Meetup Amsterdam # Last week I was honoured to be invited as one of the two speakers on Apache Mahout at the Mahout meetup in Amsterdam at JTeams offices. After free beer, cola and pizza Frank Scholten gave an overview of Mahout's clustering capabilities. After a brief introduction to Mahout itself he went into a little more detail on how clustering works in general. After that with a selection of Seinfeld scripts he used a fun data set to guide the audience through the process of choosing the right data preparation steps, coming up with good training parameters and finally evaluating clustering quality.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Sunday - smaller bits and pieces</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-sunday-smaller-bits-and-pieces182/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 20:17:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-sunday-smaller-bits-and-pieces182/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Sunday - smaller bits and pieces # With WebODF the Office track featured a very interesting project that focusses on providing a means to open ODF documents in your favourite browser: Content and formatting are converted to a form that can easily be dealt with by using a combination of HTML and CSS. Advanced editing is then supported by using JavaScript.
With Open Stack the following talk focussed on an open cloud stack project that was started by NASA and Rackspace as both simultanously needed support for an open source, openly designed, developed cloud stack that strives for community inclusion.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</guid><description>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging # Nicolas Spiegelberg gave an awesome introduction not only to the architecture that powers Facebook messaging but also to the design decisions behind their use of Apache HBase as a storage backend. Disclaimer: HBase is being used for message storage, for attachements with Haystack a different backend is used.
The reasons to go for HBase include its strong consistency model, support for auto failover, load balancing of shards, support for compression, atomic read-modify-write support and the inherent Map/Reduce support.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Django</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-django179/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 20:17:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-django179/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Django # The languages/ cloud computing track on Sunday started with the good, the bad and the ugly of Django's architecture. Without much ado the speaker started by giving a high level overview of the general package layout of Django - unfortunately not going into too much detail on the architecture itself.
What he loves about Django are the model layer abstractions that really are no ORM only - instead both relational and non-relational databases can be supported easily.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Saturday</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-saturday181/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 20:17:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-saturday181/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Saturday # Day one at FOSDEM started with a very interesting and timely keynote by Eben Moglen: Starting with the example of Egypt he voted for de-centralized distributed and thus harder to take over communication systems. In terms of tooling we are already almost there. Most use cases like micro blogging, social networking and real time communications can already be implemented in a distributed, fail safe way. So instead of going for convenience it is time to think about digital independence from very few central providers.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 22:18:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures # Big data at startups - Info ChimpsAs a startup to get good people there is no other option then to grow your own: Offer the option to gain a lot of experience in return for a not so great wage. Start out with really great hires:
People who have the &amp;quot;get shit done gene&amp;quot;: They discover new projects, are proud to contribute to team efforts, are confident in making changes to a code base probably not known before hand.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 20:17:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes # Day two of Strata started with a very inspiring insight from the host itself that extended the vision discussed earlier in the tutorials: It's not at all about the tools, the current data analytics value lies in the data itself and in the conclusions and actions drawn from analysing it.
Bit.ly keynoteThe first key note was presented by bit.ly - for them there are four dimensions to data analytics:</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 20:17:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics # Acting based on dataIt comes as no surprise to hear that also in the data analytics world engineers are unwilling to share details of how their analysis works with higher management - with on the other side not much interest on learning how analytics really works. This culture leads to a sort of black art, witch craft attitude to data analytics that hinders most innovation.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 20:13:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</guid><description>Teddy in San Francisco # Before attending O'Reilly Strata there were a few days left to adjust to the different time zone, meet up with friends and generally spend some days in the Greater San Francisco area. As was to be expected, those were way to few days. The weekend was a bit rainy, still packed with visiting China town right after the plane had landed and spending some time at .</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout in Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-in-amsterdam80/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 20:00:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-in-amsterdam80/</guid><description>Apache Mahout in Amsterdam # On February 7th there will be an Apache Mahout meetup in Amsterdam kindly organised by JTeam. There will be two presentations - one by myself on classification with Apache Mahout as well as a second one by Frank Scholten on clustering with Apache Mahout.
Time: 18:00
Location: Frederiksplein 1, 1017XK Amsterdam, The Netherlands
Looking forward to a few days in Amsterdam.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM II 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 15:46:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</guid><description>FOSDEM II 2011 # It&amp;rsquo;s already sort of a nice little tradition for me to spend the first weekend in February in Brussels for FOSDEM. This year I am particulary happy that there will be a Data Analytics Dev Room at FOSDEM. A huge Thanks to @ogrisel and @nmaillot who have done most of the heavy lifting of getting the schedule in place.
Looking forward to an interesting Cloud Track, to meeting Peter Hintjens who is going to give a talk on 0MQ, the DevOps presentation and lots of very interesting DevRooms.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata Conference</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 04:34:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-conference305/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference # Title: O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata Conference
Location: Santa Clara
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Description: Early next February O&amp;rsquo;Reilly is planning to put on a very interesting conference on the topic of data analysis and the business of generating value from raw digital data. I&amp;rsquo;m really glad to have received the acceptance notification for my presentation and travel sponsorship from the DICODE project. So see you in Santa Clara.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day one – Java, Performance and Devops</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-one-java-performance-and-devops155/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 21:22:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-one-java-performance-and-devops155/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day one – Java, Performance and Devops # In his keynote Mark Reinhold provided some information on the very interesting features to be included in the Java 7 release. Generics will be easier to declare with the diamond operator. Nested try-finally constructs that are nowadays needed to safely close resources will no longer be necessary – their will be the option of implementing a Closeable interface supporting a method close() that get&amp;rsquo;s called whenever objects of that class&amp;rsquo;s type go out of scope.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 21:30:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</guid><description>Teddy in Antwerp # When at Devoxx Teddy went to the city taking a few pictures of the Grote Markt, the Haven as well as the main train station.</description></item><item><title>Apache Lunch Devoxx</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 21:30:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</guid><description>Apache Lunch Devoxx # On Twitter I suggested to host an Apache dinner during Devoxx. Matthias Wesendorf of Apache MyFaces was so kind to take up the discussion carrying it over to the Apache community mailing-list. It quickly turned out that there was quite some interest with several members and committers attending Devoxx. We scheduled the meetup for Friday after the conference during lunch time.
I pinged a few Apache related people I knew would attend the conference (being a speaker and a committer at some Apache project almost certainly resulted in getting a ping).</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day three</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-three156/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 21:28:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-three156/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day three # The panel discussion on the future of Java was driven by visitor submitted and voted questions on the current state and future of Java. The general take-aways for me included the clear statement that the TCK will never be made available to the ASF. The promise of Oracle to continue supporting the Java community and remaining active in the JCP.
There was some discussion on whether coming Java versions should be backwards-incompatible.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 21:25:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-2-hbase154/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day 2 HBase # Devoxx featured several interesting case studies of how HBase and Hadoop can be used to scale data analysis back ends as well as data serving front ends. Twitter
Dmitry Ryaboy from Twitter explained how to scale high load and large data systems using Cassandra. Looking at the sheer amount of tweets generated each day it becomes obvious that with a system like MySQL alone this site cannot be run.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – Day two – Hadoop and HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-two-hadoop-and-hbase158/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 21:24:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-day-two-hadoop-and-hbase158/</guid><description>Devoxx – Day two – Hadoop and HBase # In his session on the current state of Hadoop Tom went into a little more detail not only on the features released in the latest release or on the roadmap for upcoming releases (including Kerberos based security, append support, warm standby namenode and others).
He also gave a very interesting view on the current Hadoop ecosystem. More and more projects are currently being created that either extend Hadoop or are built on top of Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 21:20:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-cassandra-hbase159/</guid><description>Devoxx – University – Cassandra, HBase # During the morning session FIXME Ellison gave an introduction to the distributed NoSQL database Cassandra. Being generally based on the Dynamo paper from Amazon the key-value store distributes key/value pairs according to a consistent hashing schema. Nodes can be added dynamically making the system well suited for elastic scaling. In contrast to Dynamo, Cassandra can be tuned for the required consistency level. The system is tuned for storing moderately sized key/value pairs.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:17:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</guid><description>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase # The first day at Devoxx featured several tutorials – most interesting to me was the pragramatic programmer. The speaker also is the author of the equally named book at O&amp;rsquo;Reilly. The book was the result of the observation that developers today are more and more IDE bound, no longer able to use the command line effectively. The result are developers that are unnecessarily slow when creating software.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 21:16:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</guid><description>Devoxx Antwerp # With 3000 attendees Devoxx is the largest Java Community conference world-wide. Each year in autumn it takes place in Antwerp/ Belgium, in recent years in the Metropolis cinema. The conference tickets were sold out long before doors were opened this year.
The focus of the presentations are mainly on enterprise Java featuring talks by famous Joshua Bloch, Mark Reihnhold and others on new features of the upcoming JDK release as well as intricacies of the Java programming language itself.</description></item><item><title>Travelling</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 23:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</guid><description>Travelling # Currently on my way back from a series of conferences in the past three weeks in the IC from Schiphol. After three weeks of conferences, lots of new input and lots of interesting projects I learned about it is finally time to head back and put the stuff I have learned to good use.
View Travelling in a larger map
As seems normal with open source conferences I got far more input on interesting projects than I can expect to ever get applied in on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track # This year&amp;rsquo;s Devoxx will feature several presentations coming from the Apache Hadoop ecosystem including Tom White on the basics of Hadoop: HDFS, MapReduce, Hive and Pig as well as Michael Stack on HBase.
&amp;lt; br&amp;gt;
In addition there will be a brief Tools in Action presentation on Monday evening featuring Apache Mahout.
Please let me know if you are going to Devoxx - would be great to meet some more Apache people there, maybe have dinner at one of the conference days.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 09:36:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits # Second week of November I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few days in Lisbon - never would have thought that I&amp;rsquo;d return so quickly when I visited this beautiful city this summer during vacation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for Codebits - thanks to Sapo for inviting me to be there.
Back in summer I learned only after I returned to Germany that there was someone form Portugal seeking to meet with other Apache people exactly when I was down there.</description></item><item><title>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 06:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</guid><description>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011 # Call for Presentations: Data Analysis Dev Room, FOSDEM
http://fosdem.org
5 February 2011
1pm to 7pm
Brussels, Belgium
This is to announce the Data Analysis DevRoom co-located with FOSDEM. The first Meetup on analysing and learning from data, taking place in Brussels, Belgium.
Important Dates (all dates in GMT +2):
Submission deadline: 2010-12-17
Notification of accepted speakers: 2010-12-20
Publication of final schedule: 2011-01-10</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:51:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</guid><description>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin # This evening the first Machine Learning Gossip meeting is scheduled to take place at 9p.m. at Victoriabar: Professionals working in research advancing machine learning algorithms and industry projects putting machine learning algorithms to practical use meet for some drinks, food and hopefully lots of interesting discussions.
If successful the meeting is supposed to take place on a regular schedule. Ask Michael Brückner for the date and location of the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 07:31:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-october-201058/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - October 2010 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by JTeam that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: October 7th, 5p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin, Tucholksystr. 48
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner DUS</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 19:10:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</guid><description>Apache Dinner DUS # the evening after FrOSCon - that is on August 22nd 2010 at 7:30p.m. CEST - a combined &amp;ldquo;FSFE Fellowship meetup/ Apache dinner*&amp;rdquo; takes place in Tigges in Düsseldorf (Brunnenstraße 1, at Bilker S-Bahnhof). Given it doesn&amp;rsquo;t rain, we&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting outside.
Would be great to meet you there for tasty food, interesting discussions on Apache in general, as well as projects like Lucene, Hadoop or Tomcat in particular.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Chemnitzer Linuxtage</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chemnitzer-linuxtage136/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 12:32:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chemnitzer-linuxtage136/</guid><description>Chemnitzer Linuxtage # Title: Chemnitzer Linuxtage
Location: Chemnitz
Link out: Click here
Start Date: 2010-03-13
End Date: 2010-03-14
Next week the Chemnither Linuxtage take place in - well - Chemnitz. It is the second largest Linux event after Linuxtag Berlin. However only obvious for speakers and exhibitors: It is one of those events that are known for its fantastic organisation. Nearly no problems, be it WiFi, admission to the exhibitors area, food or any help in general.</description></item><item><title>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 19:13:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</guid><description>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin # Today first talks scheduled for ignite Berlin were published. If you yourself would like to give a talk: Submission seems to still be open.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - video recordings online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 20:32:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</guid><description>FOSDEM - video recordings online # As published in the FOSDEM blog the video recordings are available online - at least for the main track and the lightning talks. Happy video watching!</description></item><item><title>Open Community Camp 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 13:07:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</guid><description>Open Community Camp 2010 # The following information just reached my via Marten Vijn. Thought it might be interesting to you:
I am pleased to announce OpenCommunityCamp 2010.
The camp is from 10th to 18th July, in Oegstgeest, the Netherlands.
The website[1] is refreshed and the first speakers are booked.
It is time to register[2] if you plan be there (please do this
quickly). Currently we need to find more people to attend, self-organizing groups</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010 # As announced at FOSDEM: Early June (currently scheduled for 7th/8th) a conference on the topics scalable search, storage and processing will take place in Kalkscheune/Berlin. The conference is co-organised by newthinking store, Jan Lehnardt, Simon Willnauer, Thilo Fromm, and Isabel Drost.
The focus will be on NoSQL databases like CouchDB, Jackrabbit, MongoDB, HBase. Search tracks will cover topics like Lucene, Solr, katta and others.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 21:02:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3 # Sunday started in Janson with Andrian Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s talk on RepRap machines, that is devices that can be used as manufacturing devices and are able to replicate themselves. After that I went over to the Mono dev room to listen to Miguel de Icaza on Mono Edge. A great talk on the history of Mono, the way the community interacts with Microsoft, the C# language itself and special features only available in Mono.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:00:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2 # The event itself featured 306 talks - so pretty hard to choose what to watch on two days. This time, not only the main tracks were awesome, but also several dev rooms featured very interesting talks by well known FOSS developers.
Saturday started with a FOSDEM birthday dance done by all attendees. The first keynote speaker Brooks Davis explained his experiences promoting open source methods at a large company.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 21:00:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1 # Four years ago I was working in Saarbrücken. From there it is a very short ride over to FOSDEM (little more than 300km). So I decided - hey, why not stay there for a weekend. I found a very nice Brussels bed and breakfast hotel called Rovignon - featuring not only comfortable rooms at reasonable prizes but also cats in the house.
Back then, I barely knew anyone at the conference.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 19:33:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM # The final schedule of FOSDEM 2010 is up: Looks like bad news - 306 interesting talks within just one weekend. Lots of interesting talks in the main track including Greg Kroah-Hartman on &amp;ldquo;Write and Submit your first Linux kernel Patch&amp;rdquo;, David Recordon from Facebook on &amp;ldquo;Scaling Facebook with OpenSource tools&amp;rdquo;, Bernard Li on &amp;ldquo;Ganglia: 10 years of monitoring clusters and grids&amp;rdquo;, Andrew Tanenbaum with his &amp;ldquo;MINIX 3: a Modular, Self-Healing POSIX-compatible Operating System&amp;rdquo; talk, Benoît Chesneau on &amp;ldquo;CouchDB!</description></item><item><title>Hadoop at Heise c't</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 13:37:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</guid><description>Hadoop at Heise c&amp;rsquo;t # &amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising&amp;gt;
Interesting for those readers speaking German: Heise published an introductory article on Hadoop in its latest issue. Have fun reading.
&amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising/&amp;gt;
Thanks to Simon for proof-reading and providing valuable input. Thanks to Thilo Fromm for the hadoop graphics (unfortunately none of them got published in its original form), the catchy title, proof-reading the text over and over again and for keeping me sane during several past and coming months.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 09:19:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">
Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010
&lt;a class="anchor" href="#apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Though the official schedule is not yet online: I will be giving an introductory talk about Apache Hadoop at next
year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM (Free and Open Source Developer European Meeting) in Brussles. This will be the 10th birthday of the
event - looking forward to a fun event, meeting other free and open source software developers from all over
Europe.&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;center>&lt;br>&lt;img src="http://fosdem.org/2010/promo/fosdem">&lt;br>&lt;/center>&lt;br>&lt;br>If you are a Apache
Hadoop developer and would like me to include some particular topic in the talk - please feel free to contact me. If
you are an Apache Hadoop user and would like to learn more on the project, please come to the talk and ask questions.
If you are an Apache Hadoop Newbie - feel free to join us.&lt;br>&lt;br>In addition there will be a NoSQL Dev Room at FOSDEM
as well. The call for presentations is up already. So if you are doing fun stuff with CouchDB, HBase and friends or are
a developer of these projects - submit a talk and join us in early-February in Brussles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</guid><description>Open Source Expo 09 # I spent last Sunday and the following Monday at Open Source Expo Karlsruhe - co-located with web-tech and php-conference organized by the Software-and-Support Verlag. Together with Simon Willnauer I ran the Lucene/Mahout booth at the expo.
So far the conference is still very small (about 400 visitors) compared to free software community events. However the focus was set to be more on professional users, accordingly several projects showed that free software can be used successfully for various business use cases.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:38:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo317/</guid><description>Open Source Expo # Title: Open Source Expo
Location: Karlsruhe
Link out: Click here
Description: There will be a booth at Open source expo introducing interested visitors to the Apache projects Lucene and Mahout. Of course we are also happy to answer any questions on the ASF in general.
Start Date: 2009-11-15
End Date: 2009-11-16</description></item><item><title>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:58:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</guid><description>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany # On October 22nd 2009 the first NoSQL Meetup Germany is going to take place in newthinking store/ Berlin: http://nosqlberlin.de
Please submit your presentation proposals until September 22nd, accepted speakers will be notified soon after.
If you would like to sponsor the event, feel free to contact us: We would be very happy to provide videos after the event and free drinks for everyone during the event.</description></item><item><title>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</guid><description>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is to take place on September 29th in newthinking store. Details are up on the web page at upcoming and will be sent out to the mailing list soon.</description></item><item><title>AMQP Erlang user group talk</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/amqp-erlang-user-group-talk9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 15:56:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/amqp-erlang-user-group-talk9/</guid><description>AMQP Erlang user group talk # Last Wednesday at the Erlang user group Berlin Matthias Radestock from the RabbitMQ project gave a talk on RabbitMQ, AMQP and messaging in general. Slides are available online.
First Matthias motivated the need for an open standard for messaging: So far, their are a few provides of middleware systems like Tibco and IBM. But those solutions are usually closed, expensive, cumbersome to handle. In short they do not fit into a world where people rely on open standards for communication, free software for development and lightweight implementations.</description></item><item><title>Lucene slides online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 10:04:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-slides-online270/</guid><description>Lucene slides online # The slides of the Lucene talk at the last Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin are available online: Lucene Slides. Especially interesting to me are the last few slides which detail both index size and machine setup:
The installation is running on two standard PCs with 2 dual-core processors (usual speed, bought in January 2008 for about 4000 Euro). They have 32GB RAM, 24 GB are used as ramdisk for the index.</description></item><item><title>Data serialization</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-serialization146/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 08:39:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-serialization146/</guid><description>Data serialization # XML, JSON and others are currently standard data exchange formats. Being human-readable but still structured enough to be easily parsable by programs is their main benefit. Problems are overhead in size and parsing time. In addition at least xml is not really as human-readable as it could be.
An alternative are binary formats. Yet those often are not platform independent (either C++ or Java or Python bindings) or are not upgradable (what if your boss comes along and wants you to add yet another field?</description></item><item><title>Scrum Table Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-berlin345/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 21:26:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-berlin345/</guid><description>Scrum Table Berlin # Last week I attended the scrum table Berlin. This time around Phillippe gave a presentation on &amp;ldquo;backlog colours&amp;rdquo;, that is types of work items tracked in the backlog.
The easiest type to track are features - that is items that generate revenue and are on the wishlist of the customer. Second type of items he sees are infrastructure items - that is, things needed to implement several features but invisible to the customer.</description></item><item><title>Open Street Map @ FSFE meetup</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-street-map-fsfe-meetup320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 20:59:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-street-map-fsfe-meetup320/</guid><description>Open Street Map @ FSFE meetup # At the last meeting of the local FSFE group here in Berlin Sabine Stengel from cartogis gave a presentation on Open Street Map. But instead of focussing on the technical side she described the legal issues and showed the broad variety of commercial projects that are possible with this type of mapping information.
It was interesting to learn of how detailed and high quality the information provided by volunteers really is.</description></item><item><title>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 18:56:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</guid><description>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg # Last week I attended a discussion meetup with Ken Schwaber in Berlin/ Kreuzberg. The event was scheduled pretty shortly
still quite a few developers and project managers from various companies in Berlin showed up.
Ken started with a brief summary of the history of Scrum: Before there was such a thing as an IT industry programming actually was a lot of fun. But somehow the creative job was turned into something people tend to suffer from pretty quickly as people tried to apply principles from manufacturing industries to software &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Back from Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 16:58:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</guid><description>Back from Zürich # I spend the last five days in Zurich. I wanted to visit the city again - and still owed one of my friends there a visit. I am really happy the weather was quite nice over the weekend. That way I could spend quite some time in town (got another one of those puzzles) and go for a hike on the Ütli mountain: I took the steep way up that had quite a lot of stairs.</description></item><item><title>DIMA @ TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dima-tu-berlin162/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 07:26:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dima-tu-berlin162/</guid><description>DIMA @ TU Berlin # On Friday, the 24th of April Prof. Volker Markl organised a Welcome Workshop at TU Berlin. The day started with an introduction by the Dekan of the faculty. First talk was given by Rudolf Bayer on the topic &amp;ldquo;From B-Trees to UB-Trees&amp;rdquo;. Second presentation was by Guy Lohman on &amp;ldquo;LEO, DB2&amp;rsquo;s Learning Optimizer&amp;rdquo;.
After the coffee break, Volker Markl gave an introduction to his selected research field, outstanding tasks and the way he is going to accomplish his goals.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</guid><description>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt # On Wednesday, the 22nd of April, about 20 people interested in Scrum gathered in the DiVino in Friedrichshain/Berlin. The event was split in two parts: In the first half we gathered topics participants were interested in, put priorities next the them and discussed the most highly ranked topic: &amp;ldquo;Scrum in large teams, splitting large tasks across teams.&amp;quot;
The basic take home messages of the discussion:</description></item><item><title>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 08:54:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</guid><description>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK # A few weeks after the Hadoop User Group UK is over, there are quite a few postings on the event online. I will try to keep this page updated if there are any further reviews. The one I found so far:
http://huguk.org/2009/04/huguk-2-wrap-up.html - the wrap-up of the event itself.
http://blog.oskarsson.nu/2009_04_01_archive.html - a short summary by the organiser - Thanks again for a great event.</description></item><item><title>GSoC: Student applications.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:57:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</guid><description>GSoC: Student applications. # Title: GSoC: Student applications closed
Link out: Click here
Description: After this date no more student applications are accepted. Internal ranking at Apache starts 7 days earlier. The ranking process finishes at 16th of April.
Date: 2009-04-03</description></item><item><title>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:54:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</guid><description>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects # Title: Students begin coding for their GSoC projects
Link out: Click here
Description: GSoC time.
Date: 2009-05-26</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:56:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3 # Friday was the last conference day. I enjoyed the Apache pioneers panel with a brief history of the Apache Software Foundation as well as lots of stories on how people first got in contact with the ASF.
After lunch I went to the testing and cloud session. I enjoyed the talk on continuum and its uses by Wendy Smoak. She gave a basic overview of why one would want a CI system and provided a brief introduction to continuum.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:42:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2 # Thursday morning started with an interesting talk on open source collaboration tools and how they can help resolving some collaboration overhead on commercial software projects. Four goals can be reached with the help of the right tools: Sharing the project vision, tracking the current status of the project, finding places to help the project and documenting the project history as well as the reasons for decisions along the way.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 18:41:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1 # The past week members, committers and users of Apache software projects gathered in Amsterdam for another Apache Con EU
and to celebrate the 10th birthday of the ASF. One week dedicated to the development and use of Free Software and the Apache Way.
Monday was BarCamp day for me, the first BarCamp I ever attended. Unfortunately not all participants proposed talks. So some of the atmosphere of an unconference was missing.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Camp Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 13:29:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</guid><description>Cloud Camp Berlin # Title: Cloud Camp Berlin
Link out: Click here
Date: 2009-04-30&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>FSFE booth at the Chemnitzer Linux Tage</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-booth-at-the-chemnitzer-linux-tage199/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 08:30:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-booth-at-the-chemnitzer-linux-tage199/</guid><description>FSFE booth at the Chemnitzer Linux Tage # This year for the 11th time the &amp;ldquo;Linux Tage&amp;rdquo; were organized at the university of Chemnitz. Each year in March this means two days devoted to the topic of open and free software. It means an event that is very well organized by a pretty professional team of volunteers.
For the third time the FSFE had its booth at the event - this time run by Rainer Kersten, Uwe Zemisch and me.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Roundtable Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-roundtable-berlin344/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:51:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-roundtable-berlin344/</guid><description>Scrum Roundtable Berlin # Title: Scrum Roundtable Berlin
Location: DiVino Restaurant, Grünberger Str. 69, Friedrichshain
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Start Time: 18:00
Date: 2009-04-22
The next Scrum Roundtable is scheduled already. Thoralf, will present his speech from the Orlando ScrumGathering
Agile Creation of Multi-Product Solutions
Motivation for Network Solutions and their Agilility
Scaling Single Product Creation
Product Solutions using Scrum
Customizing Projects
Outlook
Please let Marion know if you are coming to be able to organise the space.</description></item><item><title>Erlang User Group - Scala</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/erlang-user-group-scala169/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 12:25:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/erlang-user-group-scala169/</guid><description>Erlang User Group - Scala # What: Scala Presentation by Stefan Plantikow.
Where: Cockpit of the Box119 http://boxhagener119.de/ (Ring at UPSTREAM)
When: Wednesday, 11.03.2009, 8:00 p.m. Yesterday the Erlounge, organised by Jan Lehnardt, took place in the Cockpit of Box119 in Berlin. Topic of the evening was an introduction to Scala.
Scala is a functional language that compiles to Java Bytecode and runs on the JVM. It tries to combine the best from two worlds: Object oriented languages and functional programming.</description></item><item><title>FSFE Meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-meetup-berlin201/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 23:07:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-meetup-berlin201/</guid><description>FSFE Meetup Berlin # Title: FSFE Meetup Berlin
Location: newthinking store
Start Time: 19:00
Date: 2009-03-12
The FSFE Berlin group is going to meet next Thursday. Topics to discuss at the next Get Together are
Document Freedom Day activities.
This year is the year of elections in Germany. How do we get the topic of Free Software into the discussion?
Feel free to visit the wiki, drop by and take part in the discussions.</description></item></channel></rss>