<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Berlin Buzzwords on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Berlin-Buzzwords/</link><description>Recent content in Berlin Buzzwords on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 19:37:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Berlin-Buzzwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How hard can it be - organising a conference</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-hard-can-it-be-organising-a-conference/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 19:37:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-hard-can-it-be-organising-a-conference/</guid><description>How hard can it be - organising a conference # Setup a CfP, select a few talks, publish a schedule, book a venue, sell a few tickets - have fun: Essentially all it takes to organise a conference, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? In theory maybe - in practice - not so much. Without scaring you away from running your own here&amp;rsquo;s my experience with setting up Berlin Buzzwords (after two years of running the Berlin Hadoop Get Together, putting up a NoSQL half day meetup).</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Associated Events</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-associated-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 17:00:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-associated-events/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Associated Events # Back in 2011 I had a weird idea: Berlin Buzzwords as a core event kicks off on Sunday evening with a Barcamp but closes on Tuesday evening. There&amp;rsquo;s way too little time to meet with all the interesting people. On the other hand the organising team really was all tired on Tuesday evening, so just adding another day at the end wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an option.</description></item><item><title>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 11:21:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-to-get-your-submission-accepted-at-berlin-buzzwords236/</guid><description>How to get your submission accepted at Berlin Buzzwords # Disclaimer: Intentionally posting on my private blog - these are my own criteria, not general advice from the review committee.
Berlin Buzzwords is in it&amp;rsquo;s fourth year. Probably the most tedious task of all is having to select talks to make it into the final schedule. With roughly 120 submissions and roughly 30 slots to fill the result is that three quarters of all submissions have to be rejected.</description></item><item><title>Preparation done - clock is ticking</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preparation-done-clock-is-ticking327/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 21:24:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preparation-done-clock-is-ticking327/</guid><description>Preparation done - clock is ticking # The clock is ticking - only one more weekend to go before Berlin Buzzwords opens its doors for the main conference (check out the Wiki for the Sunday evening Barcamp and the Sunday Movie Hackday). Looking forward to an amazing week with awesome speakers and great attendees.
One word of warning before: Given all the buzz around that conference as of now until mid-next week I won&amp;rsquo;t take any major decisions, most likely I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to follow through with any additional organisation, probably I won&amp;rsquo;t remember everyone I meet on-site.</description></item><item><title>Presentation shortening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/presentation-shortening328/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 20:23:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/presentation-shortening328/</guid><description>Presentation shortening # In an effort to make more room for more talks in our schedule for this year&amp;rsquo;s Berlin Buzzwords we&amp;rsquo;ve asked quite a few people to shorten their presentation from 40min down to 20min. The thought behind it is to not only give more people a chance to talk on their work but also have those shorter talks focused down to the absolute essential information for people to learn.</description></item><item><title>Traveling to Berlin in June? Update: No airport changes!</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/traveling-to-berlin-in-june-note-the-airport-changes413/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 09:23:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/traveling-to-berlin-in-june-note-the-airport-changes413/</guid><description>Traveling to Berlin in June? Update: No airport changes! # Update: Seems like there won&amp;rsquo;t be any airport changes for Berlin Buzzwords: German article at Tagesspiegel on postponing airport opening.
If you are planning to travel to Berlin in June – e.g. to attend Berlin Buzzwords – note that there is a major change to airports happening on June 2nd:
Saturday, June 2nd will be the last day, both Schönefeld Airport (SXF) as well as Tegel Airport (TXL) are going to be open.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 10:29:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now # As of beginning of last week the Berlin Buzzwords schedule is online. The Program Committee has completed reviewing all submissions and set up the schedule containing a great lineup of speakers for this years Berlin Buzzwords program. Among the speakers we have Leslie Hawthorn (Red Hat), Alex Lloyd (Google), Michael Busch (Twitter) as well as Nicolas Spiegelberg (Facebook). Checkout our program in the online schedule.</description></item><item><title>Music in Berlin early June</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/music-in-berlin-early-june289/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 18:20:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/music-in-berlin-early-june289/</guid><description>Music in Berlin early June # A little bit of inspiration on what to do the weekend before and after Buzzwords in Berlin:
Ballet in June at the Staatsballett Berlin
Concerts in June at &amp;lt;a href=&amp;ldquo; http://www.konzerthaus.de/programm/?datetimeAnf=1338501600&amp;datetimeEnd=1341093600&amp;id_language=1&amp;month=6&amp;year=2012"
Konzerthaus Berlin
Opera in June at Staatsoper Berlin
Opera in June at Deutsche Oper Berlin
Concerts in June at the Philharmoniker Berlin
Opera in June at Komische Oper Berlin
Theater (German-only, sorry, but open-air) at Hexenkessel Hoftheater</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords scheduling - behind the scenes</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-scheduling-behind-the-scenes118/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 21:23:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-scheduling-behind-the-scenes118/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords scheduling - behind the scenes # Since roughly a week the Berlin Buzzwords schedule is available online. Tickets are still available at the regular rate - make sure to book your ticket now - you&amp;rsquo;ve got another three weeks to purchase tickets at the regular rate, last minute rate will up the prize by another 100 Euros starting May 20th.
I thought it might be interesting to share some background on how Berlin Buzzwords scheduling worked out this year.</description></item><item><title>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</guid><description>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of several people who are not quite sure yet whether they should visit Berlin Buzzwords or not - in particular when having to travel far and cross 9 time zones to attend. My general recommendation is to plan to spend some more days in Europe. The conference is conveniently scheduled on Monday and Tuesday which gives you one weekend before to explore the city and the whole week afterwards to go and see more either in the city or around.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords 2012 - Call for submissions</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2012-call-for-submissions116/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 19:15:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2012-call-for-submissions116/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords 2012 - Call for submissions # The countdown started several weeks ago - finally in the past days the date for Berlin Buzzwords was announced, the call for submissions published. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see that the first talk is in already. Looking forward to yours.
Compared to last year there are two changes: Submissions are no longer evaluated by Jan, Simon and myself only. Due to the large number of talks submitted last year we reached out for help to be able to split the task of reviewing talks.</description></item><item><title>Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords - one more week to go</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords-one-more-week-to-go133/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 20:24:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords-one-more-week-to-go133/</guid><description>Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords - one more week to go # As a little reminder: the Call for presentations of Berlin Buzzwords will close next week on Tuesday, March 1st. Submissions on scalable search, data storage and analysis are all welcome. We are looking for presentations on the core technologies such as Apache Hadoop, CouchDB, Lucene, Redis, Voldemort but also talks on interesting use cases and system architectures.</description></item><item><title>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</guid><description>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale # This is to announce the Berlin Buzzwords 2011. The second edition of the successful conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany,
taking place in Berlin.
Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - Search, Store, Scale
6/7 June 2011
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Velocity update</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/velocity-update418/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 18:34:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/velocity-update418/</guid><description>Velocity update # After Berlin Buzzwords is over now, I thought it might be time to update a formerly published velocity graph. If you have been following this blog during the past few months you may know already, that we are using Scrum @ Home for several months already. I even published results of a Scrum Nokia test earlier this year.
Today I created another one of these nice velocity charts.</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:54:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</guid><description>Apache Dinner June 2010 # After Berlin Buzzwords was over yesterday - and as there is an svn conference in the city that starts tomorrow, we thought we could easily put together a smallish Apache Dinner for tonight. So Torsten mailed a few people, booked some space at Heinz Minki in Kreuzberg. We announced it at the end of the conference and invited people to join us.
So after a beautiful day out I spent the evening with a bunch of Apache related guys and girls having drinks and great pizza: We had several svn committers, Greg Stein met us there - he arrived today for the svn conference.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 08:52:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</guid><description>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords # Staying in town after Berlin Buzzwords? Interested in meeting with the Apache folks here? Torsten Curdt kindly organises an Apache Dinner on Wednesday evening after Berlin Buzzwords. If you would like to participate, contact Torsten for details on when and where it will take place.
Though named Apache dinner, there is no need to be Apache committer or even member to participate: Being generally interested in Apache projects and in meeting the guys behind the project is totally sufficient.</description></item><item><title>Scaling user groups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 19:32:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scaling-user-groups336/</guid><description>Scaling user groups # A few hours ago, Jan Lehnardt posted a link on How to organise a nerd conference - joking that this is how we planned Berlin Buzzwords. Well, it is not exactly that easy - however the comic actually is not so far from the truth either:
About two years ago, after having started Apache Mahout together with Grant Ingersoll, Karl Wettin and others, several Apache Hadoop user groups, meetups and get togethers started to pop up all around the world.</description></item><item><title>Going to Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 08:46:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</guid><description>Going to Berlin Buzzwords # Meet me in two weeks at Berlin Buzzwords. As you may have noticed, together with Simon Willnauer, Jan Lehnardt and newthinking communications I am organising Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scalable search, data analysis and storage.
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://berlinbuzzwords.de/sites/berlinbuzzwords.de/files/buzzwords_banner.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to Berlin Buzzwords
the conference on searching, processing and storing data.&amp;rdquo;/&amp;gt;
There are a few regular tickets left, so don&amp;rsquo;t wait too long to register.</description></item><item><title>Solving puzzles</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solving-puzzles377/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 16:44:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solving-puzzles377/</guid><description>Solving puzzles # Like most software developers I like tasks that involve solving more or less complex problems analytically. Most developers I know love puzzles - either those that involve dis-entangling metal rings, or those involving putting wooden pieces back into order, or even solving Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube:
Working on the schedule for Berlin Buzzwords, I noticed that coming up with a good schedule actually has a lot more in common with solving puzzles that one is usually aware of: First of all talks on similar or related topics should not take place at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 15:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-2010-scalability-conference-june-7th-8th-in-berlin115/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Scalability conference June 7th/ 8th in Berlin # The Berlin Buzzwords schedule was published a few days ago. There are tracks specific to the three tags search, store and scale. We have a fantastic mixture of developers and users of open source software projects that make scaling data processing today possible.
There is Steve Loughran, Aaron Kimball and Stefan Groschupf from the Apache Hadoop community. We have Grant Ingersoll, Robert Muir and the &amp;ldquo;Generics Policeman&amp;rdquo; Uwe Schindler from the Lucene community.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 14:55:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-end-of-cfp-drawing-closer113/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - End of CfP drawing closer # One week to go for submitting a talk on your favourite NoSQL topic, your favourite search application or your most interesting data analysis task: The call for presentations for Berlin Buzzwords ends on April 17th, that is Sunday next week.
Shortly after the last talk was submitted we will start announcing speakers - final list of speakers is to be expected by the start of May, final schedule will be published shortly after that.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2010 15:02:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-early-bird-registration112/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - Early bird registration # I would like to invite everyone interested in data storage, analysis and search to join us for two days on June 7/8th in Berlin for Berlin Buzzwords - an in-depth, technical, developer-focused conference located in the heart of Europe. Presentations will range from beginner friendly introductions on the hot data analysis topics up to in-depth technical presentations of scalable architectures.
Our intention is to bring together users and developers of data storage, analysis and search projects.</description></item><item><title>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 15:09:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/call-for-presentations-berlin-buzzwords132/</guid><description>Call for presentations - Berlin Buzzwords # Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2010 - Search, Store, Scale
7/8 June 2010
This is to announce the opening of the Berlin Buzzwords 2010 call for presentations. Berlin Buzzwords is the first conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany, taking place in Berlin.
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 18:34:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/early-bird-registration-for-berlin-buzzwords-is-open166/</guid><description>Early bird registration for Berlin Buzzwords on June 7th/8th open # Silently registration was opened in the past days for Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scaling search, data processing and storage taking place on June 7th/8th in Berlin/ Germany. First 100 tickets will be sold for 250 Euros + tax. Registration is possible at later dates as well, however expect prizes to rise shortly before the conference starts.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010 # As announced at FOSDEM: Early June (currently scheduled for 7th/8th) a conference on the topics scalable search, storage and processing will take place in Kalkscheune/Berlin. The conference is co-organised by newthinking store, Jan Lehnardt, Simon Willnauer, Thilo Fromm, and Isabel Drost.
The focus will be on NoSQL databases like CouchDB, Jackrabbit, MongoDB, HBase. Search tracks will cover topics like Lucene, Solr, katta and others.</description></item></channel></rss>