<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cascalog on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Cascalog/</link><description>Recent content in Cascalog on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:49:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Cascalog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Video: Stefan H端bner on Cascalog</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-stefan-hubner-on-cascalog428/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 20:49:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-stefan-hubner-on-cascalog428/</guid><description>Video: Stefan H端bner on Cascalog # Stefan H端bner: "Introducing Cascalog: Functional Data Processing for Hadoop" from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:30:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012 # Despite beautiful summer weather roughly 50 people gathered at ImmobilienScout24 for the August 2012 edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together (Thanks again for hosting the event and sponsoring drinks and pizza to ImmoScout as well as to David Obermann for organising the meetup.
Today there were three talks: In the first presentation Dragan Milosevic (also known from his talk at the Hadoop GetTogether and his presentation at Berlin Buzzwords) provided more insight as to how Zanox is managing their internal RPC protocols in particular when it comes to versioning and upgrading protocol versions.</description></item><item><title>Note to self: Clojure with Vim and Maven</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/note-to-self-clojure-with-vim-and-maven298/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 20:07:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/note-to-self-clojure-with-vim-and-maven298/</guid><description>Note to self: Clojure with Vim and Maven # Steps to get a somewhat working Clojure environment with vim:
Install the current vimclojure plugin.
Get and install a nailgun client.
Add vimclojure to your clojure project pom.xml.
Start the nailgun server from within your maven project with mvn clojure:nailgun with the maven clojure plugin.
Finally start vim, open your favourite clojure file - you can open a REPL with \sr, when in a function definition you can evaluate that with \et - see also tamining vim clojure</description></item><item><title>Clojure Berlin - March 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-berlin-march-2012139/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 22:37:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/clojure-berlin-march-2012139/</guid><description>Clojure Berlin - March 2012 # In today&amp;rsquo;s Clojure meetup Stefan H端bner gave an introduction to Cascalog - a Clojure library based on Cascading for large scale data processing on Apache Hadoop without hassle.
After a brief overview of what he is using the tool for to do log processing at his day job for http://maps.nokia.com Stefan went into some more detail on why he chose Cascalog over other project that provide abstraction layers on top of Hadoop&amp;rsquo;s plain map/reduce library: Both Pig and Hive provide easy to learn SQL-like languages to quickly write analysis jobs.</description></item></channel></rss>