<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Free Software on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Free-Software/</link><description>Recent content in Free Software on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:43:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Free-Software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:43:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</guid><description>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05 # On MySQL
Second day at FOSDEM for me started with the MySQL dev room. One thing that made me smile was in the MySQL new features talk: The speaker announced support for “NoSQL interfaces” to MySQL. That is kind of fun in two dimensions: A) What he really means is support for the memcached interface. Given the vast number of different interfaces to databases today, announcing anything as “supports NoSQL interfaces” sounds kind of silly.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Search meetup Berlin – January 2013</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin-january-2013168/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 18:34:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin-january-2013168/</guid><description>Elastic Search meetup Berlin – January 2013 # The first meetup this year I went to started with a large bag of good news for Elastic Search users. In the offices of Sys Eleven (thanks for hosting) the meetup started at 7p.m. last Tuesday. Simon Willnauer gave an overview of what to expect of the upcoming major release of Elastic Search:
For all 0.20.x version ES features a shard allocator version that is ignorant of which index shards belong to, machine properties, usage patterns.</description></item><item><title>Thanks for all the help</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/thanks-for-all-the-help406/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 11:24:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/thanks-for-all-the-help406/</guid><description>Thanks for all the help # This year was a blast: It started with the ever great FOSDEM in Brussels (see you there in 2013?), an invitation to GeeCon in Poznan (if you ever get an invitation to speak there - do accept, the organisers do an amazing job at that event). In summer we had Berlin Buzzwords in Berlin for the third time with 700 attendees (to retain the community feel to the conference we decided to limit tickets in 2013, so make sure you get your&amp;rsquo;s early).</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 08:04:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</guid><description>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly # My second day started with a talk on how to fail projects fast and rapidly. There are a few tricks to do that that relate to different aspects of your project. Lets take a look at each of them in turn.
The first measures to take to fail a project are organisational really: Refer to developers as resources – that will demotivate them and express that they are replaceable instead of being valuable human beings.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - TDD and it's influence on software design</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-tdd-and-its-influence-on-software-design207/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-tdd-and-its-influence-on-software-design207/</guid><description>GeeCon - TDD and it&amp;rsquo;s influence on software design # The second talk I went to on the first day was on the influence of TDD on software design. Keith Braithwaite did a really great job of first introducing the concept of cyclomatic complexity and than showing at the example of Hudson as well as many other open source Java projects that the average and mean cyclomatic complexity of all those projects actually is pretty close to one and when plotted for all methods pretty much follows a power law distribution.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - Randomized testing</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-randomized-testing205/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 08:02:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-randomized-testing205/</guid><description>GeeCon - Randomized testing # I arrived late during lunch time on Thursday for GeeCon – however just in time to listen to one of the most interesting talks when it comes to testing. Did you ever have the issue of writing code that runs well in your development environment but crashes as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s rolled out at customers only to find out that their Locale setting was causing the issues?</description></item><item><title>Happy Valentine</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/happy-valentine234/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 06:24:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/happy-valentine234/</guid><description>Happy Valentine # Free Software developers can be very critical: Every single line of code gets scrutinized, every design is reviewed by several often opinionated people. Even the way communities are supposed to work sometimes gets restricted. Sometimes a simple Thank You can make all the difference for any contributor or committer.
FSFE proposed a really nice campaign: Celebrate the &amp;ldquo;I love Free Software&amp;rdquo; - Day on February 14th. In the hope that some of the readers of this blog actively develop or contribute to free software projects - this is a thank you for you!</description></item><item><title>February 14th: "I love free software day"</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-14th-i-love-free-software-day170/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 21:07:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-14th-i-love-free-software-day170/</guid><description>February 14th: &amp;ldquo;I love free software day&amp;rdquo; # This year FSFE is once again running their I love free software campaign on February 14th: The goal they put up is to have more love reports, hugs and Thank You messages sent out than bug reports filed against projects.
They have put online a few ideas on what to do that day. I&amp;rsquo;d like to add one additional option: If you are using any free software and you feel the urgent need to file a bug report on that day, use the opportunity to submit a patch as well: Make sure to not only describe what is going wrong but add a patch that contains a test to show the issue and a code modification that fixes the issue, is compatible with the project&amp;rsquo;s coding guidelines, doesn&amp;rsquo;t break anything else in the project.</description></item><item><title>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 13:49:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/see-you-in-vancouver-at-apache-con-na-2011363/</guid><description>See you in Vancouver at Apache Con NA 2011 # Mid November Apache hosts its famous yearly conference - this time in Vancouver/Canada. They kindly accepted my presentations on Apache Mahout for intelligent data analysis (mostly focused on introducing the project to new comers and showing what happened within the project in the past year - if you have any wish concerning topics you would like to see covered in particular, please let me know) as well as a more committer focused one on Talking people into creating patches (with the goal of highlighting some of the issues new-comers to free software projects that want to contribute run into and initiating a discussion on what helps to convince them to keep up the momentum and over come and obstacles).</description></item><item><title>Are devs contributing to OSS happier?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 20:18:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</guid><description>Are devs contributing to OSS happier? # When talking to fellow developers or meeting with students it happens from time to time that I get the question of why on earth I spent my freetime working on an open source project? Why do I spend weekends at developers&amp;rsquo; conferences like FOSDEM? Why do spent afternoons organising meetups? Why is it that I am reviewing and writing code after work for free?</description></item><item><title>Apprenticeship patterns (O'Reilly)</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apprenticeship-patterns-oreilly106/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 08:17:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apprenticeship-patterns-oreilly106/</guid><description>Apprenticeship patterns (O&amp;rsquo;Reilly) # A few days ago I finished reading the book &amp;ldquo;Apprenticeship Patterns&amp;rdquo; - Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman, by
Dave Hoover, Adewale Oshineye. The book is addressed to readers who have the goal of becoming great software devleopers.
One naive question one could ask is why there is a need for such a book at all? Students are trained in computer science at university, then enter some IT departement and simply learn from their peers.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner DUS</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 19:10:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</guid><description>Apache Dinner DUS # the evening after FrOSCon - that is on August 22nd 2010 at 7:30p.m. CEST - a combined &amp;ldquo;FSFE Fellowship meetup/ Apache dinner*&amp;rdquo; takes place in Tigges in Düsseldorf (Brunnenstraße 1, at Bilker S-Bahnhof). Given it doesn&amp;rsquo;t rain, we&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting outside.
Would be great to meet you there for tasty food, interesting discussions on Apache in general, as well as projects like Lucene, Hadoop or Tomcat in particular.</description></item><item><title>Some statistics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-statistics379/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 20:03:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-statistics379/</guid><description>Some statistics # Various research projects focus on learning more on how open source communities work:
What makes people commit themselves to such projects?
How much involvement from various companies is there?
Do people contribute during working hours or in their spare time?
Who are the most active contributors in terms of individuals and in terms of companies?
When asked to fill out surveys, especially in cases where that happens for the n-th time with n being larger than say 5, software developers usually are not very likely to fill out these questionairs.</description></item><item><title>Part 1: Travelling minds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:00:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</guid><description>Part 1: Travelling minds # In the last post I promised to share some more information on techniques I came across and found useful under an increasing work load. Instead of taking a close look at my professional calendar I decided to use my private one as an example - first because spare time is even more precious then working hours, simply because there is so few of it and secondly because I am free to publicly scrutinize not only the methods for keeping it in good shape but also the entries in it.</description></item><item><title>Series: Getting things done</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 07:07:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</guid><description>Series: Getting things done # Probably not too unusual for people working on free software mostly (though no longer exclusively) in their spare time, the number of items that appear in my private calendar have increased steadily in the past months and years:
Every three months I am organising the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin.
I have been asked (and accepted the offer) to publish articles on Hadoop and Lucene in magazines.</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scalability335/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 11:17:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scalability335/</guid><description>Scalability # For Berlin Buzzwords we concentrated pretty heavily on scalable systems and architectures: We had talks on Hadoop for scaling data analysis; HBase, Cassandra and Hypertable for scaling data storage; Lucene and Solr for scaling search.
A recurring pattern was people telling success stories involving project that either involve large amounts of data or growing user numbers. Of course the whole topic of scalability is extremely interesting for ambitious developers: Who would not be happy to solve internet-scale problems, have petabytes of data at his fingertips or tell others that their &amp;ldquo;other computer is a data center&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Teaching Free Software Development</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 12:55:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</guid><description>Teaching Free Software Development # In Summer last year I was invited to give a presentation on Apache Mahout at TU Berlin. After the talk was over some of the research group members asked me to design and give a course on scalable machine learning with open source software during the winter semester.
The project attracted four to five students - not very many - but then again it is a course people can take voluntarily.</description></item><item><title>Linus Torwalds on the Linux kernel community</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/linus-torwalds-on-the-linux-kernel-community264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 18:10:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/linus-torwalds-on-the-linux-kernel-community264/</guid><description>Linus Torwalds on the Linux kernel community # A few days ago, Linus send a very interesting mail on why he considers C the programming language that is most suitable for the Linux kernel. Despite the language specific arguments, the text contains quite a few insights on how the Linux kernel community works and communicates that might be interesting to non-kernel-hackers as well:
People working for free still doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it&amp;rsquo;s fine</description></item><item><title>Getting a Ubuntu Laptop setup for my Mum</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-a-ubuntu-laptop-setup-for-my-mum210/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 19:15:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-a-ubuntu-laptop-setup-for-my-mum210/</guid><description>Getting a Ubuntu Laptop setup for my Mum # With DSL contracts getting ever cheaper in recent years in Germany – even outside larger cities – my mom decided to get a faster internet connection (compared to the former 56k modem) including a telephone landline flatrate.
As sitting in the garden while surfing the internet is way cooler than only having a dedicated computer in an office we decided to get a notebook while at it.</description></item><item><title>Chemnitzer Linuxtage</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chemnitzer-linuxtage136/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 12:32:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/chemnitzer-linuxtage136/</guid><description>Chemnitzer Linuxtage # Title: Chemnitzer Linuxtage
Location: Chemnitz
Link out: Click here
Start Date: 2010-03-13
End Date: 2010-03-14
Next week the Chemnither Linuxtage take place in - well - Chemnitz. It is the second largest Linux event after Linuxtag Berlin. However only obvious for speakers and exhibitors: It is one of those events that are known for its fantastic organisation. Nearly no problems, be it WiFi, admission to the exhibitors area, food or any help in general.</description></item><item><title>FSFE Happy Valentine</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-happy-valentine200/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 07:05:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-happy-valentine200/</guid><description>FSFE Happy Valentine # Today I got woken up with a friendly hug and roses waiting for me:
I do not really care about presents for sort-of-artificial celebration days like valentines day. However, FSFE had a very nice idea: The proposal was to use valentines day to show your love for free software. The website proposed to e.g. hug a free software developer, to make a gift to a team of free software developers:</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 21:02:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3 # Sunday started in Janson with Andrian Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s talk on RepRap machines, that is devices that can be used as manufacturing devices and are able to replicate themselves. After that I went over to the Mono dev room to listen to Miguel de Icaza on Mono Edge. A great talk on the history of Mono, the way the community interacts with Microsoft, the C# language itself and special features only available in Mono.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:00:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2 # The event itself featured 306 talks - so pretty hard to choose what to watch on two days. This time, not only the main tracks were awesome, but also several dev rooms featured very interesting talks by well known FOSS developers.
Saturday started with a FOSDEM birthday dance done by all attendees. The first keynote speaker Brooks Davis explained his experiences promoting open source methods at a large company.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 21:00:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1 # Four years ago I was working in Saarbrücken. From there it is a very short ride over to FOSDEM (little more than 300km). So I decided - hey, why not stay there for a weekend. I found a very nice Brussels bed and breakfast hotel called Rovignon - featuring not only comfortable rooms at reasonable prizes but also cats in the house.
Back then, I barely knew anyone at the conference.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 19:33:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-10-years-fosdem184/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - 10 years FOSDEM # The final schedule of FOSDEM 2010 is up: Looks like bad news - 306 interesting talks within just one weekend. Lots of interesting talks in the main track including Greg Kroah-Hartman on &amp;ldquo;Write and Submit your first Linux kernel Patch&amp;rdquo;, David Recordon from Facebook on &amp;ldquo;Scaling Facebook with OpenSource tools&amp;rdquo;, Bernard Li on &amp;ldquo;Ganglia: 10 years of monitoring clusters and grids&amp;rdquo;, Andrew Tanenbaum with his &amp;ldquo;MINIX 3: a Modular, Self-Healing POSIX-compatible Operating System&amp;rdquo; talk, Benoît Chesneau on &amp;ldquo;CouchDB!</description></item><item><title>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 09:09:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</guid><description>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers # On Lucid Imaginations Blog Jay Hill published a great article on The seven deadly sins of solr. Basically it is a collection of his experiences &amp;ldquo;analyzing and evaluating a great many instances of Solr implementations, running in some of the largest Fortune 500 companies&amp;rdquo;. It is a collection of common mistakes, mis-configurations and pitfalls in Solr installations in production use.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 09:19:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">
Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010
&lt;a class="anchor" href="#apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Though the official schedule is not yet online: I will be giving an introductory talk about Apache Hadoop at next
year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM (Free and Open Source Developer European Meeting) in Brussles. This will be the 10th birthday of the
event - looking forward to a fun event, meeting other free and open source software developers from all over
Europe.&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;center>&lt;br>&lt;img src="http://fosdem.org/2010/promo/fosdem">&lt;br>&lt;/center>&lt;br>&lt;br>If you are a Apache
Hadoop developer and would like me to include some particular topic in the talk - please feel free to contact me. If
you are an Apache Hadoop user and would like to learn more on the project, please come to the talk and ask questions.
If you are an Apache Hadoop Newbie - feel free to join us.&lt;br>&lt;br>In addition there will be a NoSQL Dev Room at FOSDEM
as well. The call for presentations is up already. So if you are doing fun stuff with CouchDB, HBase and friends or are
a developer of these projects - submit a talk and join us in early-February in Brussles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 22:07:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/sesat-moving-from-fast-to-solr369/</guid><description>Sesat - moving from FAST to Solr # The article was first published on Sesat Weblog. As the whole site went down several days ago, I retrieved the content from the Google cache and posted it here for perservation.
Update: Original site is up again.</description></item><item><title>Moving from Fast to Solr</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:34:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-from-fast-to-solr286/</guid><description>Moving from Fast to Solr # Sesat has published a nice in-depth report on why to move from Fast to Solr. The article also includes a description of the steps taken to move over as well as several statistics:
http://sesat.no/moving-from-fast-to-solr-review.html
On a related topic, the following article details, where Apple is using Lucene/Solr to power it&amp;rsquo;s search. Spoiler: Look at Spotlight, their desktop search, as well as on the iTunes search with about 800 QPS.</description></item><item><title>Fellow now</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fellow-now173/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:45:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fellow-now173/</guid><description>Fellow now # After two years volunteering as booth staff for the FSFE at the Chemnitzer Linuxtage explaining the advantages of becoming a FSFE fellow I am a fellow myself for two days ;)
I first got in contact with the FSFE through Fernanda Weiden during my time in Zürich in 2006. In the meantime I have learned more and more about the political activities of FSFE: Mostly during the local Berlin meetups in newthinking store and as a booth member in Chemnitz.</description></item><item><title>Flying back home from Cologne</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:40:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</guid><description>Flying back home from Cologne # Last weekend FrOSCon took place in Sankt Augustin, near Cologne. FrOSCon is organized on a yearly basis at the university of applied sciences in Sankt Augustin. It is a volunteer driven event with the goal of bringing developers and users of free software projects together. This year, the conference featured 5 tracks, two examples being cloud computing and the Java track.
Unfortunately this year the conference started with a little surprise for me and my boyfriend: Being both speakers, we had booked a room in Hotel Regina via the conference committee.</description></item><item><title>AMQP Erlang user group talk</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/amqp-erlang-user-group-talk9/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 15:56:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/amqp-erlang-user-group-talk9/</guid><description>AMQP Erlang user group talk # Last Wednesday at the Erlang user group Berlin Matthias Radestock from the RabbitMQ project gave a talk on RabbitMQ, AMQP and messaging in general. Slides are available online.
First Matthias motivated the need for an open standard for messaging: So far, their are a few provides of middleware systems like Tibco and IBM. But those solutions are usually closed, expensive, cumbersome to handle. In short they do not fit into a world where people rely on open standards for communication, free software for development and lightweight implementations.</description></item><item><title>Solr at AOL</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 13:06:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</guid><description>Solr at AOL # Grant Ingersoll has posted a very interesting interview with Ian Holsman on Solr at Relegance, now AOL. It describes the business side of the decission to switch to an open source solution, provides some inside on the size of the installation and details which technological reasons have driven the decission to switch from a proprietary implementation to Solr:
http://www.lucidimagination.com/Community/Hear-from-the-Experts/Podcasts-and-Videos/Interview-Ian-Holsman-Relegence&amp;lt;/ a&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Large Scalability - Papers and implementations</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/large-scalability-papers-and-implementations259/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 12:08:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/large-scalability-papers-and-implementations259/</guid><description>Large Scalability - Papers and implementations # In recent years the Googles and Amazons on this world have released papers on how to scale computing and processing to terrabytes of data. These publications have led to the implementation of various open source projects that benefit from that knowledge. However mapping the various open source projects to the original papers and assigning tasks that these projects solve is not always easy.</description></item><item><title>Open Street Map @ FSFE meetup</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-street-map-fsfe-meetup320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 20:59:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-street-map-fsfe-meetup320/</guid><description>Open Street Map @ FSFE meetup # At the last meeting of the local FSFE group here in Berlin Sabine Stengel from cartogis gave a presentation on Open Street Map. But instead of focussing on the technical side she described the legal issues and showed the broad variety of commercial projects that are possible with this type of mapping information.
It was interesting to learn of how detailed and high quality the information provided by volunteers really is.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Development is good for you</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-development-is-good-for-you316/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 09:08:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-development-is-good-for-you316/</guid><description>Open Source Development is good for you # GSoC (Google summer of code) - one of the open source programs of Google - has started again in 2009. Students come to work for open source projects during the summer and on success are paid by Google a fair amount of money.
This program is an ideal oportunity for students to get into open source projects: You get a mentor, you have pre-defined task to work on with a goal you set yourself.</description></item><item><title>Tomcat Tuesday talk</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 09:07:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</guid><description>Tomcat Tuesday talk # Since several months at neofonie we have a talk given by external or internal developers on various subjects each Tuesday. Usually these presentations are a nice way to get an overview of new emerging technologies, to get an overview of current conference topics or to gain insight into interesting internal projects.
This week we had Apache Tomcat Committer and PMC Peter Rossbach here at neofonie to talk about the Tomcat architecture and Tomcat clustering solutions.</description></item><item><title>Back from Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 16:58:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</guid><description>Back from Zürich # I spend the last five days in Zurich. I wanted to visit the city again - and still owed one of my friends there a visit. I am really happy the weather was quite nice over the weekend. That way I could spend quite some time in town (got another one of those puzzles) and go for a hike on the Ütli mountain: I took the steep way up that had quite a lot of stairs.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 15:11:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</guid><description>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1 # This morning I received Grant&amp;rsquo;s release mail of Apache Mahout. I am really happy that after little more than one year we now have our first release out there to test and scrutinate by anyone interested in the project. Thanks to all the committers who have helped make this possible. A special thanks to Grant Ingersoll for putting so much time into getting many release issues out of the way as well as to those who reviewed the release candidates and all the major and minor problems.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:42:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2 # Thursday morning started with an interesting talk on open source collaboration tools and how they can help resolving some collaboration overhead on commercial software projects. Four goals can be reached with the help of the right tools: Sharing the project vision, tracking the current status of the project, finding places to help the project and documenting the project history as well as the reasons for decisions along the way.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Camp Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 13:29:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</guid><description>Cloud Camp Berlin # Title: Cloud Camp Berlin
Link out: Click here
Date: 2009-04-30&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>FSFE booth at the Chemnitzer Linux Tage</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-booth-at-the-chemnitzer-linux-tage199/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 08:30:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-booth-at-the-chemnitzer-linux-tage199/</guid><description>FSFE booth at the Chemnitzer Linux Tage # This year for the 11th time the &amp;ldquo;Linux Tage&amp;rdquo; were organized at the university of Chemnitz. Each year in March this means two days devoted to the topic of open and free software. It means an event that is very well organized by a pretty professional team of volunteers.
For the third time the FSFE had its booth at the event - this time run by Rainer Kersten, Uwe Zemisch and me.</description></item><item><title>FSFE Meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-meetup-berlin201/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 23:07:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-meetup-berlin201/</guid><description>FSFE Meetup Berlin # Title: FSFE Meetup Berlin
Location: newthinking store
Start Time: 19:00
Date: 2009-03-12
The FSFE Berlin group is going to meet next Thursday. Topics to discuss at the next Get Together are
Document Freedom Day activities.
This year is the year of elections in Germany. How do we get the topic of Free Software into the discussion?
Feel free to visit the wiki, drop by and take part in the discussions.</description></item></channel></rss>