<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conference on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Conference/</link><description>Recent content in Conference on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 17:21:31 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSS Backstage - CfP open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 17:21:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</guid><description>FOSS Backstage - CfP open # It&amp;rsquo;s almost ten years ago that I attended my first ApacheCon EU in Amsterdam. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new to the topic of open source or free software. I attended several talks on Apache Lucene, Apache Solr, Hadoop, Tomcat, httpd (I still remember that the most impressive stories didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily come from the project members, but from downstream users. They were the ones authorized to talk publicly about what could be done with the project - and often became committers themselves down the road.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit - Day 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:35:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</guid><description>Open Source Summit - Day 3 # Open source summit Wednesday started with a keynote by members of the Banks family telling a packed room on how they approached raising a tech family. The first hurdle that Keila (the teenage daughter of the family) talked about was something I personally had never actually thought about: Communication tools like Slack that are in widespread use come with an age restriction excluding minors.</description></item><item><title>Open source summit - Day 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:58:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-2/</guid><description>Open source summit - Day 2 # Day two of Open Source summit for me started a bit slow for lack of sleep. The first talk I went to was on &amp;ldquo;Developer tools for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; by Michelle Noorali and Matt Butcher. Essentially the two of them showed two projects (Draft and Brigade to help ease development apps for Kubernetes clusters. Draft here is the tool to use for developing long running, daemon like apps.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 13:18:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</guid><description>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1 # Open Source Summit, formerly known as LinuxCon, this year took place in Prague. Drawing some 2000 attendees to the lovely Czech city, the conference focussed on all things Linux kernel, containers, community and governance. The first day started with three crowded keynotes: First one by Neha Narkhede on Keynotes Apache Kafka and the Rise of the Streaming Platform. Second one by Reuben Paul (11 years old) on how hacking today really is just childs play: The hack itself might seem like toying around (getting into the protocol of children's toys in order to make them do things without using the app that was intended to control them).</description></item><item><title>How hard can it be - organising a conference</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-hard-can-it-be-organising-a-conference/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 19:37:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-hard-can-it-be-organising-a-conference/</guid><description>How hard can it be - organising a conference # Setup a CfP, select a few talks, publish a schedule, book a venue, sell a few tickets - have fun: Essentially all it takes to organise a conference, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? In theory maybe - in practice - not so much. Without scaring you away from running your own here&amp;rsquo;s my experience with setting up Berlin Buzzwords (after two years of running the Berlin Hadoop Get Together, putting up a NoSQL half day meetup).</description></item><item><title>Apache Con US - Program up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-program-up23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:35:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-program-up23/</guid><description>Apache Con US - Program up # The final program is available for download over at http://us.apachecon.com. The schedule is packed with interesting talks on Hadoop, Lucene, Tomcat, httpd, web services, osgi. For those less tech-savvy there is a business track explaining how to best use open source software in an entreprise environment. There is also a community track explaining what makes open source projects successful.
Looking forward to seeing you in Oakland.</description></item></channel></rss>