<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Berlin on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Berlin/</link><description>Recent content in Berlin on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:38:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visiting the Bundestag</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bundestag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bundestag/</guid><description>Visiting (and speaking at) the German Bundestag # Many, many years ago, I invited Berlin Buzzwords keynote speakers to join me for lunch pre-conference. For the view – and the impact of the location – I reserved a table at the restaurant that is located atop the Reichstags-building here in Berlin. If back then anyone had told me that one day I’d get an invitation to speak as an expert in the committee for digital issues of the German Bundestag, I wouldn’t have believed a single word!</description></item><item><title>Learning German in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-english/</guid><description>Learning German in Berlin # So you have been living in Berlin for a while, maybe even for years – but you fail to speak German fluently. It may feel weird switching to German even with friends, as your English gives you many more options to speak proficiently, to be precise when talking. People around you speak better English than you speak German.
One thing to remember: While Berlin is easy to navigate speaking only English, if you stay here for more than a couple of weeks you really truly do want to start training your German language skills: Emergency information – typically first available and more detailed in German.</description></item><item><title>ABC - die Katze lief im Schnee</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/abc-die-katze-lief-im-schnee5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 20:42:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/abc-die-katze-lief-im-schnee5/</guid><description>ABC - die Katze lief im Schnee # Seen this morning in Berlin:
A little impression from what the city looked like the weeks before it turned green on Christmas:
For winter images of other years see also previous posts. Title taken from a children&amp;rsquo;s song:</description></item><item><title>Learning German</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 08:07:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</guid><description>Learning German # For some reason I got that question multiple times now from people that moved to Germany but work in companies where English is the language to use for communication - how to best learn German (in addition finding people to talk to).
When thinking about how I got started with English there were a few things that helped: As a child I got some &amp;ldquo;made for learning English&amp;rdquo; crime stories to read.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-meetup-berlin319/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 20:22:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-meetup-berlin319/</guid><description>Open Source Meetup Berlin # This evening the (to my knowledge first) Berlin Open Source Meetup took place at Prater (Bier-)garten in Berlin. There are lots of project specific meetings, a monthly Free Software meeting, quite some stuff on project management. However this was one of the rare occasions where you get Linux kernel hackers, Wikidata project members, Debian developers, security people, mobile developers as well as people writing on free software or making movies related to the topic around one table.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 23:30:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-august-201256/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - August 2012 # Despite beautiful summer weather roughly 50 people gathered at ImmobilienScout24 for the August 2012 edition of the Apache Hadoop Get Together (Thanks again for hosting the event and sponsoring drinks and pizza to ImmoScout as well as to David Obermann for organising the meetup.
Today there were three talks: In the first presentation Dragan Milosevic (also known from his talk at the Hadoop GetTogether and his presentation at Berlin Buzzwords) provided more insight as to how Zanox is managing their internal RPC protocols in particular when it comes to versioning and upgrading protocol versions.</description></item><item><title>Recsys meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-meetup-berlin330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 01:31:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-meetup-berlin330/</guid><description>Recsys meetup Berlin # Planning a meetup in Berlin: 8 people register, a table for 14 people is booked, 16+ people arrive - all of that even if no pre-defined topic or talk is announced. Seems like building recommender systems is a hot topic currently in Berlin.
Thanks to Zeno Gantner from MyMedialight for organising the event - looking forward to the next edition.</description></item><item><title>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 20:59:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-sling-and-jackrabbit-event-coming-to-berlin84/</guid><description>Apache Sling and Jackrabbit event coming to Berlin # Interested in Apache Sling and/or Apache Jackrabbit? Then you might be interested in hearing that on September 26th to 28th there will be an event in town on these two topics - mainly organised by Adobe, but labeled as community event, meaning that there will be a number of active community members attending the conference: adaptTo().
From their website:
In late September 2012 Berlin will become the global heart beat for developers working on the Adobe CQ technical stack.</description></item><item><title>Preparation done - clock is ticking</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preparation-done-clock-is-ticking327/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2012 21:24:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preparation-done-clock-is-ticking327/</guid><description>Preparation done - clock is ticking # The clock is ticking - only one more weekend to go before Berlin Buzzwords opens its doors for the main conference (check out the Wiki for the Sunday evening Barcamp and the Sunday Movie Hackday). Looking forward to an amazing week with awesome speakers and great attendees.
One word of warning before: Given all the buzz around that conference as of now until mid-next week I won&amp;rsquo;t take any major decisions, most likely I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to follow through with any additional organisation, probably I won&amp;rsquo;t remember everyone I meet on-site.</description></item><item><title>Last minute Getting Around information for Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/last-minute-getting-around-information-for-berlin-buzzwords260/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 12:47:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/last-minute-getting-around-information-for-berlin-buzzwords260/</guid><description>Last minute Getting Around information for Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing information on how to get around in Berlin more often than I&amp;rsquo;d like to type it out - putting it here for future reference.
Before going to Berlin make sure to put an app on your phone that helps with finding the right public transport mix to use for going from one place to another:
Nokia Public Transit for WP7 phones</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 10:29:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-schedule-online-book-your-ticket-now117/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords Schedule online - book your ticket now # As of beginning of last week the Berlin Buzzwords schedule is online. The Program Committee has completed reviewing all submissions and set up the schedule containing a great lineup of speakers for this years Berlin Buzzwords program. Among the speakers we have Leslie Hawthorn (Red Hat), Alex Lloyd (Google), Michael Busch (Twitter) as well as Nicolas Spiegelberg (Facebook). Checkout our program in the online schedule.</description></item><item><title>Visiting Berlin Buzzwords - where to go for drinks and food</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/visiting-berlin-buzzwords-where-to-go-for-drinks-and-food430/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 19:39:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/visiting-berlin-buzzwords-where-to-go-for-drinks-and-food430/</guid><description>Visiting Berlin Buzzwords - where to go for drinks and food # There are literally hundreds of bars and restaurants in easy walking distance to the conference venue. And if that is now enough for you, hop on U-Bahn and head east to either Kreuzberg or Friedrichshain to find more. For inspiration check out Tip Berlin - they have a decent, reliable restaurant list.
For quick orientation: Berlin is no one city center but many districts that all have their own look and feel to them.</description></item><item><title>Walking through Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/walking-through-berlin431/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 18:27:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/walking-through-berlin431/</guid><description>Walking through Berlin # Ever made the mistake of booking a flight to a city and trying to decide on what to do only after you arrived? That type of planning does work for Berlin - though you may end up with quite a different schedule than originally intended.
The only thing that needs a bit of planning ahead (about a month) is visiting the Bundestag - fast way to discover it is to just go up to it&amp;rsquo;s dome.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Hadoop Get Together - videos are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-videos-are-up120/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 20:08:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hadoop-get-together-videos-are-up120/</guid><description>Berlin Hadoop Get Together - videos are up # Markus Andrezak on Queue management with Kanban:
Queue Management in Product Development with Kanban - enabling flow and fast feedback along the value chain from David Obermann on Vimeo.
Martin Scholl on Storm:
On Firehoses and Storms: Event Thinking, Event Processing from David Obermann on Vimeo.
Fabian Hüske on Stratosphere:
Large-Scale Data Analysis Beyond Map/Reduce from David Obermann on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</guid><description>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of several people who are not quite sure yet whether they should visit Berlin Buzzwords or not - in particular when having to travel far and cross 9 time zones to attend. My general recommendation is to plan to spend some more days in Europe. The conference is conveniently scheduled on Monday and Tuesday which gives you one weekend before to explore the city and the whole week afterwards to go and see more either in the city or around.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Tech Meetups</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 22:32:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-tech-meetups124/</guid><description>Berlin Tech Meetups # Berlin currently is of growing interest for software engineers, has a very active startup scene and as a result several community organised meetups. Listed below is a short, &amp;ldquo;highly objective&amp;rdquo; selection of local user groups - showing just the breadth of topics discussed.
Berlin Hadoop Get Together
Berlin DevOps
Berlin Buzzwords (conference, no meetup)
Berlin Scrumtisch
Java User Group Berlin/Brandenburg
Berlin Google Technology User Group</description></item><item><title>December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-2149/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 20:14:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-2149/</guid><description>December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # First of all please note that meetup organisation is being transitioned over to our xing meetup group. So in order to be notified of future meetings, make sure to join that group. Please make also sure to register for the December event as in contrast to past meetups this time space will be limited, so make sure to grab a ticket. If you cannot make it, please let the organiser know so he can issue additional tickets.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 16:20:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-hand-over43/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - Hand over # Apache Hadoop receives lots of attention from large US corporations who are using the project to scale their data processing pipelines:
“Facebook uses Hadoop and Hive extensively to process large data sets. [&amp;hellip;]” (Ashish Thusoo, Engineering Manager at Facebook), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop is a key ingredient in allowing LinkedIn to build many of our most computationally difficult features [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo; (Jay Kreps, Principal Engineer, LinkedIn), &amp;ldquo;Hadoop enables [Twitter] to store, process, and derive insights from our data in ways that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise be possible.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 06:06:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin30/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin # Title: Apache Dinner Berlin
Location: Good Morning Vietnam X-Berg&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Start Time: 19:00
Date: 2011-02-28
Please contact Simon Willnauer if you would like to attend for further information.</description></item><item><title>Video is up - Simon Willnauer on Lucene 4 Performance improvements</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-simon-willnauer-on-lucene-4-performance-improvements420/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 21:21:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-simon-willnauer-on-lucene-4-performance-improvements420/</guid><description> Video is up - Simon Willnauer on Lucene 4 Performance improvements #</description></item><item><title>Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 21:19:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</guid><description> Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia #</description></item><item><title>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-berlin-buzzwords-2011-search-score-scale134/</guid><description>CFP - Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - search, score, scale # This is to announce the Berlin Buzzwords 2011. The second edition of the successful conference on scalable and open search, data processing and data storage in Germany,
taking place in Berlin.
Call for Presentations Berlin Buzzwords
http://berlinbuzzwords.de
Berlin Buzzwords 2011 - Search, Store, Scale
6/7 June 2011
The event will comprise presentations on scalable data processing. We invite you to submit talks on the topics:</description></item><item><title>Frau Holle, Frau Holle</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/frau-holle-frau-holle192/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 18:32:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/frau-holle-frau-holle192/</guid><description>Frau Holle, Frau Holle # Winter arrived in Germany - below a few pictures I took last Thursday morning:
Seems like this season winter is trying real hard to prove that I am wrong saying that there is no real winter in Berlin with just about a week snow on the streets ;) Guess its time to get the tires with spikes back on my bike.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:51:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</guid><description>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin # This evening the first Machine Learning Gossip meeting is scheduled to take place at 9p.m. at Victoriabar: Professionals working in research advancing machine learning algorithms and industry projects putting machine learning algorithms to practical use meet for some drinks, food and hopefully lots of interesting discussions.
If successful the meeting is supposed to take place on a regular schedule. Ask Michael Brückner for the date and location of the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 09:52:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today # Just a brief reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is supposed to take place today in newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48 at 5p.m.
The meeting features two talks on Apache Mahout: Committer Sebastian Schelter will explain how to scale recommender systems with Mahout. Contributor Max Heimel is going to give an introduction to the sequence labeling facilities available in Mahout.
As usual the group will move over to Cafe Aufsturz after the meetup is over.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch August Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 16:26:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</guid><description>Scrumtisch August Berlin # Just seen it - the next Scrumtisch Berlin has been scheduled for 25th August 2010 at 18:30 Uhr. So far, no official talk has been scheduled, so please expect two topics on Scrum and its application to be selected for discussion according to Marion&amp;rsquo;s agile topic selection algorithm.
Please talk to Marion Eickmann if you would like to attend the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 06:38:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</guid><description>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening # This evening at Volkspark Friedrichshain, Café Schoenbrunn the next NoSQL summer Berlin (organised by Tim Lossen) is meeting to discuss the paper on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Dynamo &amp;ldquo;Dynamo: Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Highly Available Key-value Store&amp;rdquo;. The group is planning to meet at 19:30 for some beer and discussions on the publication.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 21:54:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</guid><description>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap # This evening yet another Apache Dinner took place in Berlin (this time Schöneberg), location booked by Simon Willnauer. As it was announced less then a week ago (see post below) we were expecting no more then some 7 people &amp;hellip; we ended up being a group of 15 attendees: There was Michi Busch from Twitter together with Tanja, Uwe Schindler from Bremen joined us.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 08:52:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-after-berlin-buzzwords28/</guid><description>Apache Dinner after Berlin Buzzwords # Staying in town after Berlin Buzzwords? Interested in meeting with the Apache folks here? Torsten Curdt kindly organises an Apache Dinner on Wednesday evening after Berlin Buzzwords. If you would like to participate, contact Torsten for details on when and where it will take place.
Though named Apache dinner, there is no need to be Apache committer or even member to participate: Being generally interested in Apache projects and in meeting the guys behind the project is totally sufficient.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - May 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:50:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - May 2010 # This evening a bunch of Apache committers and friends gathered in Berlin Kreuzberg at &amp;ldquo;Goodmorning Vietnam&amp;rdquo; for tasty food, nice drinks - or put another way, for a very nice evening. Simon had booked the table - we were expecting no more than eight people. However, as with any user group these meetup tends to grow. Shortly after the appointed time we had to move to another table to fit everyone around.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - April 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:43:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - April 2010 # Today, the April Apache Dinner took place in Berlin. We met at Sadhu - an Indian restaurant in Berlin X-Berg. We were six people: Lars Trieloff from Day Software, Simon Willnauer and Vera from Lucene, Torsten Curdt - currently Freelancer and Daniel Naber from Lucene as well.
With great food, nice discussions and a first glimpse on the submissions for Berlin Buzzwords it quickly got later and later :)</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 08:00:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday # Next Monday at 7p.m. the April Apache Dinner Berlin is scheduled to take place. Thanks to Torsten Curdt for organising the dinner - as in: Contacting people, finding a suitable data, booking the location etc.
Looking forward to another nice evening at an awesome restaurant with tasty indian food. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to join us, please contact Torsten to be included in the next announcement mail.</description></item><item><title>Coaching self-organising teams</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 21:58:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</guid><description>Coaching self-organising teams # Today, the Scrumtisch organised by Marion Eickmann from Agile 42 met in Berlin Friedrichshain. Though no talk was scheduled for this evening the room was packed with guests from various companies and backgrounds interested in participating in discussions on Scrum.
As usual we started collecting topics (timeboxed to five minutes). The list was rather short, however it contained several interesting pieces:
(6) Management buy-in
(6+) CSP - Certified Scrum Professional - what changes compared to the practitioner?</description></item><item><title>Some pictures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 11:00:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-pictures378/</guid><description>Some pictures # Uwe and Simon were so kind to take some pictures of the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_1.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/hadoop_march_5.JPG&amp;quot; alt=&amp;ldquo;Image Hadoop Get Together Berlin&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
Thanks for the pictures.</description></item><item><title>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 03:41:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bob-schulze-on-tips-and-patterns-with-hbase126/</guid><description>Bob Schulze on Tips and patterns with HBase # At the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Bob Schulze from eCircle in Munich gave a presentation on “Tips and patterns with HBase”. The talk has been video recorded. The result is now available online:
HBase Bob Schulze from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video. Thanks to Bob for an awesome talk on eCircle’s usage of HBase - and on providing some background information on how HBase was applied to solve your problems.</description></item><item><title>Dragan Milosevic on Product Search and Reporting with Hadoop</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-product-search-and-reporting-with-hadoop164/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 20:30:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-up-dragan-milosevic-on-product-search-and-reporting-with-hadoop164/</guid><description>Dragan Milosevic on Product Search and Reporting with Hadoop # At the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Dragan Milosevic from zanox in Berlin gave a presentation on &amp;ldquo;Product Search and Reporting powered by Hadoop&amp;rdquo;. The talk has been video recorded. The result is now available online:
&amp;lt;param name=&amp;ldquo;allowscriptaccess&amp;rdquo; value=&amp;ldquo;always&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;Hadoop Dragan Milosevic from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Feel free to share and distribute the video. Thanks to Dragan for a fantastic talk on Zanox&amp;rsquo; usage of Hadoop - and on providing some background information on why and how you introduced Hadoop into your systems.</description></item><item><title>Third Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 22:04:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</guid><description>Third Apache Dinner Berlin # Today the third Dinner for Apache committers and friends took place in Berlin. We met in Schöneberg at Marcello Berlin for pizza, pasta, wine, beer &amp;hellip; and lots of discussions.
It always surprises me to see how many Apache related people there are in Berlin. This time we had Peter from Tomcat, Daniel and Simon with Vera from Lucene, Eric from http components, four guys from the svn project (Welcome again at the ASF), Oswald and myself and Thilo.</description></item><item><title>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 19:13:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</guid><description>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin # Today first talks scheduled for ignite Berlin were published. If you yourself would like to give a talk: Submission seems to still be open.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 22:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-buzzwords-june-2010114/</guid><description>Berlin Buzzwords - June 2010 # As announced at FOSDEM: Early June (currently scheduled for 7th/8th) a conference on the topics scalable search, storage and processing will take place in Kalkscheune/Berlin. The conference is co-organised by newthinking store, Jan Lehnardt, Simon Willnauer, Thilo Fromm, and Isabel Drost.
The focus will be on NoSQL databases like CouchDB, Jackrabbit, MongoDB, HBase. Search tracks will cover topics like Lucene, Solr, katta and others.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together - March 2010 - Update</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-2010-update44/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 14:25:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-march-2010-update44/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together - March 2010 - Update # Due to conflicts in the schedule of newthinking store, we had to change the time of the Get Together slightly. We will start one hour earlier than announced.
When: March 10th, 4p.m.
Where: newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin Mitte
Looking forward to seeing you there.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop at Heise c't</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 13:37:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-at-heise-ct221/</guid><description>Hadoop at Heise c&amp;rsquo;t # &amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising&amp;gt;
Interesting for those readers speaking German: Heise published an introductory article on Hadoop in its latest issue. Have fun reading.
&amp;lt;surreptitious_advertising/&amp;gt;
Thanks to Simon for proof-reading and providing valuable input. Thanks to Thilo Fromm for the hadoop graphics (unfortunately none of them got published in its original form), the catchy title, proof-reading the text over and over again and for keeping me sane during several past and coming months.</description></item><item><title>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 08:40:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/march-2010-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin284/</guid><description>March 2010 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together that will take place in newthinking store in Berlin.
When: March 10th, 4p.m.
Where: Newthinking store Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner January 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 22:48:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</guid><description>Apache Dinner January 2010 # This evening in X-Berg several local committers met for the second &amp;ldquo;Apache Dinner&amp;rdquo; - an informal gathering of local Apache committers, friends and associates for food, beer and interesting discussions. Next one is probably to be scheduled some time in February. Feel free to send a message to Torsten Curdt to be included on the next invitation mail. Thanks for organizing a nice evening, Torsten.</description></item><item><title>How much of Scrum is implemented?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-much-of-scrum-is-implemented235/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 22:36:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-much-of-scrum-is-implemented235/</guid><description>How much of Scrum is implemented? # I have started using Scrum for various purposes: It has inspired the way software is developed at my current employer. I use it to organize a students&amp;rsquo; project at university. In addition we are using it at home to get all personal tasks (preparing breakfast, doing the laundry, meeting with friends&amp;hellip;) in line for each week.
Constantly looking for ways to evaluate, refine and improve work - I am also looking for ideas on how to evaluate which aspects of the Scrum implementation can actually be improved.</description></item><item><title>Third "December Hadoop Get Together" video online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-december-hadoop-get-together-video-online408/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 19:29:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-december-hadoop-get-together-video-online408/</guid><description>Third &amp;ldquo;December Hadoop Get Together&amp;rdquo; video online # In the following video taken at the last Hadoop Get Together in Berlin Jörg Möllenkamp explains why Hadoop is interesting for Sun - and why Sun Hardware might be a good fit for Hadoop applications:
Hadoop Jörg Möllenkamp from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
In a blog post published after the event, Jörg gives more details on his idea of Parasitic Hadoop he introduced at the meetup.</description></item><item><title>Second December Hadoop Get Together video</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/second-december-hadoop-get-together-video361/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 14:57:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/second-december-hadoop-get-together-video361/</guid><description>Second December Hadoop Get Together video # Richard Hutton from nugg.ad explained how they scaled their ad recommendation system to an increasing number of users with the help of Hadoop. To learn more on their use case and details on which problems they solved with Hadoop, watch the video below:
Hadoop Richard Hutton from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.</description></item><item><title>With a little help from my friends</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 23:55:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</guid><description>With a little help from my friends # The end of the year 2009 is quickly approaching. To me it feels a little like it ran away far too quickly. So instead of taking part in the annual review of past events, I would like to use it as an opportunity to say thank you: The past twelve months were a lot of fun with lots of interesting, nice people from all over the world.</description></item><item><title>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 20:27:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</guid><description>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online # The video of Nikolaus&amp;rsquo; Pohle&amp;rsquo;s talk at the December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is online already - more to come soon.
hadoop nikolaus pohle from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to Martin from newthinking for video taping and uploading. Thanks to StudiVZ for sponsoring the video.</description></item><item><title>Winter arrived at Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-arrived-at-berlin434/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 20:10:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-arrived-at-berlin434/</guid><description>Winter arrived at Berlin # Finally winter seems to have arrived at Berlin as well:
Looks a little like Christmas is drawing closer. Only disadvantage of the weather: One of the breaks of my bike was frozen after very few minutes. Luckily for me, my bike has one of those old-fashioned back pedal brakes ;)</description></item><item><title>Summary - December Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/summary-december-get-together386/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 22:23:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/summary-december-get-together386/</guid><description>Summary - December Get Together # Today the seventh Apache Hadoop Get Together took place in Berlin. The room was again packed with more than 40 people from various companies with and without practical experience with Hadoop: There were people from Nokia Gate 5, Sun, nurago, StudiVZ, Dawanda, Last.fm, nugg.ad. There were people from academia, e.g. HPI Potsdam. And a few Freelancers interested in the topic or providing help with Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>On Wednesday: December Apache Hadoop @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-berlin311/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 20:15:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-berlin311/</guid><description>On Wednesday: December Apache Hadoop @ Berlin # This week on Wednesday at 5p.m. the December Hadoop Get Together takes place in newthinking store Berlin.
Talks scheduled so far:
Richard Hutton (nugg.ad): “Moving from five days to one hour.” Jörg Möllenkamp (Sun): “Hadoop on Sun” Nikolaus Pohle (nurago): “M/R for MR - Online Market Research powered by Apache Hadoop. Enable consultants to analyze online behavior for audience segmentation, advertising effects and usage patterns.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together next week</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-next-week333/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 20:16:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-next-week333/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together next week # Just a tiny little reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is scheduled to take place next week on Wednesday.
When: 16th of December 8PM
Where: newthinking store Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin Mitte
Kindly sponsored by: newthinking store (location) and StudiVZ (videos).
Please regist er (or use Xing for registration) so planning becomes a bit easier.
Talks scheduled: Richard Hutton (nugg.ad): &amp;ldquo;Moving from five days to one hour.</description></item><item><title>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 18:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</guid><description>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # As announced at ApacheCon US, the next Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is scheduled for December 2009.
When: Wednesday December 16, 2009 at 5:00pm Where: newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 21:05:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</guid><description>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp # This is my first real day at ApacheCon US 2009. I arrived yesterday afternoon, was kept awake by three Lucene committers until midnight: &amp;ldquo;Otherwise you will have a very bad jetlag&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Admittedly it did work out: I slept like a baby until about 08:00a.m. the next morning and am not that tired today.
Today Hackthon, Trainings and barcamp Apache happen in parallel.</description></item><item><title>Slides are up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-up372/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 09:02:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-are-up372/</guid><description>Slides are up # The slides for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s talks just arrived. They are available online at:
Isabel Drost: Brief introduction.
Thorsten Schuett: Solving puzzles with map reduce.
Thilo Goetz: An introduction to jaql.
Uwe Schindler: Lucene 2.9 developments.
Videos will be online early next week.</description></item><item><title>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 19:00:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-coming-up416/</guid><description>Upcoming: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # This is a friendly reminder that the next Apache Hadoop Get Together takes place next week on Tuesday, 29th of September* at newthinking store (Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin).
Thorsten Schuett, Solving Puzzles with MapReduce.
Thilo Götz, Text analytics on jaql.
Uwe Schindler, Lucene 2.9 Developments.
Big thanks goes to newthinking store for providing the venue for free and to Cloudera for sponsoring videos of the talks.</description></item><item><title>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:58:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</guid><description>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany # On October 22nd 2009 the first NoSQL Meetup Germany is going to take place in newthinking store/ Berlin: http://nosqlberlin.de
Please submit your presentation proposals until September 22nd, accepted speakers will be notified soon after.
If you would like to sponsor the event, feel free to contact us: We would be very happy to provide videos after the event and free drinks for everyone during the event.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</guid><description>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt # On Wednesday, the 22nd of April, about 20 people interested in Scrum gathered in the DiVino in Friedrichshain/Berlin. The event was split in two parts: In the first half we gathered topics participants were interested in, put priorities next the them and discussed the most highly ranked topic: &amp;ldquo;Scrum in large teams, splitting large tasks across teams.&amp;quot;
The basic take home messages of the discussion:</description></item></channel></rss>