<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>strataeu on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/strataeu/</link><description>Recent content in strataeu on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 20:17:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/strataeu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Strata EU - part 4</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-4385/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 20:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-4385/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 4 # The rest of the day was mainly reserved for more technical talks: Tom Wight introducing the merits of MR2, also known as YARN. Steve Loughran gave a very insightful talk on the various failure modes of Hadoop – though the Namenode is like the most obvious single point of failure there are a few more traps waiting for those depending on their Hadoop clusters: Hadoop does just find with single harddisks failing.</description></item><item><title>Strata EU - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-3384/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 20:16:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-3384/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 3 # The first Tuesday morning keynote put the hype around big data into historical context: According to wikipedia big data apps are defined by their capability of coping with data set sizes that are larger than can be handled with commonly available machines and algorithms. Going from that definition we can look back to history and will realize that the issue of big data actually isn&amp;rsquo;t that new: Even back in the 1950s people had to deal with big data problems.</description></item><item><title>Strata EU - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-2383/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 20:15:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/strata-eu-part-2383/</guid><description>Strata EU - part 2 # The second keynote touched upon the topic of data literacy: In an age in which growing amounts of data are being generated being able to make sense of these becomes a crucial skill for citizens just like reading, writing and computing. The speaker&amp;rsquo;s message was two-fold: a) People currently are not being taught how to deal with that data but are being taught that all that growing data is evil.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata London - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-london-part-1306/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 20:13:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-london-part-1306/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata London - part 1 # A few weeks ago I attended O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata EU. As I had the honour of being on the program committee I remember how hard it was to decide on which talks to accept and which ones to decline. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see that potential turned into an awesome conference on all things Big Data.
I arrived a bit late as I flew in only Monday morning.</description></item></channel></rss>