<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>elasticsearch on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/elasticsearch/</link><description>Recent content in elasticsearch on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:53:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/elasticsearch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSDEM 2014</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:53:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2014 # By now FOSDEM turned into some kind of tradition in our family: Since 2007 every year in February we are travelling to that one comfy B&amp;amp;B in Brussels for a weekend - not to take a closer look at the city but to attend (together with thousands of other geeks and open source hackers) one of the biggest conferences on all things open source. I love the conference concept for scaling: As it happens on a university campus they only have a limited number of huge rooms, but a fairly large number of mid-sized and small rooms.</description></item><item><title>Hello elasticsearch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hello-elasticsearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 20:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hello-elasticsearch/</guid><description>Hello elasticsearch # First of all a disclaimer: I had a little bit of time left during the last few weeks. As a result my blog migrated from dynamic wordpress content to statically hosted pages. If anything looks odd, in case you find any encoding issues, if you miss specific functionality - please do let me know. I&amp;rsquo;ll switch from this beta url back to the old sub-domain in a week or so unless there are major complaints.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Search meetup Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 00:39:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/elastic-search-meetup-berlin167/</guid><description>Elastic Search meetup Berlin # Today Retresco hosted the (to my knowledge fourth) Elastic Search User Group Berlin - a group dedicated to using Lucene as part of Elastic Search. With roughly fifteen attendees the meetup attracted a decent crowd - most interestingly many of the people there were already using the software either in production or for closed beta projects.
The fist talk given was by people from ferret-go - a company doing media monitoring for brands focused on the German market.</description></item></channel></rss>