<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Foundation on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Software-Foundation/</link><description>Recent content in Software Foundation on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 21:07:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Software-Foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>February 14th: "I love free software day"</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-14th-i-love-free-software-day170/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 21:07:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-14th-i-love-free-software-day170/</guid><description>February 14th: &amp;ldquo;I love free software day&amp;rdquo; # This year FSFE is once again running their I love free software campaign on February 14th: The goal they put up is to have more love reports, hugs and Thank You messages sent out than bug reports filed against projects.
They have put online a few ideas on what to do that day. I&amp;rsquo;d like to add one additional option: If you are using any free software and you feel the urgent need to file a bug report on that day, use the opportunity to submit a patch as well: Make sure to not only describe what is going wrong but add a patch that contains a test to show the issue and a code modification that fixes the issue, is compatible with the project&amp;rsquo;s coding guidelines, doesn&amp;rsquo;t break anything else in the project.</description></item><item><title>Talking people into submitting patches</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches388/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 20:22:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches388/</guid><description>Talking people into submitting patches # In November I am going to attend Apache Con NA. This year I decided to do a little experiment: I sumitted a talk on talking people into contributing to free software projects. The format of the talk is a bit unusual: Drawing from my - admittedly limited and very biased - experience explaining free software to others and talking people into contributing patches this talks tries to initiate a discussion on methods to get awesome developers to consider contributing their work back to free software projects.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout Podcast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 21:21:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-podcast83/</guid><description>Apache Mahout Podcast # During Apache Con ATL Michael Coté interviewed Grant Ingersoll on Apache Mahout. The interview is available online as podcast. The interview covers the goals and current use cases of the project, goes into some detail on the reasons for initially starting it. If you are wondering what Mahout is all about, what you can do with it and which direction development is heading, the interview is a great option to find out more.</description></item><item><title>Apache Lunch Devoxx</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 21:30:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</guid><description>Apache Lunch Devoxx # On Twitter I suggested to host an Apache dinner during Devoxx. Matthias Wesendorf of Apache MyFaces was so kind to take up the discussion carrying it over to the Apache community mailing-list. It quickly turned out that there was quite some interest with several members and committers attending Devoxx. We scheduled the meetup for Friday after the conference during lunch time.
I pinged a few Apache related people I knew would attend the conference (being a speaker and a committer at some Apache project almost certainly resulted in getting a ping).</description></item><item><title>Devoxx Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 21:16:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</guid><description>Devoxx Antwerp # With 3000 attendees Devoxx is the largest Java Community conference world-wide. Each year in autumn it takes place in Antwerp/ Belgium, in recent years in the Metropolis cinema. The conference tickets were sold out long before doors were opened this year.
The focus of the presentations are mainly on enterprise Java featuring talks by famous Joshua Bloch, Mark Reihnhold and others on new features of the upcoming JDK release as well as intricacies of the Java programming language itself.</description></item><item><title>Christmas Scrumtisch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/christmas-scrumtisch138/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 22:59:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/christmas-scrumtisch138/</guid><description>Christmas Scrumtisch # Today the last Scrumtisch Berlin in 2010 took place in Friedrichshain. Thanks to Marion Eickmann and Andrea Tomasini for organising the Scrum user group regularly for the past years.
Though no presentation had been scheduled ahead of time the Scrumtisch was well attended by over twenty people, mostly from companies based in Berlin who are either using Scrum already or are currently in a transition phase.</description></item><item><title>Travelling</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 23:17:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/travelling414/</guid><description>Travelling # Currently on my way back from a series of conferences in the past three weeks in the IC from Schiphol. After three weeks of conferences, lots of new input and lots of interesting projects I learned about it is finally time to head back and put the stuff I have learned to good use.
View Travelling in a larger map
As seems normal with open source conferences I got far more input on interesting projects than I can expect to ever get applied in on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:32:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-devoxx-tools-in-action-track67/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Devoxx Tools in Action Track # This year&amp;rsquo;s Devoxx will feature several presentations coming from the Apache Hadoop ecosystem including Tom White on the basics of Hadoop: HDFS, MapReduce, Hive and Pig as well as Michael Stack on HBase.
&amp;lt; br&amp;gt;
In addition there will be a brief Tools in Action presentation on Monday evening featuring Apache Mahout.
Please let me know if you are going to Devoxx - would be great to meet some more Apache people there, maybe have dinner at one of the conference days.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 09:36:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-lisbon-codebits68/</guid><description>Apache Mahout @ Lisbon Codebits # Second week of November I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a few days in Lisbon - never would have thought that I&amp;rsquo;d return so quickly when I visited this beautiful city this summer during vacation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for Codebits - thanks to Sapo for inviting me to be there.
Back in summer I learned only after I returned to Germany that there was someone form Portugal seeking to meet with other Apache people exactly when I was down there.</description></item><item><title>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2010 20:39:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-at-apache-con-na69/</guid><description>Apache Mahout at Apache Con NA # The upcoming Apache Con NA to take place in Atlanta will feature several tracks relevant to users of Apache Mahout, Lucene and Hadoop: There will be a full track on Hadoop as well as one on NoSQL on Wednesday featuring talks on the framework itself, Pig and Hive as well as presentations from users on special use cases and on their way of getting the system to production.</description></item><item><title>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 09:52:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reminder-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-today332/</guid><description>Reminder: Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin Today # Just a brief reminder: The Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is supposed to take place today in newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48 at 5p.m.
The meeting features two talks on Apache Mahout: Committer Sebastian Schelter will explain how to scale recommender systems with Mahout. Contributor Max Heimel is going to give an introduction to the sequence labeling facilities available in Mahout.
As usual the group will move over to Cafe Aufsturz after the meetup is over.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 08:16:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-october-today-in-potsdam36/</guid><description>Apache Dinner October Today in Potsdam # The Apache Dinner Berlin will take place today. As always, everybody is invited even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the poll ( http://doodle.com/8bi2456enwe6z2g6). This time around the dinner was organised by Daniel Naber. Thanks!
When: Monday, 2010-10-04, 19:30
Where: Lindencafe, Rudolf-Breitscheid-Str. 47/48, 14482 Potsdam-Babelsberg, This is directly next to the S-Bahn (S7, Babelsberg).
Looking forward to meeting you there!</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 08:00:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-this-evening37/</guid><description>Apache Dinner this evening # This evening the September Apache Dinner takes place in Jamerica Schöneberg. I have booked a table for ten to fifteen people - we&amp;rsquo;ll see whether that is sufficient this time :)
Looking forward to see you there at 7p.m.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Scrumtisch - open discussion</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-open-discussion123/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 21:29:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-open-discussion123/</guid><description>Berlin Scrumtisch - open discussion # This evening the Berlin Scrumtisch took place in Friedrichshain. More than thirty participants followed Marion&amp;rsquo;s invitation for discussions on Scrum, wine and pizza at Vecchia Trattoria.
As there were several new participants, Felix started out with a very brief summary of the very core concepts of Scrum itself: Most important to know is the basic assumption of Scrum, that is planning ahead of time in a very detailed way is impossible.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner DUS</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 19:10:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</guid><description>Apache Dinner DUS # the evening after FrOSCon - that is on August 22nd 2010 at 7:30p.m. CEST - a combined &amp;ldquo;FSFE Fellowship meetup/ Apache dinner*&amp;rdquo; takes place in Tigges in Düsseldorf (Brunnenstraße 1, at Bilker S-Bahnhof). Given it doesn&amp;rsquo;t rain, we&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting outside.
Would be great to meet you there for tasty food, interesting discussions on Apache in general, as well as projects like Lucene, Hadoop or Tomcat in particular.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 21:54:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-august-berlin-recap29/</guid><description>Apache Dinner August Berlin recap # This evening yet another Apache Dinner took place in Berlin (this time Schöneberg), location booked by Simon Willnauer. As it was announced less then a week ago (see post below) we were expecting no more then some 7 people &amp;hellip; we ended up being a group of 15 attendees: There was Michi Busch from Twitter together with Tanja, Uwe Schindler from Bremen joined us.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin - August 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-august-201131/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 14:52:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-august-201131/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin - August 2010 # Simon (Willnauer) just sent around the following e-mail. If you have some time left next Monday evening, come join us in Yogihaus: For tasty Indian food, geeky discussions and a generally beautiful evening.
Unlike the other dinner mails this one is not a poll, it&amp;rsquo;s an announcement. Some Apache folks are in town next monday (9th of August) so we decided to have a Apache Dinner with a short term notice.</description></item><item><title>Part 1: Travelling minds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:00:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</guid><description>Part 1: Travelling minds # In the last post I promised to share some more information on techniques I came across and found useful under an increasing work load. Instead of taking a close look at my professional calendar I decided to use my private one as an example - first because spare time is even more precious then working hours, simply because there is so few of it and secondly because I am free to publicly scrutinize not only the methods for keeping it in good shape but also the entries in it.</description></item><item><title>Series: Getting things done</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 07:07:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</guid><description>Series: Getting things done # Probably not too unusual for people working on free software mostly (though no longer exclusively) in their spare time, the number of items that appear in my private calendar have increased steadily in the past months and years:
Every three months I am organising the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin.
I have been asked (and accepted the offer) to publish articles on Hadoop and Lucene in magazines.</description></item><item><title>Apache Lunch in Portugal</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-in-portugal63/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 13:37:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-in-portugal63/</guid><description>Apache Lunch in Portugal # Just read on the Apache community mailing list that inspired by our Apache Dinner Berlin people in Porto are organising an Apache Lunch event. As with the dinner here in Berlin, anyone who is interested in Apache is welcome to join - no need to be a committer or even ASF member ;) If you are living close to Porto, or always wanted to visit the city - after all it&amp;rsquo;s a very beautiful place, there is a beach close by, there are many tasty restaurants - don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with the organisers:</description></item><item><title>Linus Torwalds on the Linux kernel community</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/linus-torwalds-on-the-linux-kernel-community264/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 18:10:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/linus-torwalds-on-the-linux-kernel-community264/</guid><description>Linus Torwalds on the Linux kernel community # A few days ago, Linus send a very interesting mail on why he considers C the programming language that is most suitable for the Linux kernel. Despite the language specific arguments, the text contains quite a few insights on how the Linux kernel community works and communicates that might be interesting to non-kernel-hackers as well:
People working for free still doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it&amp;rsquo;s fine</description></item><item><title>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 18:32:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-highly-subjective-berlin-buzzwords-recap290/</guid><description>My highly subjective Berlin Buzzwords recap # Last November I innocently asked Grant what it would take to make him to give a talk in Berlin. The only requirement he told me was that I&amp;rsquo;d have to pay for his flight. About eight months later we had Berlin Buzzwords - a conference all around the topics scalability, data storage and search. With Simon Willnauer, Uwe Schindler, Michael Busch, Robert Muir, Grant Ingersoll, Andrzej Bialecki and many others we had quite a few Lucene people in town.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner June 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 23:54:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-june-201035/</guid><description>Apache Dinner June 2010 # After Berlin Buzzwords was over yesterday - and as there is an svn conference in the city that starts tomorrow, we thought we could easily put together a smallish Apache Dinner for tonight. So Torsten mailed a few people, booked some space at Heinz Minki in Kreuzberg. We announced it at the end of the conference and invited people to join us.
So after a beautiful day out I spent the evening with a bunch of Apache related guys and girls having drinks and great pizza: We had several svn committers, Greg Stein met us there - he arrived today for the svn conference.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - May 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 22:50:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-may-201027/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - May 2010 # This evening a bunch of Apache committers and friends gathered in Berlin Kreuzberg at &amp;ldquo;Goodmorning Vietnam&amp;rdquo; for tasty food, nice drinks - or put another way, for a very nice evening. Simon had booked the table - we were expecting no more than eight people. However, as with any user group these meetup tends to grow. Shortly after the appointed time we had to move to another table to fit everyone around.</description></item><item><title>Going to Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 08:46:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/going-to-berlin-buzzwords213/</guid><description>Going to Berlin Buzzwords # Meet me in two weeks at Berlin Buzzwords. As you may have noticed, together with Simon Willnauer, Jan Lehnardt and newthinking communications I am organising Berlin Buzzwords - a conference on scalable search, data analysis and storage.
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://berlinbuzzwords.de/sites/berlinbuzzwords.de/files/buzzwords_banner.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to Berlin Buzzwords
the conference on searching, processing and storing data.&amp;rdquo;/&amp;gt;
There are a few regular tickets left, so don&amp;rsquo;t wait too long to register.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner - April 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 21:43:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-april-201026/</guid><description>Apache Dinner - April 2010 # Today, the April Apache Dinner took place in Berlin. We met at Sadhu - an Indian restaurant in Berlin X-Berg. We were six people: Lars Trieloff from Day Software, Simon Willnauer and Vera from Lucene, Torsten Curdt - currently Freelancer and Daniel Naber from Lucene as well.
With great food, nice discussions and a first glimpse on the submissions for Berlin Buzzwords it quickly got later and later :)</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 08:00:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-berlin-this-evening32/</guid><description>Apache Dinner Berlin - next Monday # Next Monday at 7p.m. the April Apache Dinner Berlin is scheduled to take place. Thanks to Torsten Curdt for organising the dinner - as in: Contacting people, finding a suitable data, booking the location etc.
Looking forward to another nice evening at an awesome restaurant with tasty indian food. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to join us, please contact Torsten to be included in the next announcement mail.</description></item><item><title>GSoC - one day to go for your application</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 14:37:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-one-day-to-go-for-your-application218/</guid><description>GSoC - one day to go for your application # If you are a student interested in participating in Google Summer of Code: Registration closes tomorrow (as in &amp;ldquo;April 9, 19:00 UTC&amp;rdquo;). You hopefully published and discussed your proposal at your favourite project already so you have a clear plan of where to go and which milestones to achieve in summer.
If you are interested in Apache Mahout: Yes, as last years, we are again looking for students willing to work on awesome student projects this summer.</description></item><item><title>Third Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 22:04:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/third-apache-dinner-berlin409/</guid><description>Third Apache Dinner Berlin # Today the third Dinner for Apache committers and friends took place in Berlin. We met in Schöneberg at Marcello Berlin for pizza, pasta, wine, beer &amp;hellip; and lots of discussions.
It always surprises me to see how many Apache related people there are in Berlin. This time we had Peter from Tomcat, Daniel and Simon with Vera from Lucene, Eric from http components, four guys from the svn project (Welcome again at the ASF), Oswald and myself and Thilo.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code starting</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 19:10:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/google-summer-of-code-starting214/</guid><description>Google Summer of Code starting # As published on the Google Open Source blog the application period for mentoring organizations for GSoC starts now. The ASF is already in the process of applying. If you are a student, looking for an interesting project to work on during the coming summer - you might consider participating in GSoC. It does give you are great opportunity to get in touch with successful free software projects, learn how to work in global teams, improve your communication skills and last but not least show and publish your fantastic coding skills.</description></item><item><title>Apache brand name - survey</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-brand-name-survey11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 19:03:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-brand-name-survey11/</guid><description>Apache brand name - survey # Sally Khudairi (VP, ASF Marketing &amp;amp; Publicity) asked for distributing the following survey to people who might be interested in contributing their views to a study on how the brand name Apache is perceived. Me personally, I would be especially interested in finding out more on whether there are any differences in perception inside the ASF vs. outside&amp;hellip;
We have been working with PhD candidate Roland Schroll over the past two years as he&amp;rsquo;s been compiling information on the value of the Apache brand.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner January 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 22:48:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</guid><description>Apache Dinner January 2010 # This evening in X-Berg several local committers met for the second &amp;ldquo;Apache Dinner&amp;rdquo; - an informal gathering of local Apache committers, friends and associates for food, beer and interesting discussions. Next one is probably to be scheduled some time in February. Feel free to send a message to Torsten Curdt to be included on the next invitation mail. Thanks for organizing a nice evening, Torsten.</description></item><item><title>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 20:27:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-december-apache-hadoop-berlin-video-online175/</guid><description>First December Apache Hadoop Berlin video online # The video of Nikolaus&amp;rsquo; Pohle&amp;rsquo;s talk at the December Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is online already - more to come soon.
hadoop nikolaus pohle from Isabel Drost on Vimeo.
Thanks to Martin from newthinking for video taping and uploading. Thanks to StudiVZ for sponsoring the video.</description></item><item><title>On Thursday: Open Hadoop User Group Munich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-thursday-open-hadoop-user-group-munich310/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 06:06:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-thursday-open-hadoop-user-group-munich310/</guid><description>On Thursday: Open Hadoop User Group Munich # If one evening of Apache Hadoop is not enough for you: The next Christmas Meetup in Germany takes place one day later in Munich.
&amp;lt;li
When: Thursday December 17, 2009 at 5:30pm open end
Where: eCircle AG, Nymphenburger Straße 86, 80636 München (&amp;ldquo;Bruckmann&amp;rdquo; Building, &amp;ldquo;U1 Mailinger Str&amp;rdquo;, map in German http://www.ecircle.com/de/kontakt/anfahrt.html and look for the signs)
Talks scheduled by Bob and Lars:</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 09:19:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">
Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010
&lt;a class="anchor" href="#apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Though the official schedule is not yet online: I will be giving an introductory talk about Apache Hadoop at next
year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM (Free and Open Source Developer European Meeting) in Brussles. This will be the 10th birthday of the
event - looking forward to a fun event, meeting other free and open source software developers from all over
Europe.&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;center>&lt;br>&lt;img src="http://fosdem.org/2010/promo/fosdem">&lt;br>&lt;/center>&lt;br>&lt;br>If you are a Apache
Hadoop developer and would like me to include some particular topic in the talk - please feel free to contact me. If
you are an Apache Hadoop user and would like to learn more on the project, please come to the talk and ask questions.
If you are an Apache Hadoop Newbie - feel free to join us.&lt;br>&lt;br>In addition there will be a NoSQL Dev Room at FOSDEM
as well. The call for presentations is up already. So if you are doing fun stuff with CouchDB, HBase and friends or are
a developer of these projects - submit a talk and join us in early-February in Brussles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Apache Dinner Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-apache-dinner-berlin174/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 02:33:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-apache-dinner-berlin174/</guid><description>First Apache Dinner Berlin # A few days ago, I received a mail from Torsten Curdt that read something like: &amp;ldquo;[&amp;hellip;] For a long time now I wanted to organise an Apache Dinner Berlin. What do you think, when would be a good time for that?&amp;rdquo;. As that was about the third time I heard of that idea (and the third person mentioning the idea), I included some Berlin-based Apache-people asking whether they would be interested in having an Apache Dinner on November 24st in X-Berg.</description></item><item><title>ApacheCon Oakland Roundup</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-oakland-roundup88/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:15:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-oakland-roundup88/</guid><description>ApacheCon Oakland Roundup # Two weeks ago ApacheCon US 2009 ended in Oakland California. Shane published a set of links to articles that contain information on what happened at Apache Con. Some of them are officially published by the Apache PRC project, others are write-ups of individuals on which talks they attended and which topics they considered particularly interesting.</description></item><item><title>Mahout 0.2 released</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 10:52:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-02-released273/</guid><description>Mahout 0.2 released # Apache Mahout 0.2 has been released and is now available for public download at http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/lucene/mahout
Up to date maven artifacts can be found in the Apache repository at
https://repository.apache.org/cont ent/repositories/releases/org/apache/mahout/
Apache Mahout is a subproject of Apache Lucene with the goal of delivering scalable machine learning algorithm implementations under the Apache license. http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
Mahout is a machine learning library meant to scale: Scale in terms of community to support anyone interested in using machine learning.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Expo 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:17:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-expo-09318/</guid><description>Open Source Expo 09 # I spent last Sunday and the following Monday at Open Source Expo Karlsruhe - co-located with web-tech and php-conference organized by the Software-and-Support Verlag. Together with Simon Willnauer I ran the Lucene/Mahout booth at the expo.
So far the conference is still very small (about 400 visitors) compared to free software community events. However the focus was set to be more on professional users, accordingly several projects showed that free software can be used successfully for various business use cases.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con US Wrap Up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:10:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</guid><description>Apache Con US Wrap Up # some weeks ago I attended ApacheConUS09 in Oakland/ California. In the mean time, videos of one of the sessions have been published online:
You can find a wrap up of the most prominent topics at the conference at heise (unfortunately Germany-only).
By far the largest topics at the conference:
Lucene - there was a meetup with over 100 attendees as well as two main tracks with Lucene focussed talks.</description></item><item><title>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 18:01:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/december-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin148/</guid><description>December Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # As announced at ApacheCon US, the next Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is scheduled for December 2009.
When: Wednesday December 16, 2009 at 5:00pm Where: newthinking store, Tucholskystr. 48, Berlin
As always there will be slots of 20min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss. You can order drinks directly at the bar in the newthinking store.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con US - Program up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-program-up23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2009 07:35:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-program-up23/</guid><description>Apache Con US - Program up # The final program is available for download over at http://us.apachecon.com. The schedule is packed with interesting talks on Hadoop, Lucene, Tomcat, httpd, web services, osgi. For those less tech-savvy there is a business track explaining how to best use open source software in an entreprise environment. There is also a community track explaining what makes open source projects successful.
Looking forward to seeing you in Oakland.</description></item><item><title>Lucene 2.9 White Paper</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-white-paper268/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 21:51:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-white-paper268/</guid><description>Lucene 2.9 White Paper # Lucid recently published a white paper that explains the changes and improvements that the new 2.9 release incorporates. Interesting for all who are thinking about upgrading to the new lucene version or generally want to know what is going on at Lucene.</description></item><item><title>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 18:13:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-29-heise267/</guid><description>Lucene 2.9 @ Heise # After last week&amp;rsquo;s Hadoop Get Together heise published an in-depth article on the changes and improvements that come with the latest Lucene 2.9 release.
Thanks to Simon Willnauer for helping me write this article and patiently explaining several new features. Thanks also to Uwe Schindler for kindly proof-reading the article before it was sent out to Heise.</description></item><item><title>Mahout@TU WS 09/10</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 23:08:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</guid><description>Mahout@TU WS 09/10 # Title: Mahout@TU WS 09/10
There is going to be a project/seminar course at TU Berlin on Apache Mahout. The goal is to introduce students to the work on a free software project, interact with the community and build production ready software.
Students will be given several potential tasks ranging from optimizing existing implementations, implementing new algorithms and (depending on their prior knowledge) improving, scaling and parallelizing existing algorithms.</description></item><item><title>GSoC at Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-at-mahout219/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 22:22:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-at-mahout219/</guid><description>GSoC at Mahout # GSoC 2009 is about to finish: Final evaluations are through, most of the code submitted by Mahout&amp;rsquo;s students has been committed to svn, code samples are on their way to Google.
In Mahout, we had three students joining the project: Robin working on an HBase based Naive Bayes extension and on frequent itemset discovery. David contributing a distributed LDA implementation. Deneche was working on a Random Forest implementation.</description></item><item><title>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:58:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</guid><description>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany # On October 22nd 2009 the first NoSQL Meetup Germany is going to take place in newthinking store/ Berlin: http://nosqlberlin.de
Please submit your presentation proposals until September 22nd, accepted speakers will be notified soon after.
If you would like to sponsor the event, feel free to contact us: We would be very happy to provide videos after the event and free drinks for everyone during the event.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con drawing closer</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-drawing-closer17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2009 06:47:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-drawing-closer17/</guid><description>Apache Con drawing closer # By November I will be traveling to Oakland - for me it is the first Apache Con US ever. And the first Apache Con I will be giving a talk in one of the main tracks:
I will be presenting Apache Mahout, give an overview of the project, of our current status and explain which problems can be solved with the current implementation. The talks will conclude with an outlook to upcoming tasks and features our users can expect in the near future.</description></item><item><title>Inglourious Basterds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/inglourious-basterds238/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 22:48:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/inglourious-basterds238/</guid><description>Inglourious Basterds # This evening I went to the cinema Odeon in Berlin Schöneberg. It is a pretty traditional, old-fashioned and very lovely cinema that has specialised on showing non-dubbed, original versions of movies.
Showing the great movie Inglourious Basterds, the cinema was completely sold out today. Fortunately we were able to grab some of the last tickets.
Just in case the entrance seemed familiar to those who have attended a Mahout presentation in the recent past - a picture of the Odeon usually visualises one part of my motivation on the Mahout slides ;)</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Event Blog</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-event-blog41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2009 20:38:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-event-blog41/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Event Blog # As Apache Hadoop becomes ever more popular both in industry as well as in research, user groups, conferences and hacking days are being scheduled around the world. The goal of the event calendar blog hosted on wordpress.com is to provide a common space for organizers to announce their events and potential participants to look for new conferences.</description></item><item><title>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:48:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/september-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin366/</guid><description>September Apache Hadoop Get Together @ Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin is to take place on September 29th in newthinking store. Details are up on the web page at upcoming and will be sent out to the mailing list soon.</description></item><item><title>Flying back home from Cologne</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 20:40:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/flying-back-home-from-cologne178/</guid><description>Flying back home from Cologne # Last weekend FrOSCon took place in Sankt Augustin, near Cologne. FrOSCon is organized on a yearly basis at the university of applied sciences in Sankt Augustin. It is a volunteer driven event with the goal of bringing developers and users of free software projects together. This year, the conference featured 5 tracks, two examples being cloud computing and the Java track.
Unfortunately this year the conference started with a little surprise for me and my boyfriend: Being both speakers, we had booked a room in Hotel Regina via the conference committee.</description></item><item><title>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 09:11:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-2365/</guid><description>September 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The newthinking store Berlin is hosting the Hadoop Get Together user group meeting. It features talks on Hadoop, Lucene, Solr, UIMA, katta, Mahout and various other projects that deal with making large amounts of data accessible and processable. The event brings together leaders from the developer and user communities. The speakers present projects that build on top of Hadoop, case studies of applications being built and deployed on Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Solr at AOL</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 13:06:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solr-at-aol376/</guid><description>Solr at AOL # Grant Ingersoll has posted a very interesting interview with Ian Holsman on Solr at Relegance, now AOL. It describes the business side of the decission to switch to an open source solution, provides some inside on the size of the installation and details which technological reasons have driven the decission to switch from a proprietary implementation to Solr:
http://www.lucidimagination.com/Community/Hear-from-the-Experts/Podcasts-and-Videos/Interview-Ian-Holsman-Relegence&amp;lt;/ a&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Large Scalability - Papers and implementations</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/large-scalability-papers-and-implementations259/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 12:08:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/large-scalability-papers-and-implementations259/</guid><description>Large Scalability - Papers and implementations # In recent years the Googles and Amazons on this world have released papers on how to scale computing and processing to terrabytes of data. These publications have led to the implementation of various open source projects that benefit from that knowledge. However mapping the various open source projects to the original papers and assigning tasks that these projects solve is not always easy.</description></item><item><title>Tomcat Tuesday talk</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 09:07:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tomcat-tuesday-talk411/</guid><description>Tomcat Tuesday talk # Since several months at neofonie we have a talk given by external or internal developers on various subjects each Tuesday. Usually these presentations are a nice way to get an overview of new emerging technologies, to get an overview of current conference topics or to gain insight into interesting internal projects.
This week we had Apache Tomcat Committer and PMC Peter Rossbach here at neofonie to talk about the Tomcat architecture and Tomcat clustering solutions.</description></item><item><title>Back from Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 16:58:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/back-from-zurich109/</guid><description>Back from Zürich # I spend the last five days in Zurich. I wanted to visit the city again - and still owed one of my friends there a visit. I am really happy the weather was quite nice over the weekend. That way I could spend quite some time in town (got another one of those puzzles) and go for a hike on the Ütli mountain: I took the steep way up that had quite a lot of stairs.</description></item><item><title>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 08:54:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/feedback-from-the-hadoop-user-group-uk172/</guid><description>Feedback from the Hadoop User Group UK # A few weeks after the Hadoop User Group UK is over, there are quite a few postings on the event online. I will try to keep this page updated if there are any further reviews. The one I found so far:
http://huguk.org/2009/04/huguk-2-wrap-up.html - the wrap-up of the event itself.
http://blog.oskarsson.nu/2009_04_01_archive.html - a short summary by the organiser - Thanks again for a great event.</description></item><item><title>Mahout on EC2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-on-ec2281/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 21:00:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahout-on-ec2281/</guid><description>Mahout on EC2 # Amazon released Elastic Map Reduce only a few weeks ago. EMR is based on a hosted Hadoop environment and offers machines to run map reduce jobs against data in S3 on demand.
Last week Stephen Green has spent quite some effort to get Mahout running on EMR. Thanks to his work Mahout is running on EMR since last Thursday night. Read the weblog of Tim Bass for further information.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop User Group UK</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-user-group-uk-2226/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 20:34:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-user-group-uk-2226/</guid><description>Hadoop User Group UK # On Tuesday the 14th the second Hadoop User Group UK took place in London. This time venue and pizza was sponsored by Sun. The room quickly filled http://www.thecepblog.com/2009/04/19/kmeans-clustering-now-running-on-elastic-mapreduce/with approximately 70 people.
Tom opened the session with a talk on 10 practical tips on how to get the most benefit from Apache Hadoop. The first question users should ask themselves is which type of programming language they want to use.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 15:11:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/announcing-apache-mahout-0110/</guid><description>Announcing Apache Mahout 0.1 # This morning I received Grant&amp;rsquo;s release mail of Apache Mahout. I am really happy that after little more than one year we now have our first release out there to test and scrutinate by anyone interested in the project. Thanks to all the committers who have helped make this possible. A special thanks to Grant Ingersoll for putting so much time into getting many release issues out of the way as well as to those who reviewed the release candidates and all the major and minor problems.</description></item><item><title>GSoC: Student applications.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:57:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/gsoc-student-applications-closed220/</guid><description>GSoC: Student applications. # Title: GSoC: Student applications closed
Link out: Click here
Description: After this date no more student applications are accepted. Internal ranking at Apache starts 7 days earlier. The ranking process finishes at 16th of April.
Date: 2009-04-03</description></item><item><title>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2009 09:54:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/students-begin-coding-for-their-gsoc-projects1/</guid><description>Students begin coding for their GSoC projects # Title: Students begin coding for their GSoC projects
Link out: Click here
Description: GSoC time.
Date: 2009-05-26</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:56:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-2009-part-320/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 3 # Friday was the last conference day. I enjoyed the Apache pioneers panel with a brief history of the Apache Software Foundation as well as lots of stories on how people first got in contact with the ASF.
After lunch I went to the testing and cloud session. I enjoyed the talk on continuum and its uses by Wendy Smoak. She gave a basic overview of why one would want a CI system and provided a brief introduction to continuum.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 19:42:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-219/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 2 # Thursday morning started with an interesting talk on open source collaboration tools and how they can help resolving some collaboration overhead on commercial software projects. Four goals can be reached with the help of the right tools: Sharing the project vision, tracking the current status of the project, finding places to help the project and documenting the project history as well as the reasons for decisions along the way.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 18:41:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1 # The past week members, committers and users of Apache software projects gathered in Amsterdam for another Apache Con EU
and to celebrate the 10th birthday of the ASF. One week dedicated to the development and use of Free Software and the Apache Way.
Monday was BarCamp day for me, the first BarCamp I ever attended. Unfortunately not all participants proposed talks. So some of the atmosphere of an unconference was missing.</description></item><item><title>March 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin283/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 19:50:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin283/</guid><description>March 2009 Hadoop Get Together Berlin # Since last summer, newthinking store Berlin is hosting a Hadoop Meetup every quarter of the year. The scope of these user group meetings is not only on Hadoop projects but deals with technologies necessary with storing, processing and searching large amounts of data.
The meeting last Thursday featured a talk by Lars George on his experiences using HBase in customer projects as early as in 2007.</description></item></channel></rss>