<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Science on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Science/</link><description>Recent content in Science on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Taming Text</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 20:21:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-taming-text309/</guid><description>On Taming Text # This time of the year I would usually post pictures of my bicycle standing in the snow somewhere in Tierpark. This year however I was tricked into using public transport instead: a) After my husband found a new job, we now share some of the route to work - and he isn&amp;rsquo;t crazy going by bike when it&amp;rsquo;s snowing. b) I got myself a Nexus7 earlier this month which obsoleted having to take paper books with me when using public transport.</description></item><item><title>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 12:40:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/recsys-stammtisch-berlin-december-2012331/</guid><description>RecSys Stammtisch Berlin - December 2012 # Earlier this month I attended the fourth Recommender Stammtisch in Berlin. The event was kindly hosted by Soundcloud - who on top of organising the speakers provided a really yummy buffet by Kochzeichen D.
With Paul Lamere the evening started with a very entertaining but also very packed talk on why music recommendation is special - or put more generally why all recommender systems are special:</description></item><item><title>Data Scientists - researchers' persectives</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-scientists-researchers-persectives145/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 20:35:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/data-scientists-researchers-persectives145/</guid><description>Data Scientists - researchers&amp;rsquo; persectives # &amp;ldquo;Data scientist&amp;rdquo; as a term has caught quite some attention as of late (together with all the big data, scalability and cloud hype). Instead of re-hashing arguments seen in other sources I thought it might make more sense to link to a few of the thought provoking posts I came across recently.
In his post Mikio Braun analyses the factors motivating research in academia vs.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon 2012</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012197/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 20:25:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2012197/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2012 # On August 25th/26th the Free and Open Source Conference (FrOSCon) will again kick off in Sankt Augustin/ Germany. The event is completely community organised, hosted by the FH Sankt Augustin. It covers a broad range of free software topics like Arduino microcontrollers, git goodies, politics, strace, open nebula, wireshark and others.
Three highlights that are on my schedule:
I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure I do not miss Thilo Fromm&amp;rsquo;s presentation on building a platform project on top of Open Embedded.</description></item><item><title>Book: Search Patterns</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/book-search-patterns127/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 20:41:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/book-search-patterns127/</guid><description>Book: Search Patterns # I got the book months ago during FOSDEM - the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly book table always is a pretty dangerous place as a meeting point for me: Search Patterns - Design for Discovery is one of those small, deceivingly beautiful books that manages to explain effective search engine design by focusing on the end user needs but going into some detail concerning the basics of search engine backends as well.</description></item><item><title>Need your input: Failing big data projects - experiences from the wild</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/need-your-input-failing-big-data-projects-experiences-from-the-wild291/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 20:11:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/need-your-input-failing-big-data-projects-experiences-from-the-wild291/</guid><description>Need your input: Failing big data projects - experiences from the wild # A few weeks ago my talk on &amp;ldquo;How to fail your big data project quick and rapidly&amp;rdquo; was accepted at O&amp;rsquo;Reily Strata conference in London. The basic intention of this talk is to share some anti-patterns, embarrassing failure modes and &amp;ldquo;please don&amp;rsquo;t do this at home&amp;rdquo; kind of advice with those entering the buzzwordy space of big data.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - TDD and it's influence on software design</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-tdd-and-its-influence-on-software-design207/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 08:04:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-tdd-and-its-influence-on-software-design207/</guid><description>GeeCon - TDD and it&amp;rsquo;s influence on software design # The second talk I went to on the first day was on the influence of TDD on software design. Keith Braithwaite did a really great job of first introducing the concept of cyclomatic complexity and than showing at the example of Hudson as well as many other open source Java projects that the average and mean cyclomatic complexity of all those projects actually is pretty close to one and when plotted for all methods pretty much follows a power law distribution.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - Randomized testing</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-randomized-testing205/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 08:02:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-randomized-testing205/</guid><description>GeeCon - Randomized testing # I arrived late during lunch time on Thursday for GeeCon – however just in time to listen to one of the most interesting talks when it comes to testing. Did you ever have the issue of writing code that runs well in your development environment but crashes as soon as it&amp;rsquo;s rolled out at customers only to find out that their Locale setting was causing the issues?</description></item><item><title>Learning Machine Learning with Apache Mahout</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-video-collection262/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 22:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-mahout-video-collection262/</guid><description>Learning Machine Learning with Apache Mahout # Once in a while I get questions like Where to start learning more on machine learning. Other than the official sources I think there is quite good coverage also in the Mahout community: Since it was founded several presentations have been given that give an overview of Apache Mahout, introduce special features or even go into more details on particular implementations. Below is an attempt to create a collection of talks given so far without any claim to contain links to all videos or lectures.</description></item><item><title>Machine learning problem settings</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-problem-settings272/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 07:10:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-problem-settings272/</guid><description>Machine learning problem settings # Together with Sebastian Schelter I held a Nokia sponsored (Thank you!) lecture on large scale data analysis and data mining during the past few months. After supervising a few successful university projects based on Apache Mahout the goal of this lecture was to introduce students to some of the basic concepts and problems encountered today in a world where huge datasets are generally available and are easy to process with Apache Hadoop.</description></item><item><title>Scientific debugging</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scientific-debugging337/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 20:09:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scientific-debugging337/</guid><description>Scientific debugging # Quite some years ago I ready Why programs fail - a systematic guide to debugging - a book written on the art of debugging programs written by Andreas Zeller (Prof. at University Saarbrücken, researcher working on Mining Software Archives, Automated Debugging, Mutation Testing and Mining Models and one of the authors of famous Data Display Debugger).
One aspect that I found particularly intriguing about the book was up to then known to me only from the book Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance: Scientific debugging as a way to find bugs in a piece of software in a structured way with methods usually known from the scientific method.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2010 18:51:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/machine-learning-gossip-meeting-berlin271/</guid><description>Machine Learning Gossip Meeting Berlin # This evening the first Machine Learning Gossip meeting is scheduled to take place at 9p.m. at Victoriabar: Professionals working in research advancing machine learning algorithms and industry projects putting machine learning algorithms to practical use meet for some drinks, food and hopefully lots of interesting discussions.
If successful the meeting is supposed to take place on a regular schedule. Ask Michael Brückner for the date and location of the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 06:38:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</guid><description>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening # This evening at Volkspark Friedrichshain, Café Schoenbrunn the next NoSQL summer Berlin (organised by Tim Lossen) is meeting to discuss the paper on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Dynamo &amp;ldquo;Dynamo: Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Highly Available Key-value Store&amp;rdquo;. The group is planning to meet at 19:30 for some beer and discussions on the publication.</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>Learning to Rank Challenge</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 19:49:53 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-to-rank-challenge263/</guid><description>Learning to Rank Challenge # In one of his recent blog posts, Jeff Dalton published an article on currently running machine learning challenges. Especially interesting for those working on search engines and interested in learning new rankings from data should be the Yahoo! Learning to Rank Challenge to be held in conjunction with this year&amp;rsquo;s ICML 2010 in Haifa, Israel. The goal is to show that your algorithm does not only scale on real-world data provided by Yahoo!</description></item><item><title>MLOSS workshop at ICML accepted</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mloss-workshop-at-icml-accepted285/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 19:31:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mloss-workshop-at-icml-accepted285/</guid><description>MLOSS workshop at ICML accepted # The workshop on machine learning open source software has been accpted. Find further details on the workshop homepage.
Submissions are open until April 10th, Samoa time.</description></item></channel></rss>