<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Camp on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Camp/</link><description>Recent content in Camp on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 22:24:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Camp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mahout at Berlin ignite</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-ignite274/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 22:24:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-ignite274/</guid><description>Mahout at Berlin ignite # This evening the first Berlin ignite event took place in the &amp;ldquo;Festsaal&amp;rdquo; in Berlin X-Berg. Organiser of the event was Matt Biddulph from Nokia Gate 5. We had eleven fantastic talks (ok, to be more precise: At least ten fantastic ones, my own can only be judged by the audience ;) ).
Topics included things you can learn when starting to collect data, themes from (agile) project management, RepRap machines (see also the Rep Rap FOSDEM 2010 talk), bots and robots.</description></item><item><title>Open Community Camp 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2010 13:07:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-community-camp-2010315/</guid><description>Open Community Camp 2010 # The following information just reached my via Marten Vijn. Thought it might be interesting to you:
I am pleased to announce OpenCommunityCamp 2010.
The camp is from 10th to 18th July, in Oegstgeest, the Netherlands.
The website[1] is refreshed and the first speakers are booked.
It is time to register[2] if you plan be there (please do this
quickly). Currently we need to find more people to attend, self-organizing groups</description></item><item><title>On Thursday: Open Hadoop User Group Munich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-thursday-open-hadoop-user-group-munich310/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 06:06:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-thursday-open-hadoop-user-group-munich310/</guid><description>On Thursday: Open Hadoop User Group Munich # If one evening of Apache Hadoop is not enough for you: The next Christmas Meetup in Germany takes place one day later in Munich.
&amp;lt;li
When: Thursday December 17, 2009 at 5:30pm open end
Where: eCircle AG, Nymphenburger Straße 86, 80636 München (&amp;ldquo;Bruckmann&amp;rdquo; Building, &amp;ldquo;U1 Mailinger Str&amp;rdquo;, map in German http://www.ecircle.com/de/kontakt/anfahrt.html and look for the signs)
Talks scheduled by Bob and Lars:</description></item><item><title>NoSQL Berlin Meetup</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-berlin-meetup293/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 13:24:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-berlin-meetup293/</guid><description>NoSQL Berlin Meetup # Yesterday evening the NoSQL Berlin Meetup took place in newthinking store, Berlin Mitte. We had planned for some 50 to 70 people. It quickly became clear that the room would be full - at startup I counted about 80 guests interested in NoSQL topics both locally from Berlin but also traveling here from New York.
Some pictures are available on flickr - thanks to @langalex for sending the url to me:</description></item><item><title>Getting Hadoop trunk up and running from source</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-hadoop-0210-up-and-running-from-source211/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 20:18:27 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-hadoop-0210-up-and-running-from-source211/</guid><description>Getting Hadoop trunk up and running from source # Having told Thilo about the possibility to write Hadoop jobs in Python with Dumbo, we spent some time getting Dumbo 0.21 up and running over the past weekend. The first option the wiki proposes is to take a pre-0.21 release and patch that to work with the current Dumbo release. The second option described takes the not-yet-released version of Hadoop that can be used w/o any patches.</description></item><item><title>Dev House Berlin 2.0</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dev-house-berlin-20152/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 20:04:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dev-house-berlin-20152/</guid><description>Dev House Berlin 2.0 # This weekend DevHouseBerlin took place in the Box119, kindly organized by Jan Lehnardt, sponsored by Upstream and StudiVZ. There were about 30 people gathered in Friedrichshain, hacking and discussing various projects: Mostly Python/ Django, Ruby/ Rails and Erlang people. The first day was reserved for hacking and exchanging ideas. Late afternoon attendees put together a list of talks that were than rated, ranked with the top three chosen for presentation on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>AWS User Group Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/aws-user-group-berlin108/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 16:06:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/aws-user-group-berlin108/</guid><description>AWS User Group Berlin # On Monday the first AWS user group took place in newthinking store, Berlin. The event featured talks by Martin Buhr from Amazon as well as presentations of AWS users like Dawanda, Peritor and Sound Cloud.
Unfortunately the most interesting question concerning Elastic Map Reduce was left unanswered by Martin: Does using EMR facilitate exploiting data locality/ rack locality optimizations that are possible in Hadoop? The question on whether Amazon is using the AWS APIs internally as well was answered positively, though of course they did not publish all of their systems infractructure.</description></item><item><title>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 18:58:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/first-nosql-meetup-in-germany176/</guid><description>First NoSQL Meetup in Germany # On October 22nd 2009 the first NoSQL Meetup Germany is going to take place in newthinking store/ Berlin: http://nosqlberlin.de
Please submit your presentation proposals until September 22nd, accepted speakers will be notified soon after.
If you would like to sponsor the event, feel free to contact us: We would be very happy to provide videos after the event and free drinks for everyone during the event.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 18:41:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-europe-2009-part-118/</guid><description>Apache Con Europe 2009 - part 1 # The past week members, committers and users of Apache software projects gathered in Amsterdam for another Apache Con EU
and to celebrate the 10th birthday of the ASF. One week dedicated to the development and use of Free Software and the Apache Way.
Monday was BarCamp day for me, the first BarCamp I ever attended. Unfortunately not all participants proposed talks. So some of the atmosphere of an unconference was missing.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Camp Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 13:29:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cloud-camp-berlin141/</guid><description>Cloud Camp Berlin # Title: Cloud Camp Berlin
Link out: Click here
Date: 2009-04-30&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;</description></item></channel></rss>