<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>oss on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/oss/</link><description>Recent content in oss on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 17:17:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/oss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Source, InnerSource, CRA?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cra-isc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 17:17:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cra-isc/</guid><description>Open Source, InnerSource, CRA? # A couple days ago on Mastodon I read a post from by Robert Sander (here translated from German): &amp;ldquo;At FrOSCon I got the impression the FLOSS community is aging together. Where are people in their mid-twenties, new people entering the community?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Entering the open source community&amp;rdquo; - what does that even mean? Does it mean creating a public GitHub repo and publishing source code there?</description></item><item><title>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 08:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</guid><description>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe # tl;dr: This post summarises what I learnt at the Adobe Open Source Summit last week about which aspects to think of when running an open source office. It&amp;rsquo;s mainly a mental note for myself, hopefully others will find it useful as well.
Longer version:
This is another post in a series of articles on &amp;ldquo;random stuff I leant in Basel last week&amp;rdquo;. When I was invited to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s open source summit I had no idea what to expect from it.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2014</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:53:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2014 # By now FOSDEM turned into some kind of tradition in our family: Since 2007 every year in February we are travelling to that one comfy B&amp;amp;B in Brussels for a weekend - not to take a closer look at the city but to attend (together with thousands of other geeks and open source hackers) one of the biggest conferences on all things open source. I love the conference concept for scaling: As it happens on a university campus they only have a limited number of huge rooms, but a fairly large number of mid-sized and small rooms.</description></item><item><title>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 20:41:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</guid><description>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04 # The panel started with a bit of history of the AGPL: Born in the age of growing ASP (application service provider) businesses AGPL tried to fix the hosting loop whole in GPL in the early 2000s. More than ten years later it turns out the license hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite caught traction: On the one hand the license does have a few wording issues.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 22:39:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</guid><description>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03 # In the next talk Gervase Markham talked about his experience working for Mozilla on legal and license questions. First the speaker summarized what kind of requests he gets most:
There are lots of technical support requests.
Next on the top list is the question for whether or not shipping Mozilla with a set of modifications is ok.
Next is an internal question, namely: Can I use this code?</description></item><item><title>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:38:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</guid><description>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02 # So the first talk I went to ended up being in the legal dev room on trademarks in open source projects. The speaker had a background mainly in US American trademark law and quite some background when it comes to open source licenses.
To start Pamela first showed a graphic detailing the various types of trademarks: In the pool of generic names there is a large group of trademarks that are in use but not registered.</description></item></channel></rss>