<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/categories/Open-Source/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:13:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/categories/Open-Source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSDEM 2018 - recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2018 - recap # Too crowded, too many queues, too little space - but also lots of friendly people, Belgian waffles, ice cream, an ASF dinner with grey beards and new people, a busy ASF booth, bumping into friends every few steps, meeting humans you see only online for an entire year or more: For me, that&amp;rsquo;s the gist of this year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM.
Note: German version of the article including images appeared in my employer&amp;rsquo;s tech blog.</description></item><item><title>FOSS Backstage - CfP open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 17:21:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</guid><description>FOSS Backstage - CfP open # It&amp;rsquo;s almost ten years ago that I attended my first ApacheCon EU in Amsterdam. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new to the topic of open source or free software. I attended several talks on Apache Lucene, Apache Solr, Hadoop, Tomcat, httpd (I still remember that the most impressive stories didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily come from the project members, but from downstream users. They were the ones authorized to talk publicly about what could be done with the project - and often became committers themselves down the road.</description></item><item><title>Trust and confidence</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trust-and-confidence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 06:48:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trust-and-confidence/</guid><description>Trust and confidence # One of the main principles at Apache (as in The Apache Software Foundation) is &amp;ldquo;Community over Code&amp;rdquo; - having the goal to build projects that survive single community members loosing interest or time to contribute. In his book &amp;ldquo;Producing Open Source Software&amp;rdquo; Karl Fogel describes this model of development as Consensus-based Democracy (in contrast to benevolent dictatorship): &amp;ldquo;Consensus simply means an agreement that everyone is willing to live with.</description></item><item><title>Note to self - slides for staying sane when maintaining a popular open source project</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/note-to-self-slides-for-staying-sane-when-maintaining-a-popular-open-source-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 09:00:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/note-to-self-slides-for-staying-sane-when-maintaining-a-popular-open-source-project/</guid><description>Note to self - slides for staying sane when maintaining a popular open source project # For further reference - Simon MacDonald has a great collection of good advise on how to stay sane when running and maintaining a popular open source project. Link here: http://s.apache.org/sanity
Some things he mentioned:
Include a README. It should tell people what the project is about but also what the project is not about.</description></item><item><title>Async decision making</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/async-decision-making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:45:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/async-decision-making/</guid><description>Async decision making # This is the second in a series of posts on inner source/open source. Bertrand Delacretaz gave an interesting talk on how to avoid meetings by introducing an async way of making decisions.
He started off with a little anecdote related to Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s maker&amp;rsquo;s vs. manager&amp;rsquo;s schedule: Bertrand&amp;rsquo;s father was a carpenter. He was working in the same house that his family was living in, so joining the family for lunch was common for him.</description></item><item><title>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 08:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</guid><description>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe # tl;dr: This post summarises what I learnt at the Adobe Open Source Summit last week about which aspects to think of when running an open source office. It&amp;rsquo;s mainly a mental note for myself, hopefully others will find it useful as well.
Longer version:
This is another post in a series of articles on &amp;ldquo;random stuff I leant in Basel last week&amp;rdquo;. When I was invited to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s open source summit I had no idea what to expect from it.</description></item></channel></rss>