<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>management on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/management/</link><description>Recent content in management on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 08:05:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GeeCon - managing remote projects</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-managing-remote-projects204/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 08:05:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-managing-remote-projects204/</guid><description>GeeCon - managing remote projects # In his talk on visibility in distributed teams Pawel Wrzeszcz motivated why working remotely might be benefitial for both, employees (less commute time, more family time) as well as employers (hiring world wide instead of local, getting more talent in). He then went into more detail on some best practices that worked for his company as well as for himself.
When it comes to managing your energy the trick mainly is to find the right balance between isolating work from private live (by having a separate area in your home, having a daily routine with fixed start and end times) and integrating work into your daily live and loving what you do: The more boring your job is, the less likely you are going to succeed when working remotely.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 08:04:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</guid><description>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly # My second day started with a talk on how to fail projects fast and rapidly. There are a few tricks to do that that relate to different aspects of your project. Lets take a look at each of them in turn.
The first measures to take to fail a project are organisational really: Refer to developers as resources – that will demotivate them and express that they are replaceable instead of being valuable human beings.</description></item><item><title>Coaching self-organising teams</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 21:58:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</guid><description>Coaching self-organising teams # Today, the Scrumtisch organised by Marion Eickmann from Agile 42 met in Berlin Friedrichshain. Though no talk was scheduled for this evening the room was packed with guests from various companies and backgrounds interested in participating in discussions on Scrum.
As usual we started collecting topics (timeboxed to five minutes). The list was rather short, however it contained several interesting pieces:
(6) Management buy-in
(6+) CSP - Certified Scrum Professional - what changes compared to the practitioner?</description></item><item><title>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 18:56:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</guid><description>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg # Last week I attended a discussion meetup with Ken Schwaber in Berlin/ Kreuzberg. The event was scheduled pretty shortly
still quite a few developers and project managers from various companies in Berlin showed up.
Ken started with a brief summary of the history of Scrum: Before there was such a thing as an IT industry programming actually was a lot of fun. But somehow the creative job was turned into something people tend to suffer from pretty quickly as people tried to apply principles from manufacturing industries to software &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>