<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SFO on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/SFO/</link><description>Recent content in SFO on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 04:47:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/SFO/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Being in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 04:47:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</guid><description>Being in San Francisco # I spent the last two weeks together with Thilo in San Francisco - and neighboring areas. I had asked beforehand for recommendations on where to go and what to do, had purchased a &amp;ldquo;Rough Guide to California&amp;rdquo; as well as a &amp;ldquo;Lonely Planet guide for San Francisco&amp;rdquo;. In addition I shared my arrival and departure times with a few people I know here. As to be expected our schedule quickly grew until it exploded, so we ended up doing greedy optimisation stuffing things in and putting them out again while we went along.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 22:18:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-one-afternoon-lectures301/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - day one afternoon lectures # Big data at startups - Info ChimpsAs a startup to get good people there is no other option then to grow your own: Offer the option to gain a lot of experience in return for a not so great wage. Start out with really great hires:
People who have the &amp;quot;get shit done gene&amp;quot;: They discover new projects, are proud to contribute to team efforts, are confident in making changes to a code base probably not known before hand.</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 20:17:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-day-two-keynotes302/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Day two - keynotes # Day two of Strata started with a very inspiring insight from the host itself that extended the vision discussed earlier in the tutorials: It's not at all about the tools, the current data analytics value lies in the data itself and in the conclusions and actions drawn from analysing it.
Bit.ly keynoteThe first key note was presented by bit.ly - for them there are four dimensions to data analytics:</description></item><item><title>O'Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 20:17:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/oreilly-strata-tutorial-data-analytics303/</guid><description>O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Strata - Tutorial data analytics # Acting based on dataIt comes as no surprise to hear that also in the data analytics world engineers are unwilling to share details of how their analysis works with higher management - with on the other side not much interest on learning how analytics really works. This culture leads to a sort of black art, witch craft attitude to data analytics that hinders most innovation.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 20:13:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</guid><description>Teddy in San Francisco # Before attending O'Reilly Strata there were a few days left to adjust to the different time zone, meet up with friends and generally spend some days in the Greater San Francisco area. As was to be expected, those were way to few days. The weekend was a bit rainy, still packed with visiting China town right after the plane had landed and spending some time at .</description></item></channel></rss>