<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>open source on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in open source on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:29:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Netzwerkfr端hst端ck: Open Source in der Verwaltung</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/2025_ossfruehstueck/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:29:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/2025_ossfruehstueck/</guid><description>Netzwerkfr端hst端ck: Open Source in der Verwaltung # Networking breakfast: Open Source in public admin (at German &amp;ldquo;Smart country convention&amp;rdquo; Berlin).
Back in August, in the middle of my vacation, I got an e-mail from plain schwarz asking if I would be willing to give a brief talk at an event they were organising about open source. All I needed to do was get back to them within a week and coordinate in a quick call.</description></item><item><title>Open Source, InnerSource, CRA?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cra-isc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 17:17:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cra-isc/</guid><description>Open Source, InnerSource, CRA? # A couple days ago on Mastodon I read a post from by Robert Sander (here translated from German): &amp;ldquo;At FrOSCon I got the impression the FLOSS community is aging together. Where are people in their mid-twenties, new people entering the community?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Entering the open source community&amp;rdquo; - what does that even mean? Does it mean creating a public GitHub repo and publishing source code there?</description></item><item><title>useful ospo links</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ospo-links/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 02:07:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ospo-links/</guid><description>Some useful OSPO links # https://todogroup.org/ &amp;hellip; TODO group of Linux Foundation generally collecting material around OSPOs and getting people interested in the topic together https://github.com/github/github-ospo/?tab=readme-ov-file &amp;hellip; OSPO policy templates as published by GitHub&amp;rsquo;s OPSO Documentation skeleton &amp;hellip; skeleton for things to document in an OSS project. Quilin &amp;hellip; a starter project template for Open Source, and likely InnerSource, projects Keeping the above here to not loose them when cleaning my open tabs.</description></item><item><title>How hard can it be: Open Source contributions</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-contributions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 12:13:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-contributions/</guid><description>How hard can it be: Open Source contributions # &amp;ldquo;Sharing is caring - if only more downstream users simply contributed to the open source software that they depend upon.&amp;rdquo; - a thought that has crossed my mind more than once in the past decades. Except - for your average software engineer in industry &amp;ldquo;contributing to open source&amp;rdquo; is anything but simple. In addition it&amp;rsquo;s anything but obvious why - on top of daily work - one should commit time to open source.</description></item><item><title>FrOSCon 2018</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:34:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/froscon-2018/</guid><description>FrOSCon 2018 # A more general summary: https://tech.europace.de/froscon-2018/ of the conference written in German. Below a more detailed summary of the keynote by Lorena Jaume-Palasi.
In her keynote &amp;ldquo;Blessed by the algorithm - the computer says no!&amp;rdquo; Lorena detailed the intersection of ethics and technology when it comes to automated decision making systems. As much as humans with a technical training shy away from questions related to ethics, humans trained in ethics often shy away from topics that involve a technical layer.</description></item><item><title>An argument against proxies</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/proxies-considered-harmful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 18:53:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/proxies-considered-harmful/</guid><description>An argument against proxies # Proxies? In companies getting started with an upstream first concept this is what people are called who act as the only interface between their employer and an open source project: All information from any project used internally flows through them. All bug reports and patches intended as upstream contribution also flows through them - hiding entire teams producing the actual contributions.
At Apache projects I learnt to dislike this setup of having proxies act in place of the real contributors.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2018 - recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2018 - recap # Too crowded, too many queues, too little space - but also lots of friendly people, Belgian waffles, ice cream, an ASF dinner with grey beards and new people, a busy ASF booth, bumping into friends every few steps, meeting humans you see only online for an entire year or more: For me, that&amp;rsquo;s the gist of this year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM.
Note: German version of the article including images appeared in my employer&amp;rsquo;s tech blog.</description></item><item><title>FOSS Backstage - CfP open</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 17:21:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/foss-backstage-cfp-open/</guid><description>FOSS Backstage - CfP open # It&amp;rsquo;s almost ten years ago that I attended my first ApacheCon EU in Amsterdam. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely new to the topic of open source or free software. I attended several talks on Apache Lucene, Apache Solr, Hadoop, Tomcat, httpd (I still remember that the most impressive stories didn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily come from the project members, but from downstream users. They were the ones authorized to talk publicly about what could be done with the project - and often became committers themselves down the road.</description></item><item><title>Trust and confidence</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trust-and-confidence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 06:48:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trust-and-confidence/</guid><description>Trust and confidence # One of the main principles at Apache (as in The Apache Software Foundation) is &amp;ldquo;Community over Code&amp;rdquo; - having the goal to build projects that survive single community members loosing interest or time to contribute. In his book &amp;ldquo;Producing Open Source Software&amp;rdquo; Karl Fogel describes this model of development as Consensus-based Democracy (in contrast to benevolent dictatorship): &amp;ldquo;Consensus simply means an agreement that everyone is willing to live with.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit - Day 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:35:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-3/</guid><description>Open Source Summit - Day 3 # Open source summit Wednesday started with a keynote by members of the Banks family telling a packed room on how they approached raising a tech family. The first hurdle that Keila (the teenage daughter of the family) talked about was something I personally had never actually thought about: Communication tools like Slack that are in widespread use come with an age restriction excluding minors.</description></item><item><title>Open source summit - Day 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:58:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-day-2/</guid><description>Open source summit - Day 2 # Day two of Open Source summit for me started a bit slow for lack of sleep. The first talk I went to was on &amp;ldquo;Developer tools for Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; by Michelle Noorali and Matt Butcher. Essentially the two of them showed two projects (Draft and Brigade to help ease development apps for Kubernetes clusters. Draft here is the tool to use for developing long running, daemon like apps.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 13:18:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-source-summit-prague-2017-part-1/</guid><description>Open Source Summit Prague 2017 - part 1 # Open Source Summit, formerly known as LinuxCon, this year took place in Prague. Drawing some 2000 attendees to the lovely Czech city, the conference focussed on all things Linux kernel, containers, community and governance. The first day started with three crowded keynotes: First one by Neha Narkhede on Keynotes Apache Kafka and the Rise of the Streaming Platform. Second one by Reuben Paul (11 years old) on how hacking today really is just childs play: The hack itself might seem like toying around (getting into the protocol of children's toys in order to make them do things without using the app that was intended to control them).</description></item><item><title>Open development and inner source for fun and profit</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-development-and-inner-source-for-fun-and-profit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 09:17:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/open-development-and-inner-source-for-fun-and-profit/</guid><description>Open development and inner source for fun and profit # Last in a row if interesting talks at Adobe Open Source Summit was on Open Development/ Inner Source and how it benefits internal projects given by Michael Marth. Note: He knows there&amp;rsquo;s subtle differences between inner source and open development, but mentioned to use the terms interchangeably in his talk. So what is inner source all about? Essentially: Use all the tools and processes that already work for open source projects, just internally.</description></item><item><title>Async decision making</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/async-decision-making/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 08:45:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/async-decision-making/</guid><description>Async decision making # This is the second in a series of posts on inner source/open source. Bertrand Delacretaz gave an interesting talk on how to avoid meetings by introducing an async way of making decisions.
He started off with a little anecdote related to Paul Graham&amp;rsquo;s maker&amp;rsquo;s vs. manager&amp;rsquo;s schedule: Bertrand&amp;rsquo;s father was a carpenter. He was working in the same house that his family was living in, so joining the family for lunch was common for him.</description></item><item><title>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 08:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notebook-oss-office-at-adobe/</guid><description>Notebook - OSS office at Adobe # tl;dr: This post summarises what I learnt at the Adobe Open Source Summit last week about which aspects to think of when running an open source office. It&amp;rsquo;s mainly a mental note for myself, hopefully others will find it useful as well.
Longer version:
This is another post in a series of articles on &amp;ldquo;random stuff I leant in Basel last week&amp;rdquo;. When I was invited to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s open source summit I had no idea what to expect from it.</description></item><item><title>Talking people into submitting patches - results</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches-results389/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 18:42:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/talking-people-into-submitting-patches-results389/</guid><description>Talking people into submitting patches - results # Back in November I gave a talk at Apache Con NA in Vancouver on talking friends and colleagues into contributing patches to open source projects. The intended audience for this talk were experienced committers to Apache projects, the goal was to learn more on their tricks for talking people into patching. First of all thanks for an interesting discussion on the topic - it was great to get into the room with barely enough slides to fill 10 min and still have a lively discussion 45min later.</description></item><item><title>Some statistics</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-statistics379/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 20:03:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/some-statistics379/</guid><description>Some statistics # Various research projects focus on learning more on how open source communities work:
What makes people commit themselves to such projects?
How much involvement from various companies is there?
Do people contribute during working hours or in their spare time?
Who are the most active contributors in terms of individuals and in terms of companies?
When asked to fill out surveys, especially in cases where that happens for the n-th time with n being larger than say 5, software developers usually are not very likely to fill out these questionairs.</description></item></channel></rss>