<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travelling teddy on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/travelling-teddy/</link><description>Recent content in travelling teddy on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:04:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/travelling-teddy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teddy in London</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-london399/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:04:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-london399/</guid><description>Teddy in London # While I was at the conference – Teddy spent some time exploring the surroundings of the conference hotel. Looks like in particular Hyde park was attractive:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Down Under</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-down-under397/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 20:24:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-down-under397/</guid><description>Teddy in Down Under # The last two September weeks Teddy was in Down Under. He spent the first few days exploring Sydney: Taking the ferry from Manly to the city each morning, followed by beautiful sunny weather, warm enough to already go swimming.
The following days took him to the Blue Mountains and into Kangaroo Valley for some hiking, animal watching and kayaking:
Of course Teddy also made some new friends:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Meißen</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-meisen400/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 20:19:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-meisen400/</guid><description>Teddy in Meißen # Taken earlier this year in Meißen the picture shows a detail of the beautiful cathedral:
Teddy after a busy day:</description></item><item><title>Moving to a new domain</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 12:30:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/moving-to-a-new-domain287/</guid><description>Moving to a new domain # Executive summary: This is to warn those of you who are subscribed to this blog - the domain to reach this blog w/o redirects will soon change to by isabel-drost-fromm.de - you might want to adjust your rss subscription accordingly.
Longer version: This blog post is scheduled to go live some time after lunch-time on September 12th 2012. You might have heart rumors before - that date Ms.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Sweden</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-sweden404/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 19:22:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-sweden404/</guid><description>Teddy in Sweden # Some picture taken all the way up in northern Sweden:
Those picture were taken mid-June. That means what looks like Teddy sitting in the afternoon sun actually was taken 20min before midnight some 40km south of the arctic circle at Camp Frevisören - an incredible spot to start the day on a canoo:
View Larger Map
(That little half-isle that stretches into the ocean.)
If you ever travel that far north, make sure to stop by at Hulkoff.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Zürich</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-zurich405/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 20:20:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-zurich405/</guid><description>Teddy in Zürich # A few beautiful sunny though windy days in Zurich late April:
View from the path between Ütliberg and Adliswil/Felsenegg:
Strolling through the city and sitting next to Zürichsee enjoying the sun afterwards:
A boat trip to Rapperswil - started cold and cloudy, finished warm and sunny:</description></item></channel></rss>