<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ApacheConUS09 on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConUS09/</link><description>Recent content in ApacheConUS09 on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:15:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/ApacheConUS09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ApacheCon Oakland Roundup</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-oakland-roundup88/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 20:15:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apachecon-oakland-roundup88/</guid><description>ApacheCon Oakland Roundup # Two weeks ago ApacheCon US 2009 ended in Oakland California. Shane published a set of links to articles that contain information on what happened at Apache Con. Some of them are officially published by the Apache PRC project, others are write-ups of individuals on which talks they attended and which topics they considered particularly interesting.</description></item><item><title>Apache Con US Wrap Up</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:10:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-con-us-wrap-up24/</guid><description>Apache Con US Wrap Up # some weeks ago I attended ApacheConUS09 in Oakland/ California. In the mean time, videos of one of the sessions have been published online:
You can find a wrap up of the most prominent topics at the conference at heise (unfortunately Germany-only).
By far the largest topics at the conference:
Lucene - there was a meetup with over 100 attendees as well as two main tracks with Lucene focussed talks.</description></item><item><title>Lucene Meetup Oakland</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-meetup-oakland269/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2009 06:05:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/lucene-meetup-oakland269/</guid><description>Lucene Meetup Oakland # Though pretty late in the evening the room is packed with some 100 people. Most of them solr or pure lucene java users. There are quite a few Lucene committers at the meetup from all over the world. Several even have heard about Mahout - some even used it :)
Some introductiory questions to index sizes and query volumn: 1 Mio documents seem pretty standard for Lucene deployments - several people run 10 Mio neither.</description></item><item><title>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2009 21:05:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/hadoop-get-together-berlin-apache-con-us-barcamp222/</guid><description>Hadoop Get Together Berlin @ Apache Con US Barcamp # This is my first real day at ApacheCon US 2009. I arrived yesterday afternoon, was kept awake by three Lucene committers until midnight: &amp;ldquo;Otherwise you will have a very bad jetlag&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Admittedly it did work out: I slept like a baby until about 08:00a.m. the next morning and am not that tired today.
Today Hackthon, Trainings and barcamp Apache happen in parallel.</description></item></channel></rss>