<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apprenticeship patterns on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/apprenticeship-patterns/</link><description>Recent content in apprenticeship patterns on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 08:13:08 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/apprenticeship-patterns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 08:13:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</guid><description>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback. # In recent years demand for shorter feedback cycles especially in software development has increased. Agile development, lean management and even Scrum are all for short feedback cycles: Coming from the dark ages when software projects would last for months or even years before any results could be delivered to customers we are transforming development into a process that integrates the customer in the design and evolution of his own product.</description></item><item><title>Are devs contributing to OSS happier?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 20:18:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</guid><description>Are devs contributing to OSS happier? # When talking to fellow developers or meeting with students it happens from time to time that I get the question of why on earth I spent my freetime working on an open source project? Why do I spend weekends at developers&amp;rsquo; conferences like FOSDEM? Why do spent afternoons organising meetups? Why is it that I am reviewing and writing code after work for free?</description></item><item><title>Apprenticeship patterns (O'Reilly)</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apprenticeship-patterns-oreilly106/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 08:17:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apprenticeship-patterns-oreilly106/</guid><description>Apprenticeship patterns (O&amp;rsquo;Reilly) # A few days ago I finished reading the book &amp;ldquo;Apprenticeship Patterns&amp;rdquo; - Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman, by
Dave Hoover, Adewale Oshineye. The book is addressed to readers who have the goal of becoming great software devleopers.
One naive question one could ask is why there is a need for such a book at all? Students are trained in computer science at university, then enter some IT departement and simply learn from their peers.</description></item></channel></rss>