<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fosdem on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Fosdem/</link><description>Recent content in Fosdem on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:13:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Fosdem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FOSDEM 2018 - recap</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2018-recap/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2018 - recap # Too crowded, too many queues, too little space - but also lots of friendly people, Belgian waffles, ice cream, an ASF dinner with grey beards and new people, a busy ASF booth, bumping into friends every few steps, meeting humans you see only online for an entire year or more: For me, that&amp;rsquo;s the gist of this year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM.
Note: German version of the article including images appeared in my employer&amp;rsquo;s tech blog.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2014</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 14:53:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2014/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2014 # By now FOSDEM turned into some kind of tradition in our family: Since 2007 every year in February we are travelling to that one comfy B&amp;amp;B in Brussels for a weekend - not to take a closer look at the city but to attend (together with thousands of other geeks and open source hackers) one of the biggest conferences on all things open source. I love the conference concept for scaling: As it happens on a university campus they only have a limited number of huge rooms, but a fairly large number of mid-sized and small rooms.</description></item><item><title>Keepers of secrets - FOSDEM 09</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/keepers-of-secrets-fosdem-08256/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 20:49:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/keepers-of-secrets-fosdem-08256/</guid><description>Keepers of secrets - FOSDEM 09 # The closing keynote was given by Leslie Hawthorn whom I had the pleasure of meeting last year during Berlin Buzzwords. In her talk she shared insights into a topic commonly encountered in open source leadership that is way less often talked about than should be the case: Being in the role of a community leader people will talk to you about all sorts of confidential information and ask you to not share that information with other no matter how beneficial that might be for both parties.</description></item><item><title>On making Libre Office suck less – a major refactoring effort - FOSDEM 08</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-making-libre-office-suck-less-a-major-refactoring-effort-fosdem-08307/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 20:47:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/on-making-libre-office-suck-less-a-major-refactoring-effort-fosdem-08307/</guid><description>On making Libre Office suck less – a major refactoring effort - FOSDEM 08 # Libre Office is currently in a phase of code cleanup and refactoring that turns the whole code base upside down. What that means is that people need tooling to avoid quality from going down and allow for new features going in without too much risk. The project made good experiences with using gerrit for code review of patches, tinderbox for fast integration testing, strict whitespace checks to avoid unintended mistakes, use clang compiler plugins.</description></item><item><title>E17 - FOSDEM 07</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/e17-fosdem-07165/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:46:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/e17-fosdem-07165/</guid><description>E17 - FOSDEM 07 # I&amp;rsquo;m really glad the NoSQL room was all packed on afternoon – otherwise I&amp;rsquo;d have missed an amazing talk by people behind Enlightenment – a window manager that is older than Gnome, nearly older than KDE and has been my favourite choice for years and years (simply because they have sensible default configuration options: focus follows mouse, virtual desktops that allow for desktop switching when moving the mouse close to the screen edges, menu opening when clicking anywhere on the desktop background, options for remembering window placement and configuration on re-boot etc).</description></item><item><title>Systemd - FOSDEM 06</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/systemd-fosdem-06387/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 20:45:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/systemd-fosdem-06387/</guid><description>Systemd - FOSDEM 06 # As sort of a “go out of your comfort zone and discover new stuff” exercise I went to the systemd – two years later talk next. It&amp;rsquo;s just plain amazing to see a machine boot in roughly one second (that is not counting the 7s that the BIOS needs for initialization). The whole project started as a init-only project but has since grown to a much larger purpose: An init platform ranging from mobile, embedded, desktop devices to servers many features were just over-due across the board.</description></item><item><title>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 20:43:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/notes-on-storage-options-fosdem-05300/</guid><description>Notes on storage options - FOSDEM 05 # On MySQL
Second day at FOSDEM for me started with the MySQL dev room. One thing that made me smile was in the MySQL new features talk: The speaker announced support for “NoSQL interfaces” to MySQL. That is kind of fun in two dimensions: A) What he really means is support for the memcached interface. Given the vast number of different interfaces to databases today, announcing anything as “supports NoSQL interfaces” sounds kind of silly.</description></item><item><title>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 20:41:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/afero-gpl-panel-discussion-fosdem-047/</guid><description>AFERO GPL Panel discussion - FOSDEM 04 # The panel started with a bit of history of the AGPL: Born in the age of growing ASP (application service provider) businesses AGPL tried to fix the hosting loop whole in GPL in the early 2000s. More than ten years later it turns out the license hasn&amp;rsquo;t quite caught traction: On the one hand the license does have a few wording issues.</description></item><item><title>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 22:39:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mozilla-legal-issues288/</guid><description>Mozilla legal issues - FOSDEM 03 # In the next talk Gervase Markham talked about his experience working for Mozilla on legal and license questions. First the speaker summarized what kind of requests he gets most:
There are lots of technical support requests.
Next on the top list is the question for whether or not shipping Mozilla with a set of modifications is ok.
Next is an internal question, namely: Can I use this code?</description></item><item><title>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:38:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/trademarks-and-oss412/</guid><description>Trademarks and OSS - FOSDEM 02 # So the first talk I went to ended up being in the legal dev room on trademarks in open source projects. The speaker had a background mainly in US American trademark law and quite some background when it comes to open source licenses.
To start Pamela first showed a graphic detailing the various types of trademarks: In the pool of generic names there is a large group of trademarks that are in use but not registered.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2013 - 01</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2013-01188/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 22:38:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2013-01188/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2013 - 01 # On Friday morning our train left for this year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM. Though a bit longish I have a strong preference for going by train as this gives more time and opportunity for hacking (in my case trying out Elastic Search), reading (in my case the book “Team Geek”) and chatting with other FOSDEM visitors.
Monday morning was mostly busy with meeting people - at the FSFE, Debian, Apache Open Office booths, generally in the hallways.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Sunday - smaller bits and pieces</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-sunday-smaller-bits-and-pieces182/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 20:17:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-sunday-smaller-bits-and-pieces182/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Sunday - smaller bits and pieces # With WebODF the Office track featured a very interesting project that focusses on providing a means to open ODF documents in your favourite browser: Content and formatting are converted to a form that can easily be dealt with by using a combination of HTML and CSS. Advanced editing is then supported by using JavaScript.
With Open Stack the following talk focussed on an open cloud stack project that was started by NASA and Rackspace as both simultanously needed support for an open source, openly designed, developed cloud stack that strives for community inclusion.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</guid><description>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging # Nicolas Spiegelberg gave an awesome introduction not only to the architecture that powers Facebook messaging but also to the design decisions behind their use of Apache HBase as a storage backend. Disclaimer: HBase is being used for message storage, for attachements with Haystack a different backend is used.
The reasons to go for HBase include its strong consistency model, support for auto failover, load balancing of shards, support for compression, atomic read-modify-write support and the inherent Map/Reduce support.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Django</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-django179/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 20:17:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-django179/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Django # The languages/ cloud computing track on Sunday started with the good, the bad and the ugly of Django's architecture. Without much ado the speaker started by giving a high level overview of the general package layout of Django - unfortunately not going into too much detail on the architecture itself.
What he loves about Django are the model layer abstractions that really are no ORM only - instead both relational and non-relational databases can be supported easily.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - Saturday</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-saturday181/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 20:17:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-saturday181/</guid><description>FOSDEM - Saturday # Day one at FOSDEM started with a very interesting and timely keynote by Eben Moglen: Starting with the example of Egypt he voted for de-centralized distributed and thus harder to take over communication systems. In terms of tooling we are already almost there. Most use cases like micro blogging, social networking and real time communications can already be implemented in a distributed, fail safe way. So instead of going for convenience it is time to think about digital independence from very few central providers.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM II 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 15:46:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-ii-2011189/</guid><description>FOSDEM II 2011 # It&amp;rsquo;s already sort of a nice little tradition for me to spend the first weekend in February in Brussels for FOSDEM. This year I am particulary happy that there will be a Data Analytics Dev Room at FOSDEM. A huge Thanks to @ogrisel and @nmaillot who have done most of the heavy lifting of getting the schedule in place.
Looking forward to an interesting Cloud Track, to meeting Peter Hintjens who is going to give a talk on 0MQ, the DevOps presentation and lots of very interesting DevRooms.</description></item><item><title>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 06:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/cfp-data-analysis-dev-room-at-fosdem-2011135/</guid><description>CfP: Data Analysis Dev Room at Fosdem 2011 # Call for Presentations: Data Analysis Dev Room, FOSDEM
http://fosdem.org
5 February 2011
1pm to 7pm
Brussels, Belgium
This is to announce the Data Analysis DevRoom co-located with FOSDEM. The first Meetup on analysing and learning from data, taking place in Brussels, Belgium.
Important Dates (all dates in GMT +2):
Submission deadline: 2010-12-17
Notification of accepted speakers: 2010-12-20
Publication of final schedule: 2011-01-10</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - video recordings online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 20:32:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</guid><description>FOSDEM - video recordings online # As published in the FOSDEM blog the video recordings are available online - at least for the main track and the lightning talks. Happy video watching!</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 21:02:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3 # Sunday started in Janson with Andrian Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s talk on RepRap machines, that is devices that can be used as manufacturing devices and are able to replicate themselves. After that I went over to the Mono dev room to listen to Miguel de Icaza on Mono Edge. A great talk on the history of Mono, the way the community interacts with Microsoft, the C# language itself and special features only available in Mono.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:00:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2 # The event itself featured 306 talks - so pretty hard to choose what to watch on two days. This time, not only the main tracks were awesome, but also several dev rooms featured very interesting talks by well known FOSS developers.
Saturday started with a FOSDEM birthday dance done by all attendees. The first keynote speaker Brooks Davis explained his experiences promoting open source methods at a large company.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM visitor seems to like my baby</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-visitor-seems-to-like-my-car190/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 08:19:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-visitor-seems-to-like-my-car190/</guid><description>FOSDEM visitor seems to like my baby # &amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://img.mobypicture.com/72f4dd04dc8f74e0bf9203189744f9ed_view.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;Posted using Mobypicture.com&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
Another picture that was taken before the first session early in the morning:</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 21:00:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1 # Four years ago I was working in Saarbrücken. From there it is a very short ride over to FOSDEM (little more than 300km). So I decided - hey, why not stay there for a weekend. I found a very nice Brussels bed and breakfast hotel called Rovignon - featuring not only comfortable rooms at reasonable prizes but also cats in the house.
Back then, I barely knew anyone at the conference.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 09:19:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-201040/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">
Apache Hadoop at FOSDEM 2010
&lt;a class="anchor" href="#apache-hadoop-at-fosdem-2010">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Though the official schedule is not yet online: I will be giving an introductory talk about Apache Hadoop at next
year&amp;rsquo;s FOSDEM (Free and Open Source Developer European Meeting) in Brussles. This will be the 10th birthday of the
event - looking forward to a fun event, meeting other free and open source software developers from all over
Europe.&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;center>&lt;br>&lt;img src="http://fosdem.org/2010/promo/fosdem">&lt;br>&lt;/center>&lt;br>&lt;br>If you are a Apache
Hadoop developer and would like me to include some particular topic in the talk - please feel free to contact me. If
you are an Apache Hadoop user and would like to learn more on the project, please come to the talk and ask questions.
If you are an Apache Hadoop Newbie - feel free to join us.&lt;br>&lt;br>In addition there will be a NoSQL Dev Room at FOSDEM
as well. The call for presentations is up already. So if you are doing fun stuff with CouchDB, HBase and friends or are
a developer of these projects - submit a talk and join us in early-February in Brussles.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>