<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vacation on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/vacation/</link><description>Recent content in vacation on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:59:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/vacation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 19:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/reasons-for-you-to-visit-berlin-buzzwords329/</guid><description>Reasons for you to visit Berlin Buzzwords # I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of several people who are not quite sure yet whether they should visit Berlin Buzzwords or not - in particular when having to travel far and cross 9 time zones to attend. My general recommendation is to plan to spend some more days in Europe. The conference is conveniently scheduled on Monday and Tuesday which gives you one weekend before to explore the city and the whole week afterwards to go and see more either in the city or around.</description></item><item><title>Being in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 04:47:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</guid><description>Being in San Francisco # I spent the last two weeks together with Thilo in San Francisco - and neighboring areas. I had asked beforehand for recommendations on where to go and what to do, had purchased a &amp;ldquo;Rough Guide to California&amp;rdquo; as well as a &amp;ldquo;Lonely Planet guide for San Francisco&amp;rdquo;. In addition I shared my arrival and departure times with a few people I know here. As to be expected our schedule quickly grew until it exploded, so we ended up doing greedy optimisation stuffing things in and putting them out again while we went along.</description></item><item><title>Dear lazy web: Travel recommendations</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dear-lazy-web-travel-recommendations147/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 21:21:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dear-lazy-web-travel-recommendations147/</guid><description>Dear lazy web: Travel recommendations # Finally getting to spend some days of vacation in the bay area soon - so I thought I might try to leverage the lazy web on recommendations on what not to miss while there. So far on our list:
Rent a canoo in Sausalito
Take a tour to Alcatras
Get to drive down along the coast towards Half Moon Bay
Spend one or two days strolling through the city to take photos</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Portugal</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 20:32:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</guid><description>Teddy in Portugal # During the past two weeks my teddy was on vacation. As destination he chose to fly to Portugal. One day was reserved for a visit to Lisboa, the capital city of the country. He also took a few really nice pictures there:
On his return, he was no longer alone. Seems like he found a cute little portugese girl friend:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/teddyGirlFriend.png&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
In addition he brought the following image.</description></item><item><title>Bye, bye Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bye-bye-germany131/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 15:27:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bye-bye-germany131/</guid><description>Bye, bye Germany # &amp;hellip; for the next two weeks: I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation with strict internet interdiction. Will be a tourist exploring beaches and maybe a few hiking tracks in the next few days, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect to read anything here apart from what was scheduled already ;)</description></item></channel></rss>