<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>German on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/German/</link><description>Recent content in German on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:38:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/German/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visiting the Bundestag</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bundestag/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 15:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bundestag/</guid><description>Visiting (and speaking at) the German Bundestag # Many, many years ago, I invited Berlin Buzzwords keynote speakers to join me for lunch pre-conference. For the view – and the impact of the location – I reserved a table at the restaurant that is located atop the Reichstags-building here in Berlin. If back then anyone had told me that one day I’d get an invitation to speak as an expert in the committee for digital issues of the German Bundestag, I wouldn’t have believed a single word!</description></item><item><title>Learning German in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-english/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 17:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-english/</guid><description>Learning German in Berlin # So you have been living in Berlin for a while, maybe even for years – but you fail to speak German fluently. It may feel weird switching to German even with friends, as your English gives you many more options to speak proficiently, to be precise when talking. People around you speak better English than you speak German.
One thing to remember: While Berlin is easy to navigate speaking only English, if you stay here for more than a couple of weeks you really truly do want to start training your German language skills: Emergency information – typically first available and more detailed in German.</description></item><item><title>Learning German</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 08:07:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/learning-german261/</guid><description>Learning German # For some reason I got that question multiple times now from people that moved to Germany but work in companies where English is the language to use for communication - how to best learn German (in addition finding people to talk to).
When thinking about how I got started with English there were a few things that helped: As a child I got some &amp;ldquo;made for learning English&amp;rdquo; crime stories to read.</description></item></channel></rss>