<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>antwerp on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/antwerp/</link><description>Recent content in antwerp on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 21:30:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/antwerp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teddy in Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 21:30:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</guid><description>Teddy in Antwerp # When at Devoxx Teddy went to the city taking a few pictures of the Grote Markt, the Haven as well as the main train station.</description></item><item><title>Apache Lunch Devoxx</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 21:30:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-lunch-devoxx62/</guid><description>Apache Lunch Devoxx # On Twitter I suggested to host an Apache dinner during Devoxx. Matthias Wesendorf of Apache MyFaces was so kind to take up the discussion carrying it over to the Apache community mailing-list. It quickly turned out that there was quite some interest with several members and committers attending Devoxx. We scheduled the meetup for Friday after the conference during lunch time.
I pinged a few Apache related people I knew would attend the conference (being a speaker and a committer at some Apache project almost certainly resulted in getting a ping).</description></item><item><title>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 21:17:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-university-productive-programmer-hbase161/</guid><description>Devoxx University – Productive programmer, HBase # The first day at Devoxx featured several tutorials – most interesting to me was the pragramatic programmer. The speaker also is the author of the equally named book at O&amp;rsquo;Reilly. The book was the result of the observation that developers today are more and more IDE bound, no longer able to use the command line effectively. The result are developers that are unnecessarily slow when creating software.</description></item><item><title>Devoxx Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 21:16:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/devoxx-antwerp153/</guid><description>Devoxx Antwerp # With 3000 attendees Devoxx is the largest Java Community conference world-wide. Each year in autumn it takes place in Antwerp/ Belgium, in recent years in the Metropolis cinema. The conference tickets were sold out long before doors were opened this year.
The focus of the presentations are mainly on enterprise Java featuring talks by famous Joshua Bloch, Mark Reihnhold and others on new features of the upcoming JDK release as well as intricacies of the Java programming language itself.</description></item></channel></rss>