<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TU Berlin on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/TU-Berlin/</link><description>Recent content in TU Berlin on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 12:55:07 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/TU-Berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teaching Free Software Development</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 12:55:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teaching-free-software-development390/</guid><description>Teaching Free Software Development # In Summer last year I was invited to give a presentation on Apache Mahout at TU Berlin. After the talk was over some of the research group members asked me to design and give a course on scalable machine learning with open source software during the winter semester.
The project attracted four to five students - not very many - but then again it is a course people can take voluntarily.</description></item><item><title>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 21:10:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/seminar-on-scaling-learning-at-dima-tu-berlin364/</guid><description>Seminar on scaling learning at DIMA TU Berlin # Last Thursday the seminar on scaling learning problems took place at DIMA at TU Berlin. We had five students give talks.
The talks started with an introduction to map reduce. Oleg Mayevskiy first explained the basic concept, than gave an overview of the parallelization architecture and finally showed how jobs can be formulated as map reduce jobs.
His paper as well as his slides are available online.</description></item><item><title>With a little help from my friends</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 23:55:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/with-a-little-help-from-my-friends435/</guid><description>With a little help from my friends # The end of the year 2009 is quickly approaching. To me it feels a little like it ran away far too quickly. So instead of taking part in the annual review of past events, I would like to use it as an opportunity to say thank you: The past twelve months were a lot of fun with lots of interesting, nice people from all over the world.</description></item><item><title>Mahout@TU WS 09/10</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 23:08:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/mahouttu-ws-0910282/</guid><description>Mahout@TU WS 09/10 # Title: Mahout@TU WS 09/10
There is going to be a project/seminar course at TU Berlin on Apache Mahout. The goal is to introduce students to the work on a free software project, interact with the community and build production ready software.
Students will be given several potential tasks ranging from optimizing existing implementations, implementing new algorithms and (depending on their prior knowledge) improving, scaling and parallelizing existing algorithms.</description></item><item><title>DIMA @ TU Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dima-tu-berlin162/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2009 07:26:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dima-tu-berlin162/</guid><description>DIMA @ TU Berlin # On Friday, the 24th of April Prof. Volker Markl organised a Welcome Workshop at TU Berlin. The day started with an introduction by the Dekan of the faculty. First talk was given by Rudolf Bayer on the topic &amp;ldquo;From B-Trees to UB-Trees&amp;rdquo;. Second presentation was by Guy Lohman on &amp;ldquo;LEO, DB2&amp;rsquo;s Learning Optimizer&amp;rdquo;.
After the coffee break, Volker Markl gave an introduction to his selected research field, outstanding tasks and the way he is going to accomplish his goals.</description></item></channel></rss>