<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Freetime on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Freetime/</link><description>Recent content in Freetime on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 04:47:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Freetime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Being in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 04:47:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/being-in-san-francisco111/</guid><description>Being in San Francisco # I spent the last two weeks together with Thilo in San Francisco - and neighboring areas. I had asked beforehand for recommendations on where to go and what to do, had purchased a &amp;ldquo;Rough Guide to California&amp;rdquo; as well as a &amp;ldquo;Lonely Planet guide for San Francisco&amp;rdquo;. In addition I shared my arrival and departure times with a few people I know here. As to be expected our schedule quickly grew until it exploded, so we ended up doing greedy optimisation stuffing things in and putting them out again while we went along.</description></item><item><title>One Ring to rule them all</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/one-ring-to-rule-them-all313/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 19:23:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/one-ring-to-rule-them-all313/</guid><description>One Ring to rule them all # One Ring to find them
One Ring to bring them all and in the darkness bind them:</description></item><item><title>Dear lazy web: Travel recommendations</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dear-lazy-web-travel-recommendations147/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 21:21:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dear-lazy-web-travel-recommendations147/</guid><description>Dear lazy web: Travel recommendations # Finally getting to spend some days of vacation in the bay area soon - so I thought I might try to leverage the lazy web on recommendations on what not to miss while there. So far on our list:
Rent a canoo in Sausalito
Take a tour to Alcatras
Get to drive down along the coast towards Half Moon Bay
Spend one or two days strolling through the city to take photos</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Amsterdam</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam391/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 20:16:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam391/</guid><description> Teddy in Amsterdam # On his trip from SFO back to Europe teddy spent a few days in Amsterdam. He brought back the following pictures of bikes, cheese and the canals: Going to Amsterdam usually is pretty darn dangerous: I tend to return with some toys added to my collection of puzzles. Somehow I tend to be drawn to the shop called Gamekeeper selling them even when I do not remember the exact address or even just the street name:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Brussels</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-brussels395/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 20:16:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-brussels395/</guid><description>Teddy in Brussels # Not much time here, except for a brief view of the atomium from our bed&amp;amp;breakfast place in Brussels and a few very beautiful churches:</description></item><item><title>Teddy in San Francisco</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 20:13:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-san-francisco403/</guid><description>Teddy in San Francisco # Before attending O'Reilly Strata there were a few days left to adjust to the different time zone, meet up with friends and generally spend some days in the Greater San Francisco area. As was to be expected, those were way to few days. The weekend was a bit rainy, still packed with visiting China town right after the plane had landed and spending some time at .</description></item><item><title>White Christmas</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/white-christmas432/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 16:44:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/white-christmas432/</guid><description>White Christmas # Christmas brought &amp;ldquo;a little surprise&amp;rdquo; to Germany last night:
The result this morning: a few cm (as in about 20) of snow - that is a white christmas everyone had been looking forward to. Just one question: Where to put all that snow when digging out my car? ;)
Thanks to snow clearing services streets are all white but well drivable. Other than that lots of time for enjoying the white weather.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Antwerp</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 21:30:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-antwerp393/</guid><description>Teddy in Antwerp # When at Devoxx Teddy went to the city taking a few pictures of the Grote Markt, the Haven as well as the main train station.</description></item><item><title>Frau Holle, Frau Holle</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/frau-holle-frau-holle192/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 18:32:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/frau-holle-frau-holle192/</guid><description>Frau Holle, Frau Holle # Winter arrived in Germany - below a few pictures I took last Thursday morning:
Seems like this season winter is trying real hard to prove that I am wrong saying that there is no real winter in Berlin with just about a week snow on the streets ;) Guess its time to get the tires with spikes back on my bike.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 21:11:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-amsterdam-schiphol392/</guid><description>Teddy in Amsterdam Schiphol # Caught Teddy just before the plane took off:</description></item><item><title>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 08:13:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</guid><description>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback. # In recent years demand for shorter feedback cycles especially in software development has increased. Agile development, lean management and even Scrum are all for short feedback cycles: Coming from the dark ages when software projects would last for months or even years before any results could be delivered to customers we are transforming development into a process that integrates the customer in the design and evolution of his own product.</description></item><item><title>Salsa steps</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/salsa-steps334/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 20:50:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/salsa-steps334/</guid><description>Salsa steps # If you always wanted to start learning Salsa and never really had the time to do so: Today a new beginners&amp;rsquo; course starts at Salsa Con Corazon in Berlin Schöneberg. The course is still open for registration teaching the very basics in four sessions - one per week.</description></item><item><title>A Get Together Checklist</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/a-get-together-checklist4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 19:38:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/a-get-together-checklist4/</guid><description>A Get Together Checklist # Still on the list of potentially interesting books: The Checklist Manifesto - explaining why checklists can still be valuable - especially for complex problems and tasks.
Though not very complex, I chose to come up with a checklist for running a Hadoop Get Together in Berlin as an exercise. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to stick with advise provided by the Checklist for Checklists.
Parties involved
Find two to three speakers two months in advance.</description></item><item><title>Are devs contributing to OSS happier?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 20:18:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/are-devs-contribution-to-oss-happier107/</guid><description>Are devs contributing to OSS happier? # When talking to fellow developers or meeting with students it happens from time to time that I get the question of why on earth I spent my freetime working on an open source project? Why do I spend weekends at developers&amp;rsquo; conferences like FOSDEM? Why do spent afternoons organising meetups? Why is it that I am reviewing and writing code after work for free?</description></item><item><title>Part 3: A polite way to say no - and why there are times when it does not work.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-3-a-polite-way-to-say-no-and-why-there-are-times-when-it-doesnot-work323/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 23:05:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-3-a-polite-way-to-say-no-and-why-there-are-times-when-it-doesnot-work323/</guid><description>Part 3: A polite way to say no - and why there are times when it does not work. # After having shared my thoughts on how to improve focus and how to track tasks eating up time this post will explain how to keep time invested at a more or less constant level. The goal of this exercise is to keep obligations at a reasonable level - be it at work or during ones spare time.</description></item><item><title>Part 2: Tracking tasks, or - Where the hack did my time go to last week?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-2-tracking-tasks-or-where-the-hack-did-my-time-go-to-last-week322/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 18:22:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-2-tracking-tasks-or-where-the-hack-did-my-time-go-to-last-week322/</guid><description>Part 2: Tracking tasks, or - Where the hack did my time go to last week? # After summarising some strategies for not loosing track of tasks, meetings and conferences in the last post, this one is going to focus on the retrospect on achievements. If at some point in time you have asked yourself &amp;ldquo;Where the hack did time go to?&amp;rdquo; - maybe after two busy weeks of work this article might have a few techniques for you.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner DUS</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 19:10:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-dus33/</guid><description>Apache Dinner DUS # the evening after FrOSCon - that is on August 22nd 2010 at 7:30p.m. CEST - a combined &amp;ldquo;FSFE Fellowship meetup/ Apache dinner*&amp;rdquo; takes place in Tigges in Düsseldorf (Brunnenstraße 1, at Bilker S-Bahnhof). Given it doesn&amp;rsquo;t rain, we&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting outside.
Would be great to meet you there for tasty food, interesting discussions on Apache in general, as well as projects like Lucene, Hadoop or Tomcat in particular.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 06:38:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/nosql-summer-berlin-this-evening294/</guid><description>NoSQL summer Berlin - this evening # This evening at Volkspark Friedrichshain, Café Schoenbrunn the next NoSQL summer Berlin (organised by Tim Lossen) is meeting to discuss the paper on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Dynamo &amp;ldquo;Dynamo: Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Highly Available Key-value Store&amp;rdquo;. The group is planning to meet at 19:30 for some beer and discussions on the publication.</description></item><item><title>Part 1: Travelling minds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:00:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</guid><description>Part 1: Travelling minds # In the last post I promised to share some more information on techniques I came across and found useful under an increasing work load. Instead of taking a close look at my professional calendar I decided to use my private one as an example - first because spare time is even more precious then working hours, simply because there is so few of it and secondly because I am free to publicly scrutinize not only the methods for keeping it in good shape but also the entries in it.</description></item><item><title>Series: Getting things done</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 07:07:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</guid><description>Series: Getting things done # Probably not too unusual for people working on free software mostly (though no longer exclusively) in their spare time, the number of items that appear in my private calendar have increased steadily in the past months and years:
Every three months I am organising the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin.
I have been asked (and accepted the offer) to publish articles on Hadoop and Lucene in magazines.</description></item><item><title>Teddy in Portugal</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 20:32:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/teddy-in-portugal401/</guid><description>Teddy in Portugal # During the past two weeks my teddy was on vacation. As destination he chose to fly to Portugal. One day was reserved for a visit to Lisboa, the capital city of the country. He also took a few really nice pictures there:
On his return, he was no longer alone. Seems like he found a cute little portugese girl friend:
&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;/teddyGirlFriend.png&amp;quot; width=&amp;ldquo;400&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
In addition he brought the following image.</description></item><item><title>Bye, bye Germany</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bye-bye-germany131/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 15:27:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/bye-bye-germany131/</guid><description>Bye, bye Germany # &amp;hellip; for the next two weeks: I&amp;rsquo;ll be on vacation with strict internet interdiction. Will be a tourist exploring beaches and maybe a few hiking tracks in the next few days, so don&amp;rsquo;t expect to read anything here apart from what was scheduled already ;)</description></item><item><title>Service as in real good customer service</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/service-as-in-real-good-customer-service368/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2010 08:07:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/service-as-in-real-good-customer-service368/</guid><description>Service as in real good customer service # First thing to do after getting up: Go to the kitchen and switch on the coffee machine. However, one random Sunday morning that caused the fuse for exactly this kitchen to go off. After fixing that we turned on the coffee machine again - trying to finally get a first cup. All worked well until having a closer look at what the machine produced as coffee: It was cold!</description></item><item><title>Solving puzzles</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solving-puzzles377/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 16:44:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/solving-puzzles377/</guid><description>Solving puzzles # Like most software developers I like tasks that involve solving more or less complex problems analytically. Most developers I know love puzzles - either those that involve dis-entangling metal rings, or those involving putting wooden pieces back into order, or even solving Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube:
Working on the schedule for Berlin Buzzwords, I noticed that coming up with a good schedule actually has a lot more in common with solving puzzles that one is usually aware of: First of all talks on similar or related topics should not take place at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Tierpark Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tierpark-berlin410/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 19:36:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tierpark-berlin410/</guid><description>Tierpark Berlin # I love taking fotos, like being outdoors and like animals. Living in a large city, it is not exactly easy to get in touch with donkeys or sheep. A very simple way to combine all three preferences here is to visit Tierpark Berlin. Being larger than your average zoo, most bawns are rather roomy with lots space outside and inside.
Little more than one year ago I received a great birthday present from Thilo: It is possible to purchase a one year ticket for that park.</description></item><item><title>Getting a Ubuntu Laptop setup for my Mum</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-a-ubuntu-laptop-setup-for-my-mum210/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 19:15:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/getting-a-ubuntu-laptop-setup-for-my-mum210/</guid><description>Getting a Ubuntu Laptop setup for my Mum # With DSL contracts getting ever cheaper in recent years in Germany – even outside larger cities – my mom decided to get a faster internet connection (compared to the former 56k modem) including a telephone landline flatrate.
As sitting in the garden while surfing the internet is way cooler than only having a dedicated computer in an office we decided to get a notebook while at it.</description></item><item><title>Definition of a Blogger</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/definition-of-a-blogger150/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 19:17:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/definition-of-a-blogger150/</guid><description>Definition of a Blogger # While at lunch yesterday the topic of what Bloggers do, how they earn money and most important of all - what the hack a blogger really is - came up. Well, some criteria those who went to a restaurant nearby came up with the following criteria:
Blog is read by more than 5 people. (Well, in my opinion a very low barrier, really.)
Bloggers tend to get invited to give talks at conferences.</description></item><item><title>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 19:13:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/preliminary-schedule-online-for-ignite-berlin326/</guid><description>Preliminary schedule online for ignite Berlin # Today first talks scheduled for ignite Berlin were published. If you yourself would like to give a talk: Submission seems to still be open.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - video recordings online</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 20:32:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-video-recordings-online183/</guid><description>FOSDEM - video recordings online # As published in the FOSDEM blog the video recordings are available online - at least for the main track and the lightning talks. Happy video watching!</description></item><item><title>FSFE Happy Valentine</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-happy-valentine200/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 07:05:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fsfe-happy-valentine200/</guid><description>FSFE Happy Valentine # Today I got woken up with a friendly hug and roses waiting for me:
I do not really care about presents for sort-of-artificial celebration days like valentines day. However, FSFE had a very nice idea: The proposal was to use valentines day to show your love for free software. The website proposed to e.g. hug a free software developer, to make a gift to a team of free software developers:</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 21:02:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-3187/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 3 # Sunday started in Janson with Andrian Bowyer&amp;rsquo;s talk on RepRap machines, that is devices that can be used as manufacturing devices and are able to replicate themselves. After that I went over to the Mono dev room to listen to Miguel de Icaza on Mono Edge. A great talk on the history of Mono, the way the community interacts with Microsoft, the C# language itself and special features only available in Mono.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 21:00:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-2186/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 2 # The event itself featured 306 talks - so pretty hard to choose what to watch on two days. This time, not only the main tracks were awesome, but also several dev rooms featured very interesting talks by well known FOSS developers.
Saturday started with a FOSDEM birthday dance done by all attendees. The first keynote speaker Brooks Davis explained his experiences promoting open source methods at a large company.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM visitor seems to like my baby</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-visitor-seems-to-like-my-car190/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 08:19:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-visitor-seems-to-like-my-car190/</guid><description>FOSDEM visitor seems to like my baby # &amp;lt;img src=&amp;ldquo; http://img.mobypicture.com/72f4dd04dc8f74e0bf9203189744f9ed_view.jpg" alt=&amp;ldquo;Posted using Mobypicture.com&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
Another picture that was taken before the first session early in the morning:</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 21:00:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-2010-part-1185/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2010 - part 1 # Four years ago I was working in Saarbrücken. From there it is a very short ride over to FOSDEM (little more than 300km). So I decided - hey, why not stay there for a weekend. I found a very nice Brussels bed and breakfast hotel called Rovignon - featuring not only comfortable rooms at reasonable prizes but also cats in the house.
Back then, I barely knew anyone at the conference.</description></item><item><title>Apache Dinner January 2010</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 22:48:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-dinner-january-201034/</guid><description>Apache Dinner January 2010 # This evening in X-Berg several local committers met for the second &amp;ldquo;Apache Dinner&amp;rdquo; - an informal gathering of local Apache committers, friends and associates for food, beer and interesting discussions. Next one is probably to be scheduled some time in February. Feel free to send a message to Torsten Curdt to be included on the next invitation mail. Thanks for organizing a nice evening, Torsten.</description></item><item><title>Screws are out</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/screws-are-out338/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2009 16:45:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/screws-are-out338/</guid><description> Screws are out # Before:Some time in between:After:
On December 22nd those screws got taken out of my knee: Early in the morning (early as in arrive at 6:45am) I was to be at the hospital. In return I was allowed to go home the same day in the afternoon: Finally some time for reading and refining MAHOUT-85 ;)</description></item><item><title>Winter arrived at Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-arrived-at-berlin434/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 20:10:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-arrived-at-berlin434/</guid><description>Winter arrived at Berlin # Finally winter seems to have arrived at Berlin as well:
Looks a little like Christmas is drawing closer. Only disadvantage of the weather: One of the breaks of my bike was frozen after very few minutes. Luckily for me, my bike has one of those old-fashioned back pedal brakes ;)</description></item><item><title>Photos the traditional way</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/photos-the-traditional-way325/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 21:05:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/photos-the-traditional-way325/</guid><description>Photos the traditional way # After one year of taking pictures at various occasions and at various places the pile of photos grew frighteningly large:
I am not counting the images taken at Apache Con US Oakland - they are not yet developed. All other photos were taken either with an old fashioned Olympus µ-zoom or a Praktica Nova 1st.
Several hours of work later, I ended up with one more book containing memories of an exciting year&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>"Schneeflöckchen, Weißröckchen"</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-finally2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 09:23:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/winter-finally2/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Schneeflöckchen, Weißröckchen&amp;rdquo; # First snow seen this morning - seems like finally it&amp;rsquo;s winter:</description></item><item><title>Berlin hospital chaos (Charite)</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hospital-chaos-charite121/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 08:05:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-hospital-chaos-charite121/</guid><description>Berlin hospital chaos (Charite) # What getting screws out of your knee looks like at Charite: Got sent to &amp;ldquo;Virchow Klinikum&amp;rdquo; by my doctor back home: I got some recommendations for it from my colleagues and is easy to reach for me. Called up there earlier this week and got an appointment for today at 8:30 a.m. (was already wondering, that this was possible so quickly). Arrived this morning: But seems like I was out of luck - no one at the hospital knew about the appointment.</description></item><item><title>katta @ Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/katta-berlin255/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 20:46:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/katta-berlin255/</guid><description>katta @ Berlin # After finishing the slides for next week&amp;rsquo;s Mahout course at TU Berlin (if you are not subscribed yet: Subscribe now!) I spent half of the day in Tierpark Berlin: Watching ice-bears, taking pictures of tigers. On my way through the park I met those cute little guys:
The plate next to the bawn gave them away as &amp;hellip; kattas - so that is what they look like!</description></item><item><title>Looking for a dancing school in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/looking-for-a-dancing-school-in-berlin266/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 20:23:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/looking-for-a-dancing-school-in-berlin266/</guid><description>Looking for a dancing school in Berlin # I am looking for a dancing school (standard as well as Salsa Cubana) in Berlin Schöneberg. So in case you have any recommendations - please leave a comment.</description></item><item><title>Two days on Rügen</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/two-days-on-rugen415/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 15:50:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/two-days-on-rugen415/</guid><description>Two days on Rügen # Below: Sunday morning on Rügen, feet in the East Sea. It looks colder than it actually was: Air was about 17 °C, but the water was fine. At least for my feet.
Thanks to the colleague who sold two spare tickets for the Störtebecker Festspiele last Thursday and caused us to drive to isle Rügen yesterday afternoon.</description></item></channel></rss>