<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scrum on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Scrum/</link><description>Recent content in Scrum on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 08:05:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Scrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GeeCon - managing remote projects</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-managing-remote-projects204/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 08:05:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-managing-remote-projects204/</guid><description>GeeCon - managing remote projects # In his talk on visibility in distributed teams Pawel Wrzeszcz motivated why working remotely might be benefitial for both, employees (less commute time, more family time) as well as employers (hiring world wide instead of local, getting more talent in). He then went into more detail on some best practices that worked for his company as well as for himself.
When it comes to managing your energy the trick mainly is to find the right balance between isolating work from private live (by having a separate area in your home, having a daily routine with fixed start and end times) and integrating work into your daily live and loving what you do: The more boring your job is, the less likely you are going to succeed when working remotely.</description></item><item><title>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 08:04:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/geecon-failing-software-projects-fast-and-rapidly203/</guid><description>GeeCon - failing software projects fast and rapidly # My second day started with a talk on how to fail projects fast and rapidly. There are a few tricks to do that that relate to different aspects of your project. Lets take a look at each of them in turn.
The first measures to take to fail a project are organisational really: Refer to developers as resources – that will demotivate them and express that they are replaceable instead of being valuable human beings.</description></item><item><title>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 20:34:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/february-2012-apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin171/</guid><description>February 2012 Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin # The upcoming Apache Hadoop Get-Together is scheduled for 22. February, 6 p.m. - taking place at Axel Springer, Axel-Springer-Str. 65, 10888 Berlin. Thanks to Springer for sponsoring the location!
Note: It is important to indicate attendance. Due to security restrictions at the venue only registered visitors will be permitted. Get your ticket here: https://www.xing.com/events/hadoop-22-02-859807
Talks scheduled thus far:
Markus Andrezak : &amp;ldquo;Queue Management in Product Development with Kanban - enabling flow and fast feedback along the value chain&amp;rdquo; - It&amp;rsquo;s a truism today that fast feedback from your market is a key advantage.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin357/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 23:10:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin357/</guid><description>Scrumtisch Berlin # After quite some time off I went to the Scrumtisch Berlin. The event was incredibly well visited - roughly 50 people filled the upper floor at Cafe Hundertwasser. Today&amp;rsquo;s event was organised such that participants first collected discussion topics, prioritised them together and then discussed the top three items in a timebox of 15 minutes each.
Topics collected were:
Best tricks to make teams self organised (20 votes)</description></item><item><title>Scrum done wrong</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-done-wrong-scrum-done-wrong-scrum-done-wrong343/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 06:39:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-done-wrong-scrum-done-wrong-scrum-done-wrong343/</guid><description>Scrum done wrong # “Agile and Lean have a single purpose: to continually challenge the status quo. If you’re not doing that, you’re probably an impediment to it.” agile42.com
Judging from the way some people become overly careful when discussing agile in general and Scrum in particular in my presence I seem to slowly have built up a reputation for being a strong proponent of these methods. Given the large number of flaky implementations as well as misunderstandings it seems to have become fashionable to blame Scrum for all badness and dismiss it altogether - up to the point where developers are proud to finally having abandoned Scrum completely - so that now they can work in iterations, accept new tasks only for upcoming but not for the current iteration, develop in a test-driven way, have daily sync meetings, mark tasks done only when they are delivered to and accepted by the customer, have regular “how to improve our work” meetings, estimate tasks in story points and only plan for as much work per iteration as was done in the past iteration</description></item><item><title>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 21:38:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/design-thinking-scrumtisch-berlin151/</guid><description>Design Thinking @ Scrumtisch Berlin # This evening Mary Poppendieck gave a presentation on Design Thinking in Berlin. &amp;ldquo;What does the US Military have in common with Apple?&amp;rdquo; In her talk Mary went into more detail about how increasing complexity calls for a need to rethink design. Slides are available online. Thanks for sharing them.
Mary started with a question for the audience on who in your company decides what is to be developed: Is it the PO?</description></item><item><title>Berlin Scrumtisch - February 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-february-2011122/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 21:33:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-february-2011122/</guid><description>Berlin Scrumtisch - February 2011 # The February Scrumtisch Berlin featured a talk by Lyssa Adkins, famously known for her publications on Coaching Agile teams. A mixture of fifty developers, scrum masters, coaches and product owner as well as one project manager followed Marion Eikmann&amp;rsquo;s invitation. Thanks for organising the event, as well as thank you to Hypoport for providing the venue.
In her one-hour presentation she mainly focussed on two core topics: On the roles agile coaches have to fullfill as well as on the skill set needed by agile coaches.</description></item><item><title>Christmas Scrumtisch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/christmas-scrumtisch138/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 22:59:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/christmas-scrumtisch138/</guid><description>Christmas Scrumtisch # Today the last Scrumtisch Berlin in 2010 took place in Friedrichshain. Thanks to Marion Eickmann and Andrea Tomasini for organising the Scrum user group regularly for the past years.
Though no presentation had been scheduled ahead of time the Scrumtisch was well attended by over twenty people, mostly from companies based in Berlin who are either using Scrum already or are currently in a transition phase.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch November</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-november359/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 04:31:04 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-november359/</guid><description>Scrumtisch November # Title: Scrumtisch November
Location: Berlin
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Description: Next Scrum meetup - Scrumtisch - is scheduled to take place end of November in Berlin FHain. See you there (that is at La Vecchia Trattoria) if you are interested in agile development. Please make sure to register with Marion first.
Start Time: 18:30
Date: 2010-11-29</description></item><item><title>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback.</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2010 08:13:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-4-constant-evaluation-and-improvement-finding-sources-for-feedback324/</guid><description>Part 4: Constant evaluation and improvement: Finding sources for feedback. # In recent years demand for shorter feedback cycles especially in software development has increased. Agile development, lean management and even Scrum are all for short feedback cycles: Coming from the dark ages when software projects would last for months or even years before any results could be delivered to customers we are transforming development into a process that integrates the customer in the design and evolution of his own product.</description></item><item><title>Part 2: Tracking tasks, or - Where the hack did my time go to last week?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-2-tracking-tasks-or-where-the-hack-did-my-time-go-to-last-week322/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 18:22:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-2-tracking-tasks-or-where-the-hack-did-my-time-go-to-last-week322/</guid><description>Part 2: Tracking tasks, or - Where the hack did my time go to last week? # After summarising some strategies for not loosing track of tasks, meetings and conferences in the last post, this one is going to focus on the retrospect on achievements. If at some point in time you have asked yourself &amp;ldquo;Where the hack did time go to?&amp;rdquo; - maybe after two busy weeks of work this article might have a few techniques for you.</description></item><item><title>Berlin Scrumtisch - open discussion</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-open-discussion123/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2010 21:29:05 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/berlin-scrumtisch-open-discussion123/</guid><description>Berlin Scrumtisch - open discussion # This evening the Berlin Scrumtisch took place in Friedrichshain. More than thirty participants followed Marion&amp;rsquo;s invitation for discussions on Scrum, wine and pizza at Vecchia Trattoria.
As there were several new participants, Felix started out with a very brief summary of the very core concepts of Scrum itself: Most important to know is the basic assumption of Scrum, that is planning ahead of time in a very detailed way is impossible.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch August Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2010 16:26:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-august-berlin356/</guid><description>Scrumtisch August Berlin # Just seen it - the next Scrumtisch Berlin has been scheduled for 25th August 2010 at 18:30 Uhr. So far, no official talk has been scheduled, so please expect two topics on Scrum and its application to be selected for discussion according to Marion&amp;rsquo;s agile topic selection algorithm.
Please talk to Marion Eickmann if you would like to attend the next meetup.</description></item><item><title>Part 1: Travelling minds</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 06:00:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/part-1-travelling-minds321/</guid><description>Part 1: Travelling minds # In the last post I promised to share some more information on techniques I came across and found useful under an increasing work load. Instead of taking a close look at my professional calendar I decided to use my private one as an example - first because spare time is even more precious then working hours, simply because there is so few of it and secondly because I am free to publicly scrutinize not only the methods for keeping it in good shape but also the entries in it.</description></item><item><title>Series: Getting things done</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 07:07:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/series-getting-things-done367/</guid><description>Series: Getting things done # Probably not too unusual for people working on free software mostly (though no longer exclusively) in their spare time, the number of items that appear in my private calendar have increased steadily in the past months and years:
Every three months I am organising the Apache Hadoop Get Together in Berlin.
I have been asked (and accepted the offer) to publish articles on Hadoop and Lucene in magazines.</description></item><item><title>Scrum - prepare your meetings</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-prepare-your-meetings339/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2010 15:45:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-prepare-your-meetings339/</guid><description>Scrum - prepare your meetings # &amp;ldquo;But Scrum involves so many meetings - we already have meetings like all day and don&amp;rsquo;t get to coding anything.&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;However we do need transparency and communication to build great software.&amp;rdquo; - &amp;ldquo;Actually scheduling and re-prioritising items during scrum planning takes so much time.&amp;rdquo; Does that sound familiar to you?
What if you could fit Sprint Review and Planning I for a team of three people doing three week sprints into one hour?</description></item><item><title>Using Scrum for software development</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/using-scrum-for-software-development417/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 15:31:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/using-scrum-for-software-development417/</guid><description>Using Scrum for software development # A few months ago I entered a new team of until then two software developers. Being so small and with a rather busy product owner, until then people had followed the rituals of Scrum only loosely. When starting to work on a new component the three of us decided to change a few thing several weeks ago:
We would setup infrastructure to be somewhat similar to what we knew from Apache projects: All issues to be accomplished were to be tracked in our issue tracker.</description></item><item><title>Velocity update</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/velocity-update418/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 18:34:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/velocity-update418/</guid><description>Velocity update # After Berlin Buzzwords is over now, I thought it might be time to update a formerly published velocity graph. If you have been following this blog during the past few months you may know already, that we are using Scrum @ Home for several months already. I even published results of a Scrum Nokia test earlier this year.
Today I created another one of these nice velocity charts.</description></item><item><title>Coaching self-organising teams</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2010 21:58:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/coaching-self-organising-teams143/</guid><description>Coaching self-organising teams # Today, the Scrumtisch organised by Marion Eickmann from Agile 42 met in Berlin Friedrichshain. Though no talk was scheduled for this evening the room was packed with guests from various companies and backgrounds interested in participating in discussions on Scrum.
As usual we started collecting topics (timeboxed to five minutes). The list was rather short, however it contained several interesting pieces:
(6) Management buy-in
(6+) CSP - Certified Scrum Professional - what changes compared to the practitioner?</description></item><item><title>Alan Atlas at Scrumtisch Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/alan-atlas-at-scrumtisch-berlin8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 23:35:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/alan-atlas-at-scrumtisch-berlin8/</guid><description>Alan Atlas at Scrumtisch Berlin # At the last Berlin Scrumtisch, @AlanAtlas gave a presentation on how he introduced Scrum at Amazon (starting as early as back in 2004). Introducing Scrum at Amazon by that time seemed natural due to a few factors:
Amazon was and is always very customer centric. The original methodology of working backwards in time - that is starting with the press release, from there writing the FAQ and manual and finally get to the code - really made people concentrate on the product.</description></item><item><title>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 09:09:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/the-7-deadly-sins-of-java-software-developers407/</guid><description>The 7 deadly sins of (Java) software developers # On Lucid Imaginations Blog Jay Hill published a great article on The seven deadly sins of solr. Basically it is a collection of his experiences &amp;ldquo;analyzing and evaluating a great many instances of Solr implementations, running in some of the largest Fortune 500 companies&amp;rdquo;. It is a collection of common mistakes, mis-configurations and pitfalls in Solr installations in production use.</description></item><item><title>How much of Scrum is implemented?</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-much-of-scrum-is-implemented235/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 22:36:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/how-much-of-scrum-is-implemented235/</guid><description>How much of Scrum is implemented? # I have started using Scrum for various purposes: It has inspired the way software is developed at my current employer. I use it to organize a students&amp;rsquo; project at university. In addition we are using it at home to get all personal tasks (preparing breakfast, doing the laundry, meeting with friends&amp;hellip;) in line for each week.
Constantly looking for ways to evaluate, refine and improve work - I am also looking for ideas on how to evaluate which aspects of the Scrum implementation can actually be improved.</description></item><item><title>ScrumTisch Berlin - November</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin-november358/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 23:03:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-berlin-november358/</guid><description>ScrumTisch Berlin - November # This evening Marion organised another successful Scrumtisch: Usually we either meet for timeboxed discussions on Scrum and agile development questions or a speaker is invited to present his favourite Scrum or Lean or Agile topic.
Today Markus Frick gave a presentation of how Scrum was introduced at SAP, a German software company. They started implementing Scrum in a &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; team of about 60 people, organised in about six to seven teams.</description></item><item><title>Scrumtisch with Mary and Tom Poppendiek</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-with-mary-and-tom-poppendiek360/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:07:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrumtisch-with-mary-and-tom-poppendiek360/</guid><description>Scrumtisch with Mary and Tom Poppendiek # Yesterday evening the Scrumtisch Berlin hosted a talk by Mary Poppendiek on Lean Development. Mary started the session with a talk on what lean development is all about and why it goes further than Scrum ever did. Some of the core principles she explained:
The first goal of every lean project should be to strive for customer satisfaction. The low hanging fruit is to do exactly what the customer wanted to have.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Day Düsseldorf</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-day-dusseldorf341/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 05:24:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-day-dusseldorf341/</guid><description>Scrum Day Düsseldorf # On 01. to 02. December the Scrum Day is going to take place in Düsseldorf.
If you are working in a non-Scrum company and would like to use agile methods both for development and management, I would like to recommend going to the talk by Thilo Fromm: Scrum in a waterfall. He explains how he transformed his project to an agile way in a waterfall environment.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Tisch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch-3348/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 18:30:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch-3348/</guid><description>Scrum Tisch # Title: Scrum Tisch
Description: The Scrumtisch on October 11th will feature a talk by Mary Poppendieck.
She will join that extraordinary Scrumtisch at 6pm.
The location is not yet defined yet, because Marion first needs to know how many of are coming.
Start Time: 18:00
Date: 2009-10-11</description></item><item><title>Scrum Tisch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch-2349/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 18:01:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch-2349/</guid><description>Scrum Tisch # Title: Scrum Tisch
Location: La Vecchia Trattoria
Description: The next Scrum Tisch organized by Marion Eickmann takes place this Thursday. Since a pretty long time the format will be open for questions, prioritized by the participants again.
The location is in Niederbarnimstraße 25, near U-Bahn Samariterstrasse.
Start Time: 18:30
Date: 2009-09-24</description></item><item><title>Scrum Table Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-berlin345/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 21:26:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-berlin345/</guid><description>Scrum Table Berlin # Last week I attended the scrum table Berlin. This time around Phillippe gave a presentation on &amp;ldquo;backlog colours&amp;rdquo;, that is types of work items tracked in the backlog.
The easiest type to track are features - that is items that generate revenue and are on the wishlist of the customer. Second type of items he sees are infrastructure items - that is, things needed to implement several features but invisible to the customer.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Tisch</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch347/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 11:27:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-tisch347/</guid><description>Scrum Tisch # Title: Scrum Tisch
Location: Divino FHain
Link out: Click here
Description: Philippe will present his speech from the Orlando scrum Gathering where he will speak about backlog and time-box, about value versus cost, about visible features versus invisible features (and in particular software architecture), about defects and technical debt, and more generally about release planning and sprint planning for non-trivial and long-lived software development projects.
Start Time: 18:00</description></item><item><title>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 18:56:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/ken-schwaber-in-berlin-xberg258/</guid><description>Ken Schwaber in Berlin XBerg # Last week I attended a discussion meetup with Ken Schwaber in Berlin/ Kreuzberg. The event was scheduled pretty shortly
still quite a few developers and project managers from various companies in Berlin showed up.
Ken started with a brief summary of the history of Scrum: Before there was such a thing as an IT industry programming actually was a lot of fun. But somehow the creative job was turned into something people tend to suffer from pretty quickly as people tried to apply principles from manufacturing industries to software &amp;ldquo;production&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 09:19:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-table-with-thoralf-klatt346/</guid><description>Scrum Table with Thoralf Klatt # On Wednesday, the 22nd of April, about 20 people interested in Scrum gathered in the DiVino in Friedrichshain/Berlin. The event was split in two parts: In the first half we gathered topics participants were interested in, put priorities next the them and discussed the most highly ranked topic: &amp;ldquo;Scrum in large teams, splitting large tasks across teams.&amp;quot;
The basic take home messages of the discussion:</description></item><item><title>Scrum Roundtable Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-roundtable-berlin344/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 14:51:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-roundtable-berlin344/</guid><description>Scrum Roundtable Berlin # Title: Scrum Roundtable Berlin
Location: DiVino Restaurant, Grünberger Str. 69, Friedrichshain
Link out: Click here&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Start Time: 18:00
Date: 2009-04-22
The next Scrum Roundtable is scheduled already. Thoralf, will present his speech from the Orlando ScrumGathering
Agile Creation of Multi-Product Solutions
Motivation for Network Solutions and their Agilility
Scaling Single Product Creation
Product Solutions using Scrum
Customizing Projects
Outlook
Please let Marion know if you are coming to be able to organise the space.</description></item><item><title>Scrum @ Home</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-home340/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 00:12:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-home340/</guid><description>Scrum @ Home # Scrum has proven to be a suitable toolset for managing software projects: Large, unmanageable tasks are broken up into little pieces that can be easily estimated in terms of complexity or time necessary for implementation. During a fixed amount of time, several of these tasks are implemented. By looking back at previous iterations it is simple to predict exactly how many items can be expected to be ready after the next iteration.</description></item><item><title>Scrum discussions in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-discussions-in-berlin342/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 20:11:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/scrum-discussions-in-berlin342/</guid><description>Scrum discussions in Berlin # As software development cycles become ever shorter more and more companies adopt agile development methods. In many cases companies have switched to using Scrum or are still transitioning from less flexible approaches.
Since last summer Marion Eickmann is organising a Scrum Roundtable in Berlin. The goal is to discuss advantages and problems when introducing and practicing Scrum. But discussions on Scrum itself are also welcome.</description></item></channel></rss>