<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gotocon on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/gotocon/</link><description>Recent content in gotocon on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 10:47:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/gotocon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GoTo Con AMS - Day 2</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-amsterdam-day-2217/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 10:47:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-amsterdam-day-2217/</guid><description>GoTo Con AMS - Day 2 # Day two of GoTo Con Amsterdam started with a keynote by former Squeak developer Dan Ingalls. He introduced the Lively kernel - a component architecture for HTML5 that runs in any browser and allows easy composition, sharing and programming of items. Having seen Squeak years ago and being thrilled by its concepts even back then it was amazing to see what you can do with Lively kernel in a browser.</description></item><item><title>GoTo Con AMS - Day 1</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-ams-day-1216/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 20:44:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/goto-con-ams-day-1216/</guid><description>GoTo Con AMS - Day 1 # Last week GoTo Con took place in Amsterdam. Being a sister conference to GoTo in Aarhus the Amsterdam event focused on the broad topics of agile development, architectural challenges, backend and frontend development, platforms like the JVM and .NET. In addition the Amsterdam event featured a special Apache track tailored towards presentations focusing on the development model at Apache and the technologies developed at Apache.</description></item><item><title>Night Trains</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 05:40:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/night-trains292/</guid><description>Night Trains # It was several years ago that a frequent traveller told me about it being more comfortable and time saving to travel mid-sized distances (e.g. from Berlin to Amsterdam) by train - night train that is - instead of flying. Back then without decent knowledge of which combination of booking early and discount card make prizes of trips by train somewhat comparable to those offered by airlines that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really an option for me.</description></item></channel></rss>