<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Hadoop on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Hadoop/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Hadoop on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 21:19:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/tags/Apache-Hadoop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 21:19:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/video-is-up-josh-devins-on-apache-hadoop-at-nokia419/</guid><description> Video is up - Josh Devins on Apache Hadoop at Nokia #</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/fosdem-hbase-at-facebook-messaging180/</guid><description>FOSDEM - HBase at Facebook Messaging # Nicolas Spiegelberg gave an awesome introduction not only to the architecture that powers Facebook messaging but also to the design decisions behind their use of Apache HBase as a storage backend. Disclaimer: HBase is being used for message storage, for attachements with Haystack a different backend is used.
The reasons to go for HBase include its strong consistency model, support for auto failover, load balancing of shards, support for compression, atomic read-modify-write support and the inherent Map/Reduce support.</description></item><item><title>Slides of yesterday's Apache Hadoop Get Together</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-of-yesterdays-apache-hadoop-get-together374/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 21:40:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/slides-of-yesterdays-apache-hadoop-get-together374/</guid><description>Slides of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Apache Hadoop Get Together # This time with little less than 24 hours delay - the usual, by some impatiently expected, summary of the Apache Hadoop Get Together. The meetup took place at Zanox&amp;rsquo; event campus. The room was well filled with some fourty attendees from various companies, experience with Hadoop ranging from interested beginners to experienced users.
Slides of all presentations:
Josh Devins on Hadoop at Nokia</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 16:31:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-get-together-berlin-january-201157/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop Get Together Berlin - January 2011 # This is to announce the next Apache Hadoop Get Together sponsored by Cloudera and Zanox that will take place in the Zanox Event Campus in Berlin.
When: January 27th 2011, 6p.m.
Where: zanox Event Campus (Please mark the changed event location.)
&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;Größere Kartenansicht
As always there will be slots of 30min each for talks on your Hadoop topic. After each talk there will be a lot time to discuss.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hadoop - Trainings by Cloudera in Berlin</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-trainings-by-cloudera-in-berlin39/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 23:53:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-hadoop-trainings-by-cloudera-in-berlin39/</guid><description>Apache Hadoop - Trainings by Cloudera in Berlin # Cloudera is offering trainings both for Administrators as well as for Developers early next year in Berlin. If your are getting started in using Apache Hadoop this might be a great option to get your developers and operations up to speed with the framework. If you are a regular of the local Apache Hadoop Get Together a discount code should have been sent to you by mail.</description></item></channel></rss>