<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache on Inductive Bias</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/categories/Apache/</link><description>Recent content in Apache on Inductive Bias</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:06:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isabel-drost.de/categories/Apache/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Board of Directors - a retrospective</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-board-of-directors-a-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:06:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-board-of-directors-a-retrospective/</guid><description>Apache Board of Directors - a retrospective # Last term I had the honour of serving on the ASF board of directors, better explained in context of the ASF governance structure. As quite a few directors (myself included) declined to run for the board this year again, I thought it would be a good idea to think about the past term, write that down and publish those thoughts. As I wanted to give every board member a chance to respond, I shared some guiding questions but left it to board members to choose the channel they deemed most appropriate to share their responses on.</description></item><item><title>DataworksSummit Berlin - Wednesday morning</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dataworkssummit-berlin-wednesday-morning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 08:50:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/dataworkssummit-berlin-wednesday-morning/</guid><description>DataworksSummit Berlin - Wednesday morning # Data strategy - cloud strategy - business strategy: Aligning the three was one of the main themes (initially put forward in his opening keynote by CTO of Hortonworks Scott Gnau) thoughout this weeks Dataworks Summit Berlin kindly organised and hosted by Hortonworks. The event was attended by over 1000 attendees joining from 51 countries.
The inspiration hat was put forward in the first keynote by Scott was to take a closer look at the data lifecycle - including the fact that a lot of data is being created (and made available) outside the control of those using it: Smart farming users are using a combination of weather data, information on soil conditions gathered through sensors out in the field in order to inform daily decisions.</description></item><item><title>Apache Breakfast</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 09:39:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/apache-breakfast/</guid><description>Apache Breakfast # In case you missed it but are living in Berlin - or are visiting Berlin/ Germany this week: A handful of Apache people (committers/ members) are meeting over breakfast on Friday morning this week. If you are interested in joining, please let me know (or check yourself - in the archives of the mailing list party@apache.org)</description></item><item><title>My board nomination statement 2018</title><link>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-board-nomination-statement-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 08:21:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isabel-drost.de/my-board-nomination-statement-2018/</guid><description>My board nomination statement 2018 # Two days ago the Apache Software Foundation members meeting started. One of the outcomes of each members meeting is an elected board of directors. The way that works is explained here: Annual Apache members meeting. As explained in the linked post, members accepting their nomination to become a director are supposed to provide a nomination statement. This year they were also asked to answer a set of questions so members could better decide who to vote for.</description></item></channel></rss>